<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medicine | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/medicine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>medicine</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/medicine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sultan&#39;s Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the month of September issues of the Egyptian Gazette, the newspaper talks about the Sultan&#39;s illness. Specifically, in page three of the September 21st issue of 1906, the Sultan is mentioned and the author says he has Bright&#39;s disease. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bright%27s_disease&#34;&gt;This disease was named after Richard Bright, a physician.&lt;/a&gt; It was a disease pertaining to the kidney, but was later discovered to be a classification of a variety of kidney diseases that were unknown at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kidney.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brights-Disease&#34; title=&#34;A kidney with Bright&#39;s Disease&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A patient with this disease could experience swelling, convulsions, blindness, and coma. A lot of patients with this disease may have also had high blood pressure, heart disease, or diabetes. The newspaper mentions Dr. Nafiz, and Dr. Noureddin Pasha as the primary physicians of the Sultan, but it mentions that they had to consult Professor Bergmann for assistance. Bergmann was the one to diagnose the Sultan with Bright&#39;s disease, and ordered an immediate surgical operation. He also says that he is suffering from &amp;quot;other complications,&amp;quot; which may be anything from diabetes to heart disease to kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160915235645/https:/www.guideline.gov/summaries/summary/36900&#34;&gt;Today, a patient with the same symptoms would be likely diagnosed with chronic nephritis, which is an inflammation of the kidney.&lt;/a&gt; However, in the Thursday issue, it is mentioned that the Sultan was suffering from a stone. This means that he may have had a urinary tract infection. The most common cause of a UTI is  Escherichia coli, or similar fungi. Other causes may include genetic predisposition or being uncircumcised. What exactly caused the Sultan to be ill is unknown, however, the diagnosis at the time was based on similar cases. Richard Bright attributed the disease to high blood pressure and diabetes, which could have been true in the Sultan&#39;s case, as he mourned the recent death of two high functionaries, one of which &amp;quot;enjoyed his majesty&#39;s confidence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Look Into The History of Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-tryfontheophilopoulos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-tryfontheophilopoulos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills were originally advertised as &amp;ldquo;miracle pills&amp;rdquo;, which claimed to treat a variety of ailments. There were not a large quantity of advertisements that advertised to do a similar thing, but the main two were Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills and Dr. William&#39;s Pink Pills. Due to the fact that medicine at the time was still developing and overall understanding of illnesses was relatively unknown, actual medical professionals weren&#39;t able to properly diagnose and treat many  of their patients properly. This resulted in many individuals going and using these untraditional methods of treatment. In general, kidney function was not well understood, resulting in renal diseases being broadly categorized as &lt;a href=&#34;https://raycityhistory.wordpress.com/2011/03/15/george-emory-swindle-sought-cure-at-buffalo-lithia-springs-va/&#34;&gt;Bright’s disease&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raycityhistory.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/doans-box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills&#34; title=&#34;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the similar alternative to the Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills, Dr. William&#39;s Pink Pills were eventually realized for their true worth and removed from the market. I was originally expecting a similar result for Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills, although it appears that these pills are actually sold today even. It appears at some point the deceptive and untruthful advertising was changed to only advertise for the true effects of the pill. Sometime during this timeline, the ingredients of the pills were switched from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjFkaux-KvmAhUHnOAKHT6vBmYQFjACegQIDBAI&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.urbanremainschicago.com%2Fsingle-rare-antique-and-all-original-wall-mount-porcelain-enameled-metal-thermometer-advertisement-for-doan-s-pills-remedy-for-kidney-ailments.html&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw0S9N9AfJ1HZbQYcHul184I/&#34;&gt;oil of jupiter &amp;amp; potassium nitrate&lt;/a&gt; to magnesium salicylate, a mild analgesic and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug. The differences between the two are that potassium nitrate is used today mainly in explosives and fertilizers, whereas modern Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills actually contain a substance that has been proven to help with pain and inflammation. It is frightening to see Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills avoided the same fate as Dr. William&#39;s Pink Pills, despite not being a placebo capsule and instead containing substances such as potassium nitrate which have been proven to cause &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjvmPKV-avmAhVhkeAKHXBACG0QFjACegQIDRAI&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftoxnet.nlm.nih.gov%2Fcgi-bin%2Fsis%2Fsearch%2Fa%3Fdbs%2Bhsdb%3A%40term%2B%40DOCNO%2B1227&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3vK1ctvthIXB-LB4F7JVDi/&#34;&gt;violent gastroenteritis, anemia, methemoglobinemia, or even nephritis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Similar blogs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/&#34;&gt;Miraculous Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34;&gt;Pink Pills for Pale People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty in Pink</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-breannaheflin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-breannaheflin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early 1900&#39;s casualties were in abundance due to a lack of understanding of the human body. Disease and illness became an everyday battle for those who had been discharged as “incurable” with no hope for a healthy life. Marketing ploys done for many “patented” drugs, such as “Dr. William’s Pink Pills for Pale People”, fed on this vulnerability not knowing that many diseases did not even require medical intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pink Pills for Pale People” grew immensely in Great Britain and North America for their shiny pink coat and claims to cure TB, rickets, kidney diseases, and even &lt;a href=&#34;https://macdonaldtownbicycleclub.com/2017/04/24/mrs-e-j-curtis-paralysed-with-rheumatism-restored-to-active-health-by-dr-williams-pink-pills/&#34;&gt;paralysis&lt;/a&gt;. A new “miracle” drug had been invented that seemed to cure fatal diseases in a matter of days,  purifying the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kshs.org/kansapedia/pink-pills-for-pale-people/10240&#34;&gt;“bad blood”&lt;/a&gt; that resulted in muscle and nerve disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One case was that of a young daughter named Sophie Caspeele who suffered from a severe case of anemia: chronic weakness, loss of appetite, and poor digestion. Claiming to cure female ailments, marketing practices such as this one tugged on the heart strings of parents and suffering women. The pills became well-known and named for the healthy complexion that they restored to its patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bmh19/blog-posts/master/2019-10-17-Breanna%20Heflin/Pink%20Pills.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sophie Caspeele&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, the famous “Pink Pills” were discovered to contain merely “extract of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wellcomelibrary.org/2015/03/dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34;&gt;Barbadoes&lt;/a&gt; aloes enclosed in a thick coating of sugar, colored with pink carmine”, yet continued to be sold into the 20th century. The “Pink Pills” were eventually exposed for quackery and withdrawn in the UK in 1970.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though still flawed, this case of medical negligence shows the improvement needed and made within the pharmaceutical industry relied on by many even today. Marketing strategies fool us similarly in the 21st century as they did in the 20th with physical appeals and claims of the unbelievable happening, because it is not actually happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;similar-blog-posts&#34;&gt;Similar blog posts:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34;&gt;Pink Pills for Pale People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/&#34;&gt;Miraculous Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Pills for Pale People</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of clickbait, tabloid papers, and fake news, it&#39;s still nice to see that we haven&#39;t changed a bit. This is a classic example of a snake oil salesmen at work. Dr. Williams&amp;rsquo; Pink Pills are said to cure Anaemia, Indigestion, Eczema, Rheumatism, Sciatica, St. Vitus’ Dance, Neuralgia, Nervous Disorders, Paralysis, and Locomotor Ataxy. Since the pills did have ferrous sulphate or just Iron sulphate, it would have an effect on the anemic. This however, is still a scam because the amount that was in his pink pills was much less than actual medicine and because of this, the pills were much weaker and were more expensive than just the regular iron pills doctors would usually prescribe. This is probably one of the only pills that are in song, while the song is a critique of commercialism in society, it was sung by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wu2V3TkHufA&#34;&gt;Benny Bell&lt;/a&gt;. Also something that intrigued me was that you can still &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springbokpharmacy.co.za/Product?product_id=354130&amp;amp;category_id=33098&#34;&gt;buy these pills&lt;/a&gt; online to cure basically anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more &lt;a href=&#34;https://diseasesofmodernlife.org/2016/11/29/pills-for-our-ills-dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34;&gt;elaborate backstory&lt;/a&gt; of the company and pills, as well as how they fared in Asian markets.
[Pink Pills](1907-05-20-p5 selection)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trend of snake oil pills being sold in The Egyptian Gazette is not a new one. Looking through other blog posts I saw a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Esteve-Medicine/&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; about &amp;ldquo;Doan&#39;s Backache Kidney Pills&amp;rdquo;. The man who used it was told he only had 3 months to live but after some pills, he made a miraculous recovery! Another post follows the same vein of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/baxter-Peruna/&#34;&gt;miraculous medicine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miraculous Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Ida Caldwell, a seemingly sweet old lady, has been suffering with “catarrh of the respiratory organs on and off for the last three years”. She had to use her greatest care not to “expose herself to chilly air or dampness as it increased her troubles.” She was advised to change her climate, but she couldn’t leave her family so she had to stay put. Then she was introduced to Peruna which relieved her of her pain in three days, and she was completely cured in two months. What a miracle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post seemed like a serious article about a well-known woman who seemed to be in a lot of pain due to her &amp;ldquo;catarrh of her lungs.&amp;rdquo; However, when I kept reading, I noticed that it was just a gimmicky ad for a sketchy medicine that claimed to &amp;ldquo;cure symptoms of the common cold.&amp;rdquo; The ad seemed really convincing, and I almost believed that this woman had her illness cured because of this medicine. On the downside, I did notice that this ad sounded a lot like the ones I hear today, which seems quite interesting, that advertisements haven’t changed that much since 1906. This was a very interesting, well put together ad, and I do believe that a lot of people would have jumped at the chance to buy this medicine upon reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Boil Your Water</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-01-ferguson.katherine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-01-ferguson.katherine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Typhoid fever ravaged many armies, including the Egyptian. Therefore, extensive research was conducted in order to identify the source of infection and how to prevent it. Dr. Leigh Canney was on the forefront of this field in Egypt during the 19th century. “Dr. Leigh Canney was able to produce evidence from the reports of the Army Medical Department to show that the Army was ‘sanitarily untrained and unprotected’”. Furthermore, he recognized that enteric disease came from unsanitary water. However, the Army Medical Department did not want to hear it; this was not the answer they were looking for. Sir T. Gallaway argued against boiling water before drinking stating that, “all our schemes for sterilization of water by boiling or otherwise have had no effect.” Dr. Leigh Canney persisted on not only the sterilization, but also the preservation of clean water. He urged the Army to keep clean water in enclosed clean bottles to prevent contact with flies and dust which could cause recontamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days after this article was posted, on December 6, 1905, a letter to the editor was published regarding the issues faced when implementing the rules on sanitary water. The author states that boiling water and allowing it to cool after a hard days work in the desert is simply impossible, and “the system is not sufficiently practical to hold water”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both sides of the argument have made valid points, we now know that sanitizing drinking water is essential. Contaminated water houses pathogens such as Typhoid, Cholera, and a plethora of others. Although Typhoid had been identified in 1880, a vaccine &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news-medical.net/health/Typhoid-Fever-History.aspx&#34;&gt;was not developed and distributed until 1896&lt;/a&gt;. The chlorination of water during the 20th century also reduced Typhoid prevalence. Currently, India, Pakistan and Egypt are “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.medicinenet.com/typhoid_fever/article.htm&#34;&gt;known as high risk areas for developing this disease&lt;/a&gt;.” 21 million people are infected annually worldwide, with over 200,000 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Killer</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-soap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a time when merchandise regulation is not nearly as controlled as it is now, it can be expected that there will be defaults in the products produced. [Salicylate of soda](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2220712/?page=1&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2220712/?page=1&lt;/a&gt; Define Salicylate of Soda&amp;rdquo;) was thought to have restorative effects during the mid to late 19th century. It was often recommended to people with joint disease, such as rheumatism, to alleviate pain.  At first the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1322509/?page=7&#34;&gt;negative side effects&lt;/a&gt; associated with salicylate of soda reported were minor, like a relapse in pain after the salicylate of soda was no longer being used. Many users had to be gradually weaned from the chemical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;soap-ad.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunlight Soap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years after its use in soap, physicians began noting that people who were repeated salicylate of soda users had painful skin and there was even a case of failing vision after taking a bath in the soap with the chemicals. In the early 1900s, manufacturers of soap products containing the chemical were ordered to stop production and were prosecuted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=5a-Uc3NJuPUC&amp;amp;pg=PA206&amp;amp;lpg=PA206&amp;amp;dq=1905+egyptian+sanitary+administration&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=pGXkko-vu3&amp;amp;sig=P6WCUO4P1BmN_u7Zm8Ny2nSY3Dc&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi60p_rs4zQAhWSZiYKHXwdDTMQ6AEIHTAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=1905%20egyptian%20sanitary%20administration&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;sanitary administration&lt;/a&gt;. Large soap companies during this time, like Pears’ Soap, were not being advertised because of the ordeal. Instead, the same issue of the newspaper that published the harmful soap announcement had an ad for Sunlight Soap, which advertises its lack of “obnoxious or harmful feature.” This small news brief gives insight about this time period, showing its lack of medical knowledge and its clever marketing methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pear-soap.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pear Soap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-esteve-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-esteve-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-mans-trash-is-another-mans-treasure&#34;&gt;One Man&#39;s Trash is Another Man&#39;s Treasure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, a man wrote to the Egyptian Gazette about the stricture and kidney disease that he had suffered with for 19 years. After living with excruciating pain and being told that he would only have three months to live, this man began taking Doan&#39;s Backache Kidney Pills.&lt;br&gt;
I was immediately curious about this, because &lt;a href=&#34;https://pics.drugstore.com/prodimg/498956/450.jpg&#34;&gt;Doan&#39;s Backache Kidney Pills&lt;/a&gt; are a cheap, over the counter drug that people use today. While someone today might take these pills to relieve minor back pain, this man believes that they saved his life. This speaks a great deal to the quality of medicine during the early 1900&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern day America, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medlineplus.gov/magazine/issues/winter08/articles/winter08pg9-10.html&#34;&gt;kidney disease&lt;/a&gt; is often not curable and can usually only be delayed with extensive treatment and medication. As time passes and it gets worse, dialysis or a transplant is needed. I mention all of this to draw attention to the diagnosis of the man in the Egyptian Gazette. He suffered for 19 years and was diagnosed with three months to live, yet an over the counter drug managed to save his life. Either drugs were much better 100 years ago, or he was severely misdiagnosed. People often take for granted the high level of medicine and easy access to treatment that exists throughout the world today. I wonder how much of an impact old-fashioned medicine had on other people living in the early 1900&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
