<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medicine | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/medicine/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>medicine</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/medicine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Pills: Stronger Than Death</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-16-phuong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-16-phuong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pills and medicines have relentlessly shown themselves throughout the Egyptian Gazette as miraculous solutions to peoples&#39; problems. This piece called &amp;ldquo;STRONGER THAN DEATH&amp;rdquo; begins with stating its purpose: to add more evidence that Pink Pills work. The story of a woman&amp;rsquo;s tragedy plays out in which she develops accumulating sickness after having many children in a short span of time. The sickness only worsens as she finds out her husband had died falling, trying to get out of a tram car in America. The story goes on with how she healed to the point of full health after discovering the existence of the pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, this article seems to be more about promoting an idea than a real cure. What offsets its validity as a medicine is the idea that it could cure numerous types of sicknesses. &amp;ldquo;They cure anaemia, chlorosis, general debility, stom-ach complaints, rheumatism and neurasthenia.&amp;rdquo; Targeting the population, it uses several tactics. The article appeals to the entire audience, saying &amp;ldquo;Everyone must agree&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;they will do for everybody&amp;rdquo; and more. The article uses a relatable and pained main character that the people would feel sorry for, appealing to human emotions when the descriptions of her life and tragedies such as her husband dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;From this instance one learns what Pink Pills can achieve for the weak and enfeebled.&amp;rdquo; This statement paints the pill as a wondrous cure that saves people from weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I found was that these stories of the use of phenomenal Pink Pills may be continuous and confirm their worth. In this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;
, it is revealed that the pill has before already been called &amp;ldquo;Pink Pills are said to cure Anaemia, Indigestion, Eczema, Rheumatism, Sciatica, St. Vitus’ Dance, Neuralgia, Nervous Disorders, Paralysis, and Locomotor Ataxy.&amp;rdquo; This article &amp;ldquo;STRONGER THAN DEATH&amp;rdquo; links back to that with the mention of some of those same sicknesses. The author gives more depth to the pill&amp;rsquo;s contents and how the pills are a scam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sultan&#39;s Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the month of September issues of the Egyptian Gazette, the newspaper talks about the Sultan&#39;s illness. Specifically, in page three of the September 21st issue of 1906, the Sultan is mentioned and the author says he has Bright&#39;s disease. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bright%27s_disease&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This disease was named after Richard Bright, a physician.&lt;/a&gt;
 It was a disease pertaining to the kidney, but was later discovered to be a classification of a variety of kidney diseases that were unknown at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kidney.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brights-Disease&#34; title=&#34;A kidney with Bright&#39;s Disease&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A patient with this disease could experience swelling, convulsions, blindness, and coma. A lot of patients with this disease may have also had high blood pressure, heart disease, or diabetes. The newspaper mentions Dr. Nafiz, and Dr. Noureddin Pasha as the primary physicians of the Sultan, but it mentions that they had to consult Professor Bergmann for assistance. Bergmann was the one to diagnose the Sultan with Bright&#39;s disease, and ordered an immediate surgical operation. He also says that he is suffering from &amp;quot;other complications,&amp;quot; which may be anything from diabetes to heart disease to kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160915235645/https:/www.guideline.gov/summaries/summary/36900&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Today, a patient with the same symptoms would be likely diagnosed with chronic nephritis, which is an inflammation of the kidney.&lt;/a&gt;
 However, in the Thursday issue, it is mentioned that the Sultan was suffering from a stone. This means that he may have had a urinary tract infection. The most common cause of a UTI is  Escherichia coli, or similar fungi. Other causes may include genetic predisposition or being uncircumcised. What exactly caused the Sultan to be ill is unknown, however, the diagnosis at the time was based on similar cases. Richard Bright attributed the disease to high blood pressure and diabetes, which could have been true in the Sultan&#39;s case, as he mourned the recent death of two high functionaries, one of which &amp;quot;enjoyed his majesty&#39;s confidence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Look Into The History of Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-tryfontheophilopoulos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-tryfontheophilopoulos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills were originally advertised as &amp;ldquo;miracle pills&amp;rdquo;, which claimed to treat a variety of ailments. There were not a large quantity of advertisements that advertised to do a similar thing, but the main two were Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills and Dr. William&amp;rsquo;s Pink Pills. Due to the fact that medicine at the time was still developing and overall understanding of illnesses was relatively unknown, actual medical professionals weren&amp;rsquo;t able to properly diagnose and treat many  of their patients properly. This resulted in many individuals going and using these untraditional methods of treatment. In general, kidney function was not well understood, resulting in renal diseases being broadly categorized as 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://raycityhistory.wordpress.com/2011/03/15/george-emory-swindle-sought-cure-at-buffalo-lithia-springs-va/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bright’s disease&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raycityhistory.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/doans-box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills&#34; title=&#34;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the similar alternative to the Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills, Dr. William&amp;rsquo;s Pink Pills were eventually realized for their true worth and removed from the market. I was originally expecting a similar result for Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills, although it appears that these pills are actually sold today even. It appears at some point the deceptive and untruthful advertising was changed to only advertise for the true effects of the pill. Sometime during this timeline, the ingredients of the pills were switched from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjFkaux-KvmAhUHnOAKHT6vBmYQFjACegQIDBAI&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.urbanremainschicago.com%2Fsingle-rare-antique-and-all-original-wall-mount-porcelain-enameled-metal-thermometer-advertisement-for-doan-s-pills-remedy-for-kidney-ailments.html&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw0S9N9AfJ1HZbQYcHul184I/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;oil of jupiter &amp;amp; potassium nitrate&lt;/a&gt;
 to magnesium salicylate, a mild analgesic and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug. The differences between the two are that potassium nitrate is used today mainly in explosives and fertilizers, whereas modern Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills actually contain a substance that has been proven to help with pain and inflammation. It is frightening to see Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills avoided the same fate as Dr. William&amp;rsquo;s Pink Pills, despite not being a placebo capsule and instead containing substances such as potassium nitrate which have been proven to cause 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjvmPKV-avmAhVhkeAKHXBACG0QFjACegQIDRAI&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftoxnet.nlm.nih.gov%2Fcgi-bin%2Fsis%2Fsearch%2Fa%3Fdbs%2Bhsdb%3A%40term%2B%40DOCNO%2B1227&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3vK1ctvthIXB-LB4F7JVDi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;violent gastroenteritis, anemia, methemoglobinemia, or even nephritis&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Similar blogs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Miraculous Medicine&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pink Pills for Pale People&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Terminology as a means of analysis for the progression of medicine in Egypt and the British Empire</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-theophilopoulos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-theophilopoulos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, the world found itself in quite the predicament regarding medicine due to the relatively unknown cause and actual pathophysiological processes surrounding infection and contamination of a pathogen. Egypt and Alexandria in particular were still under British rule, as can be seen through the Egyptian Gazette, which is a primarily English containing newspaper marketed towards the British in the surrounding Egyptian areas as well as those who dealt with these individuals on a primary basis. In conclusion, this newspaper was made for the rich imperialists in control. Because of this, many different European and British influences can be seen within the Egyptian Gazette, one of which being certain medically affiliated advertisements. Two advertisements which caught my eye in particular were ones advertising Dr. William’s Pink Pills as well as Doan’s Kidney Pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/klxKSl2.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Painful Portrait 1905-01-04&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These pills were marketed as miracle pills that would be able to cure essentially any ailment that one encountered, including but not limited to kidney disease, heart palpitations, anxiety, stress, weakness, pain, backache, anaemia, clinical depression, poor appetite, and even cancer at one point. The funny part about the absurdness of the entire sales pitch?- they consisted of only iron oxide and magnesium sulfate. When looking into 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5337769/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt;
 conducted by Reyhaneh Kheiri, et al., they found that iron oxide had no real positive effect on the body, and iron levels only slightly increased depending on the dose between 1-6 hours following consumption. 12 hours following consumption, no iron level change could be observed. Magnesium sulfate, on the other hand, does have some health benefits such as prevent low magnesium blood levels as well as seizures in women. It is &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; unexpected that this compound also fails to treat any of the illnesses and conditions that these miracle pills claim to cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the catch? The simple answer is that these pills are entirely based on placebo and were such a large success due to the overall failure to understand medicine and pathology as we do today in modern medicine as well as the clever marketing that has been implemented not only in Egypt, but also worldwide during the selling of these pills. My analysis project deals primarily with the medical terminology which was employed in order to successfully market these “miracle pills”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin my analysis, I first had to find suitable advertisements that I would be able to use for this nature of a project. My main issue that I encountered was that most of the time, advertisements remain the same or only change once or twice throughout their lifetime in the Egyptian Gazette. This severely limited the advertisements that I would be able to use for this project, as I had to find more dynamic ones which were constantly changing on a daily or even monthly basis depending on the prevalence and frequency of them in the newspaper. I finally cut down all of the candidates I was originally looking at down to two: Dr. William’s Pink Pills &amp;amp; Doan’s Kidney Pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These advertisements seemed to be very different from other advertisements within the Egyptian Gazette in a couple different senses which made them perfect candidates for this embarkment. The main reason was because these advertisements often did not find themselves coming up within the main advertisement sections at all. The places that I found these advertisements were within actual bodies of text where stories and other items would be found. This meant that instead of being a reoccurring identical template, it changed constantly. In addition, because of this constant dynamic aspect that the advertisements had, they were often formatted in the form of a testimonial to make it seem less like a product being sold and more like an actual account from a civilian just like one who may be reading the newspaper, increasing their overall authenticity to the reader. In the end, this entire con is just a marketing scheme to make money, and it appears that these antics worked for a reason I will expand on when showing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;procedural-method-for-obtaining-results&#34;&gt;Procedural Method for Obtaining Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, due to the nature of these advertisements not actually being put into a advertisement div, I had to form my Xpath Query slightly differently so that it would find the instances of the title of the pills. I also was required to keep the Xpath Query fairly basic as narrowing it down in various ways resulted in not flagging positives as it should have been. For example, there was no template for these advertisements due to the fact that, once again, they were constantly changing throughout the Egyptian Gazette. The two queries that I used to create a database were the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;//div/div/p[contains(., &amp;lsquo;Pink Pills’)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;//div/div/p[contains(., ‘Doan’s Kidney Pills’)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After moving all of the div’s into a plaintext file, I separated them by year and began looking for patterns and certain terminology that I deemed important and observed repeating throughout. I then took specific words that I found important and created a database of the occurrences that they came up in the advertisements. I also counted the number of each advertisement for each year and then created a ratio of instances of word : instances of the advertisement that year. That created a fraction of the average number of times a specific word came up in one advertisement, allowing me to properly compare between years. I then plotted this data using Tableau and came up with the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dr-williams-pink-pills&#34;&gt;Dr. William&amp;rsquo;s Pink Pills:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Book1_15758293045230/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doans-kidney-pills&#34;&gt;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Book1s_15758318890720/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this data, I was able to learn and infer a couple of different things. The first thing that stood out to me was the amount of times the advertisements for these “miracle pills” would come up throughout the Egyptian Gazette. For example, when looking at instances of Dr. William’s Pink Pills, in 1905 there were only 16 occurrences of the advertisement. In 1906, that number increased slightly to 19 instances. Then, in 1907, the number skyrocketed to 45 different instances of that advertisement throughout the year in the Egyptian Gazette. When looking Doan’s Kidney Pills, a similar jump can be observed in the Egyptian Gazette. In 1905, 11 instances were recorded, in 1906 12 instances were recorded, and in 1907 the number shot through the roof. This clearly goes to show that the success surrounding these pills was flourishing as much more money was able to be put towards advertising following what I believe was a good year or two of selling their product. I also believe that this is due to this relatively new method of advertising which implemented personal testimonials to sell the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other patterns that I observed from this data was regarding exactly why many of these terms decreased in frequency over the three year time span. I believe after looking at the data and taking a detailed look into what types of treatments that the pills were offering that as medicine became slightly more advanced over this time period, these advertisements began to vouch for treating less and less serious ailments. They instead appear to move towards more general symptoms, the primary one being pain. These advertisements saw an increase in the prevalence of “pain” as pain can be associated with various illnesses, allowing them to generalize to more diseases without distinctly claiming to cure one or the other. As actual treatments for certain illnesses became available, these “miracle pills” began to advertise less towards specific ones and more for general symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of this move towards a better understanding of modern medicine can be seen in the word “blood”. I observed a decrease in the word blood within both advertisements, primarily because medicine was becoming more advanced as actual understanding of the body and pathogens slightly deepened. It was a common misconception that many ailments were caused by an impurity in the blood, and that a way to get new blood was a way to prevent further illnesses. These pills claimed to give “new blood” to the user, although this logic is clearly flawed by today’s understanding. As the understanding of pathology increased during this time period, we can also see a decrease in the word “blood” coming up in the newspaper, leading me to believe that this assumption of blood impurities became less prevalent as other more accurate explanations for illnesses arose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine Analysis Project</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many diseases that emerged in the 19th century included cholera, yellow fever, typhus, smallpox, and many more. However, it wasn’t until the late 19th century that weak medical practices became outdated. Before these breakthroughs there was only a basic understanding, which furthermore, commercialized the industry by selling medications with little to know regulation utilizing public fear and desperation. Many campaigns and ads sold the idea of “bad blood” being the cause as these medications were claimed to generate new blood and purify the body. Obviously, we know this is not real science but then, it was all the people knew and believed in regards to infectious diseases that were on a constant rise in the 1900s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;medical-terminology&#34;&gt;Medical Terminology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dr-williams-pink-pills&#34;&gt;Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Book1_15758293045230/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doans-kidney-pills&#34;&gt;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Kidney Pills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Book1s_15758318890720/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this data, I was able to learn and infer a couple of different things. The first thing that stood out to me was the amount of times the advertisements for these “miracle pills” would come up throughout the Egyptian Gazette. For example, when looking at instances of Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills, in 1905 there were only 16 occurrences of the advertisement. In 1906, that number increased slightly to 19 instances. Then, in 1907, the number skyrocketed to 45 different instances of that advertisement throughout the year in the Egyptian Gazette. When looking Doan’s Kidney Pills, a similar jump can be observed in the Egyptian Gazette. In 1905, 11 instances were recorded, in 1906 12 instances were recorded, and in 1907 the number shot through the roof. This clearly goes to show that the success surrounding these pills was flourishing as much more money was able to be put towards advertising following what I believe was a good year or two of selling their product. I also believe that this is due to this relatively new method of advertising which implemented personal testimonials to sell the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other patterns that I observed from this data was regarding exactly why many of these terms decreased in frequency over the three year time span. I believe after looking at the data and taking a detailed look into what types of treatments that the pills were offering that as medicine became slightly more advanced over this time period, these advertisements began to vouch for treating less and less serious ailments. They instead appear to move towards more general symptoms, the primary one being pain. These advertisements saw an increase in the prevalence of “pain” as pain can be associated with various illnesses, allowing them to generalize to more diseases without distinctly claiming to cure one or the other. As actual treatments for certain illnesses became available, these “miracle pills” began to advertise less towards specific ones and more for general symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of this move towards a better understanding of modern medicine can be seen in the word “blood”. I observed a decrease in the word blood within both advertisements, primarily because medicine was becoming more advanced as actual understanding of the body and pathogens slightly deepened. It was a common misconception that many ailments were caused by an impurity in the blood, and that a way to get new blood was a way to prevent further illnesses. These pills claimed to give “new blood” to the user, although this logic is clearly flawed by today’s understanding. As the understanding of pathology increased during this time period, we can also see a decrease in the word “blood” coming up in the newspaper, leading me to believe that this assumption of blood impurities became less prevalent as other more accurate explanations for illnesses arose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?As for the application of these results to the group project, it ties in strongly with the other topics in the sense that we are able to apply these results to the work of the other topics within this project. For example, by looking at prevalence of words in advertisements, we can infer that certain ailments that are commonly found within the miracle pill advertisements likely also are symptoms of larger diseases that medical schools and hospitals are dealing with. We are able to get a sense for what is affecting the larger population and tie this in by looking at the proper ways that these illnesses and symptoms are being treated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;medical-schools-and-the-diseases-found&#34;&gt;Medical Schools and the Diseases Found&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correlation between the location of medical schools and hospitals with the diseases that were being researched at these medical facilities. By finding if these diseases were prevalent in certain areas, it may be concluded that  the disease was being researched at a prominent medical institution.  The first disease found was Tropical Disease which is mentioned in the Gazette four times. Three of these times were cases within Cairo and the last one was found within Sudan. While this data is not enough to say there was an epidemic, it may be enough to deduce that these areas were experiencing hardships from this disease. The lack of knowledge about this disease stemmed from fear of the collapsing British Empire. One gave a fearful message that the Tropical Disease would lead to the death of the British Empire if it was not completely eradicated. The article then called for the Kasr-el-Ainy and other medical schools to try and find a cure to this disease.  There was only one occurrence of the disease within Sudan at the Gordon College Laboratories,but that is only to talk about trying to find a cure for the animals in that area.   It can be seen by the number of times this disease was mentioned to be in Cairo that this disease was mainly affecting that area during the period of 1905-1906. Also, with the article blatantly warning the public of London about how the disease would cause extreme harm to the British Empire from those who were in Cairo, it can be shown that the disease was mainly affecting this region in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another disease that appeared in the newspaper was trypanosomiasis. This disease was mainly found within Sudan, but upon further inspection it was shown that this disease only stemmed from another disease called sleeping sickness. We used the x-path queries below to research more about sleeping sickness in Sudan and at Gordon College. Sleeping sickness was the main disease that was prevalent since there are 17 occurrences of the term within the newspaper. This disease was being researched by the Gordon College Laboratories in Sudan, but there were articles explaining how the disease was killing off livestock and people within the area of Sudan.Upon further inspection, we wanted to see if there would be a link between the Kasr-el-Ainy and Cairo.  Both of queries yielded no results for either which could mean that the disease was only centralized to Sudan or that a cure was found before it was able to spread to elsewhere. I was able to find one outside resource 
&lt;a href=&#34;search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=edsbl&amp;amp;AN=vdc.100063233501.0x000001&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site.&#34;&gt;Elimination of Sleeping Sickness&lt;/a&gt;
that talked about how political and social conflict within Sudan could lead to a cure for sleeping sickness to be halted. It was a very interesting to see how these disease is still affecting those in Sudan for over 100 years. Also, this article gave me an insight into how modern medicine is now begin used to treat early disease from the 1900s that have caused much harm an area.  The graphs for the analysis of sleeping sickness in Sudan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Kasr-el-Ainy&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;
-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Cairo&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;
-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Sudan&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;
-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Gordon College&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/t/dorseydigitalmircolab/views/SleepingSicknessandtrypanosomiasiswithinSudan/Sheet1?:origin=card_share_link&amp;:embed=n:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/#/site/dorseydigitalmircolab/workbooks/60188?:origin=card_share_link&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/t/dorseydigitalmircolab/views/TropicalDiseasesinCairoandSudan/Sheet1?:origin=card_share_link&amp;:embed=n:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/#/site/dorseydigitalmircolab/workbooks/60187?:origin=card_share_link&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diseases&#34;&gt;Diseases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A disease that appeared in the newspaper was the Bubonic Plague or also known as the Third Pandemic. The earliest records of the Bubonic Plague within &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was found on January second of 1905. However, according to history, the first outbreaks of the plague in Egypt took place back in April of 1899 after a long time of disease-free (
&lt;a href=&#34;www.jstor.org/stable/20436191.&#34;&gt;Plague In Egypt&lt;/a&gt;
). The plague has persisted in Egypt each year since 1899 arriving from the trade ports. With that said, that means that the cities closest to the ports must be the ones most affected by it. After gathering the following data through the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and inputting it into Tableau, this statement proved to be correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Bubonicplaguechartdata/Sheet2?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown above, the city that was most frequently affected by the Bubonic Plague was Alexandria. Following Alexandria was Suez, which also has a huge trade port that connects the Red Sea with the Mediterranean Sea. However, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; newspaper explained another possibility of why this might be the case. &amp;ldquo;It is the only town with a drainage system, and many of the drains are in a very dilapidated condition and infested with rats. This may be one of the reasons which account for the persistence of the disease at Alexandria&amp;rdquo; (1906-07-27.xml).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a considerable diminution in the number of cases of plague in Egypt as in the year of 1905. However, the following year, in 1906, the plague spread and the number of cases severely increased. In comparison with 1904, there was a considerable diminution in the number of cases of plague in Egypt as in the year of 1905. However, the following year, 1906, the plague spread and the number of cases severely increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to preventing the spread of this plague, “Clayton Gas” was used in the early 1900s. It destroyed not only rats and vermin, but also the parasites on them and sterilized the eggs of insects as well. Since no cures were discovered until 20 years later, preventions taken towards infected humans were unsuccessful. An important thing to notice is that the infected rat is the cause of the disease remaining endemic in a town, but the epidemic form of the disease is caused by the infected human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph shows how mentions of ad have no correlation to mentions of cholera throughout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/cholera_15753985669840/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one advertisement claims to remedy cholera, diarrhea, colic, and dysentery, and that product is Dr. J. Collis Browne’s Chlorodyne.  Surprisingly enough, the product is only advertised fourteen times over the three years or so of the newspaper that has been encoded.  Further research into Chlorodyne revealed that the medication was an effective treatment for these diseases as well as other ailments not listed in the advertisements.  The reasoning behind its effectiveness were the active ingredients being opiates and marijuana (McCabe, 1979) .  Interestingly enough this advertisement that claims to remedy cholera do not seem to have any correlation to when cholera was mentioned more frequently in the newspaper, even as fears of cholera began to spread within Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an editorial by Charles McCabe written in 1979, he recalls the days when Dr. J. Collis Browne’s Chlorodyne was available everywhere.  McCabe described the potion as  “a staple of British medicine cabinets since 1848.”  He further states that chlorodyne took “care of the most persistent of the traveler’s and imperialist complaints, dysentery of one kind or another.  It [was] also good for hangovers.  It subdues the screaming angst.  It is one of the best sleeping potions I know.”  He further states that the modern version of chlorodyne, which they now call “J. Collis Browne’s Mixture” is not as effective as the older version.  The original concoction was able to “combat ‘colds, coughs, influenza, diarrhea, stomach chills, cholic…” etc. the list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, this advertisement was not run many times over the course of our repository.  And this is strange being that Charles McCabes testimony, although from 1979, was very convincing of how well this product works in treating an assortment of ailments.  Maybe the advertising budget in Alexandria, Egypt at the time was not much, and that&amp;rsquo;s why the ad was not widely published.  According to McCabe, this medicine was widely published throughout British newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of an ongoing disease plaguing both Egypt and Europe during this time period was tuberculosis. At the beginning of the 19th century treatments consisted of the encouragement of adopting a new lifestyle. Hiking, eating fruits and vegetables, and fresh air were very common examples of this change in “bad living”. As this became outdated, the development of sanatoriums became more acceptable. Due to the lack of technology and understanding of immunology, antibiotics and vaccinations had not yet been invented, therefore, bed rest in a sanatorium was really the only option for the individuals infected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Tuberculosisstats/Story1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bar graph displays the frequency of tuberculosis mentioned within the Egyptian Gazette, primarily in the local and general section. Ads such as Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills for Pale People and Puruna feature other disorders and medical conflicts. These include paralysis, rheumatism, and ladies’ complaints. Oddly, however, is the neglect to mention tuberculosis, the infamous “white plague”. Clearly this is a little puzzling seeing how tuberculosis was in many local and general headlines as a deadly concern of the population. This confirms the idea that medical advances were very limited at this time in Egypt and Europe as they were never featured in pill ads that claimed to be the cure-all, miraculously relieving a patient in a matter of days. Many methods and trials probably failed or were not worth mentioning in the Gazette since readers might have been more interested in hearing about success stories rather than failed attempts at one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disease and sickness was a hot topic during this time of uncertainty and doubt, paving the way for big time advertisers to market their ideas and sell an abundance of pill bottles of color- coated candy that claimed to cure everything when in reality, they couldn’t cure a headache. But much of what was not understood during this time can be directly related to what lead to the later understanding of medicine and immunology that we possess today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuberculosis and Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-heflin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-heflin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tuberculosis was the major threat of the 19th century in both Europe and North America that killed one victim in England and Wales every five minutes. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30656236&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sanatorium&lt;/a&gt;
 movement labeled tuberculosis as a disease caused by one&amp;rsquo;s way of life and could be prevented and treated by fresh air, exercise, and good nutrition in a sanatorium. Sanatoriums were hospitals for long term illnesses like TB before the invention of antibiotics. Very common it was treated by rest in bed in hospital through the second half of 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peruna ads do not contain tuberculosis though it is clearly an issue and had major news coverage. Little to none was known about illnesses like tuberculosis leaving medical professionals scratching their heads. Perhaps trials were done but were deemed unsuccessful, and therefore, not published in the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there were no new drugs on the market for tuberculosis, action was being taken in other avenues. A village in Italy named Salsomaggiore became famous for its waters rich in various nutrients such as bromine, iodine, and lithium that were used to treat rheumatism, tuberculosis, and ladies’ complaints. The Anti-Tuberculosis League worked to educate the public when news headlines disclosed that tuberculosis was a concern in Egypt. This group blamed the outbreak of the disease on the ignorance of natives and part of the European population to hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a telegram I found a heading referring to “Bovine tuberculosis” and that it had been discovered to be communicable through raw milk in 1907 which left me to infer that at this time Egypt and Europe had not yet created any pasteurization laws or pasteurized milk was difficult to obtain for certain populations. However, I recalled an ad entitled “Howie’s Sterilized Milk or Cream” which was targeted to those traveling to Europe as well as young children. This ad starting to appear in the Gazette even in the year 1905, before it was circulated in telegrams in sent in 1907. Perhaps no laws yet required the pasteurization of milk and only those that could afford sterilized milk bought it and the rest were left more susceptible to tuberculosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the query //div[(@type=&amp;ldquo;advert&amp;rdquo;) or (@type=&amp;ldquo;advertisement&amp;rdquo;)]/p originally to see if there were any advertisements that contained either TB or Tuberculosis, and I came up with only one ad in the local and general section that was not really supposed to be tagged as an ad. After that, I was curious as to how many times just the word “tuberculosis” appeared with no restriction and got 78 results. I then decided that since there were so little results, that I would just go through these one at a time to see what information I could gather most of which I touched on above. Furthermore, I created a visualization comparing the frequency of tuberculosis per month and per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Tuberculosisstats/Story1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years 1905-1907 September, October, and May had the most mentions of tuberculosis. This may be correlated to weather conditions or an overall decrease in cases due to the establishment of more hospitals and sanatoriums. In October of 1905 a Professor by the name of Behring claimed of a new remedy, but this new remedy was never officially disclosed. This new remedy could have possibly been revealed as insufficient and was therefore not retouched in the Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many ads like Dr. William’s Pink Pills for Pale People, which claimed to be the cure all by purifying the blood or even making new blood, since at the time bad blood was thought to be a trigger for disease, you would think tuberculosis would be included in their long list of curable diseases. I personally do not know a lot about tuberculosis and its status in the medical world today, so I decided to do a little more digging to see how medical breakthroughs have altered the occurrence and elimination of the disease currently and how this is compares to Egypt in the early 1900s. What I found from an article by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3125027/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;US National Library of Medicine and the National Institute of Health&lt;/a&gt;
 was that to the World Health Organization (WHO), TB is still a worldwide epidemic. In 2010 WHO declared that about 1/3 of the world’s population was infected by TB, which is not very far from 2019. Doctors even face issues with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/tb/topic/drtb/default.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;drug-resistant strains&lt;/a&gt;
of the disease which lead to further modifications of treatment. Of course, we have witnessed ground-breaking discoveries in treating and preventing the spread of TB by the development of vaccines as well as antibiotics since the 1900s but there is still a lot of guesswork done in the treatment and management of tuberculosis, a lot similar to the nature of medical intervention mentioned in Egypt and Europe between the years 1904 and 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty in Pink</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-breannaheflin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-breannaheflin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s casualties were in abundance due to a lack of understanding of the human body. Disease and illness became an everyday battle for those who had been discharged as “incurable” with no hope for a healthy life. Marketing ploys done for many “patented” drugs, such as “Dr. William’s Pink Pills for Pale People”, fed on this vulnerability not knowing that many diseases did not even require medical intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pink Pills for Pale People” grew immensely in Great Britain and North America for their shiny pink coat and claims to cure TB, rickets, kidney diseases, and even 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://macdonaldtownbicycleclub.com/2017/04/24/mrs-e-j-curtis-paralysed-with-rheumatism-restored-to-active-health-by-dr-williams-pink-pills/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paralysis&lt;/a&gt;
. A new “miracle” drug had been invented that seemed to cure fatal diseases in a matter of days,  purifying the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kshs.org/kansapedia/pink-pills-for-pale-people/10240&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“bad blood”&lt;/a&gt;
 that resulted in muscle and nerve disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One case was that of a young daughter named Sophie Caspeele who suffered from a severe case of anemia: chronic weakness, loss of appetite, and poor digestion. Claiming to cure female ailments, marketing practices such as this one tugged on the heart strings of parents and suffering women. The pills became well-known and named for the healthy complexion that they restored to its patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bmh19/blog-posts/master/2019-10-17-Breanna%20Heflin/Pink%20Pills.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sophie Caspeele&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, the famous “Pink Pills” were discovered to contain merely “extract of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wellcomelibrary.org/2015/03/dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Barbadoes&lt;/a&gt;
 aloes enclosed in a thick coating of sugar, colored with pink carmine”, yet continued to be sold into the 20th century. The “Pink Pills” were eventually exposed for quackery and withdrawn in the UK in 1970.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though still flawed, this case of medical negligence shows the improvement needed and made within the pharmaceutical industry relied on by many even today. Marketing strategies fool us similarly in the 21st century as they did in the 20th with physical appeals and claims of the unbelievable happening, because it is not actually happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;similar-blog-posts&#34;&gt;Similar blog posts:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pink Pills for Pale People&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Miraculous Medicine&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Pills for Pale People</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of clickbait, tabloid papers, and fake news, it&amp;rsquo;s still nice to see that we haven&amp;rsquo;t changed a bit. This is a classic example of a snake oil salesmen at work. Dr. Williams&#39; Pink Pills are said to cure Anaemia, Indigestion, Eczema, Rheumatism, Sciatica, St. Vitus’ Dance, Neuralgia, Nervous Disorders, Paralysis, and Locomotor Ataxy. Since the pills did have ferrous sulphate or just Iron sulphate, it would have an effect on the anemic. This however, is still a scam because the amount that was in his pink pills was much less than actual medicine and because of this, the pills were much weaker and were more expensive than just the regular iron pills doctors would usually prescribe. This is probably one of the only pills that are in song, while the song is a critique of commercialism in society, it was sung by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wu2V3TkHufA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Benny Bell&lt;/a&gt;
. Also something that intrigued me was that you can still 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springbokpharmacy.co.za/Product?product_id=354130&amp;amp;category_id=33098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;buy these pills&lt;/a&gt;
 online to cure basically anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://diseasesofmodernlife.org/2016/11/29/pills-for-our-ills-dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;elaborate backstory&lt;/a&gt;
 of the company and pills, as well as how they fared in Asian markets.
[Pink Pills](1907-05-20-p5 selection)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trend of snake oil pills being sold in The Egyptian Gazette is not a new one. Looking through other blog posts I saw a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Esteve-Medicine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt;
 about &amp;ldquo;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Backache Kidney Pills&amp;rdquo;. The man who used it was told he only had 3 months to live but after some pills, he made a miraculous recovery! Another post follows the same vein of a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/baxter-Peruna/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;miraculous medicine&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miraculous Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Ida Caldwell, a seemingly sweet old lady, has been suffering with “catarrh of the respiratory organs on and off for the last three years”. She had to use her greatest care not to “expose herself to chilly air or dampness as it increased her troubles.” She was advised to change her climate, but she couldn’t leave her family so she had to stay put. Then she was introduced to Peruna which relieved her of her pain in three days, and she was completely cured in two months. What a miracle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post seemed like a serious article about a well-known woman who seemed to be in a lot of pain due to her &amp;ldquo;catarrh of her lungs.&amp;rdquo; However, when I kept reading, I noticed that it was just a gimmicky ad for a sketchy medicine that claimed to &amp;ldquo;cure symptoms of the common cold.&amp;rdquo; The ad seemed really convincing, and I almost believed that this woman had her illness cured because of this medicine. On the downside, I did notice that this ad sounded a lot like the ones I hear today, which seems quite interesting, that advertisements haven’t changed that much since 1906. This was a very interesting, well put together ad, and I do believe that a lot of people would have jumped at the chance to buy this medicine upon reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Boil Your Water</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-01-ferguson.katherine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-01-ferguson.katherine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Typhoid fever ravaged many armies, including the Egyptian. Therefore, extensive research was conducted in order to identify the source of infection and how to prevent it. Dr. Leigh Canney was on the forefront of this field in Egypt during the 19th century. “Dr. Leigh Canney was able to produce evidence from the reports of the Army Medical Department to show that the Army was ‘sanitarily untrained and unprotected’”. Furthermore, he recognized that enteric disease came from unsanitary water. However, the Army Medical Department did not want to hear it; this was not the answer they were looking for. Sir T. Gallaway argued against boiling water before drinking stating that, “all our schemes for sterilization of water by boiling or otherwise have had no effect.” Dr. Leigh Canney persisted on not only the sterilization, but also the preservation of clean water. He urged the Army to keep clean water in enclosed clean bottles to prevent contact with flies and dust which could cause recontamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days after this article was posted, on December 6, 1905, a letter to the editor was published regarding the issues faced when implementing the rules on sanitary water. The author states that boiling water and allowing it to cool after a hard days work in the desert is simply impossible, and “the system is not sufficiently practical to hold water”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both sides of the argument have made valid points, we now know that sanitizing drinking water is essential. Contaminated water houses pathogens such as Typhoid, Cholera, and a plethora of others. Although Typhoid had been identified in 1880, a vaccine 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news-medical.net/health/Typhoid-Fever-History.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;was not developed and distributed until 1896&lt;/a&gt;
. The chlorination of water during the 20th century also reduced Typhoid prevalence. Currently, India, Pakistan and Egypt are “
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.medicinenet.com/typhoid_fever/article.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;known as high risk areas for developing this disease&lt;/a&gt;
.” 21 million people are infected annually worldwide, with over 200,000 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Killer</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-soap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a time when merchandise regulation is not nearly as controlled as it is now, it can be expected that there will be defaults in the products produced. [Salicylate of soda](
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2220712/?page=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2220712/?page=1&lt;/a&gt;
 Define Salicylate of Soda&amp;quot;) was thought to have restorative effects during the mid to late 19th century. It was often recommended to people with joint disease, such as rheumatism, to alleviate pain.  At first the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1322509/?page=7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;negative side effects&lt;/a&gt;
 associated with salicylate of soda reported were minor, like a relapse in pain after the salicylate of soda was no longer being used. Many users had to be gradually weaned from the chemical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;soap-ad.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunlight Soap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years after its use in soap, physicians began noting that people who were repeated salicylate of soda users had painful skin and there was even a case of failing vision after taking a bath in the soap with the chemicals. In the early 1900s, manufacturers of soap products containing the chemical were ordered to stop production and were prosecuted by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=5a-Uc3NJuPUC&amp;amp;pg=PA206&amp;amp;lpg=PA206&amp;amp;dq=1905&amp;#43;egyptian&amp;#43;sanitary&amp;#43;administration&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=pGXkko-vu3&amp;amp;sig=P6WCUO4P1BmN_u7Zm8Ny2nSY3Dc&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi60p_rs4zQAhWSZiYKHXwdDTMQ6AEIHTAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=1905%20egyptian%20sanitary%20administration&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sanitary administration&lt;/a&gt;
. Large soap companies during this time, like Pears’ Soap, were not being advertised because of the ordeal. Instead, the same issue of the newspaper that published the harmful soap announcement had an ad for Sunlight Soap, which advertises its lack of “obnoxious or harmful feature.” This small news brief gives insight about this time period, showing its lack of medical knowledge and its clever marketing methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pear-soap.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pear Soap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-esteve-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-esteve-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-mans-trash-is-another-mans-treasure&#34;&gt;One Man&amp;rsquo;s Trash is Another Man&amp;rsquo;s Treasure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, a man wrote to the Egyptian Gazette about the stricture and kidney disease that he had suffered with for 19 years. After living with excruciating pain and being told that he would only have three months to live, this man began taking Doan&amp;rsquo;s Backache Kidney Pills.&lt;br&gt;
I was immediately curious about this, because 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pics.drugstore.com/prodimg/498956/450.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Backache Kidney Pills&lt;/a&gt;
 are a cheap, over the counter drug that people use today. While someone today might take these pills to relieve minor back pain, this man believes that they saved his life. This speaks a great deal to the quality of medicine during the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern day America, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medlineplus.gov/magazine/issues/winter08/articles/winter08pg9-10.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;kidney disease&lt;/a&gt;
 is often not curable and can usually only be delayed with extensive treatment and medication. As time passes and it gets worse, dialysis or a transplant is needed. I mention all of this to draw attention to the diagnosis of the man in the Egyptian Gazette. He suffered for 19 years and was diagnosed with three months to live, yet an over the counter drug managed to save his life. Either drugs were much better 100 years ago, or he was severely misdiagnosed. People often take for granted the high level of medicine and easy access to treatment that exists throughout the world today. I wonder how much of an impact old-fashioned medicine had on other people living in the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
