<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/technology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>technology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>technology</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/technology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Fingerprint Evidence</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-carolinebanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-carolinebanks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fingerprinting technology was first developed as a method of crime solving for police in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crimescene-forensics.com/History_of_Fingerprints.html&#34;&gt;1901 in India.&lt;/a&gt; England was the first country to make this system of classifying and using fingerprints official in its police forces. With Alexandria being occupied by England in the early 1900’s, this new technology quickly spread to Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, fingerprinting was not the foolproof method of crime fighting we know it to be today. In 1905, people in Alexandria were excited about this new technology, but could not trust it fully. The underdeveloped technique often provided incorrect results which caused people to be fearful of wrongful convictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even today, there are problems with faulty fingerprint evidence resulting in &lt;a href=&#34;https://heinonline.org/HOL/Page?handle=hein.journals/ggulr37&amp;amp;div=10&amp;amp;g_sent=1&amp;amp;casa_token=&amp;amp;collection=journals&#34;&gt;wrongful convictions&lt;/a&gt; and the technology has been improved upon for over one hundred years. There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14714787.2016.1147978&#34;&gt;theory&lt;/a&gt; that part of the reason fingerprinting became so popular in England and British occupied countries was that it helped the British keep track of those under their control without any cultural barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingerprinting is a universal way to identify people that does not require those people to speak the same language and therefore is less likely to be deceptive. This article from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; warns the public of the mistakes that can be made when the police are not trained well enough to interpret fingerprint evidence; however, it still supports the use of the technology when done correctly. The view of this article seems to support the British view on the emerging technology of fingerprint evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Troubles</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-technology-troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-technology-troubles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first few weeks of this semester I was completely dedicated to toiling for hours in order to receive an “A” in this class. I would stay up until midnight finishing editing text that was OCRd making sure that no detail was overlooked. I would spend hours working on this editing only to go back to it and find that all of my hard work had either disappeared or been undone and not for lack of saving. When I started working with Oxygen, I would find that a file I had just started coding the previous night could not be found when I went to open and edit it the next day. This setback has been a source of major frustration for obvious reasons. I don’t know whether this unfortunate series of events is occurring because of some delayed karma or because I have the dreaded apple computer but it has caused me to become lazy with the workload. That being said, I have prayed to the computer gods to fix my issues so I can save my grade and it seems to have worked so far. In the wake of my realization about how quickly the semester is coming to an end I have kicked back into gear and have decided to push through any and all technical difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
