<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>advertisement | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/advertisement/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/advertisement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>advertisement</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>advertisement</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/advertisement/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>H &amp; C Flick, Cigar Importers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-flick-h-c-flick-cigar-importers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-flick-h-c-flick-cigar-importers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egyptian_cigarette_industry#cite_note-5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Egyptian cigarette industry&lt;/a&gt; was one of the main exports in Egypt during the time period from the 1880s to the end of the World War I. Just from reading one week of issues of the Egyptian Gazette, I could tell that cigarettes were a major part of an Egyptian’s life. There was at least one advertisement for cigarettes on each page of the newspaper, but one specific advertisement in particular stood out to me the most: “H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, Cigar Importers.” Now this specific ad might not sound important to anyone else, but to me it was very interesting and got me thinking about my ancestry. I am 99.9% sure that I am not related to these Flick’s, but I wonder what it would be like to be a Flick in Egypt in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1905, Egypt imported a total of 8,078 tonnes of tobacco and a total of 8,377 tonnes in 1906 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=qs_YlWuFjooC&amp;amp;lpg=PR3&amp;amp;pg=PA59#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Relli Shechter, &lt;em&gt;Smoking, Culture and Economy in the Middle East: The Egyptian Tobacco Market 1850-2000&lt;/em&gt;, p. 59 &lt;/a&gt;). The advertisement states that H. &amp;amp; C. Flick was the largest depot of cigars in Egypt, so I can imagine that Flick’s were a very successful in 1906 due to the increase in cigar imports from 1905 to 1906.  Egyptian tobacco was usually very poorly made and didn’t taste very well, so most of the cigarettes in Egypt were not made from Egyptian tobacco (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/41339516?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES AND TOBACCO, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Society of Arts&lt;/em&gt; Vol. 59, No. 3034 (JANUARY 13, 1911), pp. 201-203&lt;/a&gt;). Due to Egyptian tobacco not being up to par with what most tourists and immigrants are used to, being a cigarette importer was probably a very good business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I might not actually be related to H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, I now know that it would probably be a good family business in Egypt in 1906, but it might be harder to be a cigar importer in the United States in 2017 due to all the information about how terrible cigarettes are for our health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Blog Post by ALEX CALIENDO: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants that make ice?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-morales-plants-that-make-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-morales-plants-that-make-ice/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While going through the newspaper, OCR-ing it, and transcribing it to XML, I usually don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention to what&amp;rsquo;s written. Not because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to - but because I go through it so fast, I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to. Until I came across this interesting advertisement. At a quick glance of the page, it immediately caught my attention. Yes, the big letters aided in that, but what was in the title is what really got me puzzled. &amp;ldquo;Ice Making Plants&amp;rdquo;? I thought, there’s &lt;em&gt;no way&lt;/em&gt; they found plants that make ice. Upon continuing to read I saw it said &amp;ldquo;Power Driven Machines to produce 1 cwt. Per 24 hours&amp;rdquo; (or about 1lb ≈ every 15 mins). So now I drew another conclusion – they’ve made robotic plants that make ice instead of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this couldn’t be correct so I took it upon myself to call the number on the ad and ask – but &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I got a &amp;ldquo;Your call could not be completed as dialed&amp;rdquo; (must have been a typo). Unfortunately, they didn’t put an email I could contact so I went to my backup-backup plan and scoured the web. After adequate research, I came to my last conclusion: This misleading ad sold ice machines crankable by hand that could be used in &lt;strong&gt;factory&lt;/strong&gt; plants to produce a lot of ice. I also concluded that the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Engineering Co., LTD.&amp;rdquo; didn’t come up with the product, it just resold it as a white label. The RAPLIN originally came from England in the 1890s made by &amp;ldquo;Pulsometer Engineering Co., LTD&amp;rdquo; which continued to manufacture ice machines and other advancements throughout the years. Who knew &lt;del&gt;an innocent&lt;/del&gt; a deceptive advertisement from the early 1900s could get a person from the 21st century so well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=kBMpAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA110&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1898&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ice and Refrigeration Illustrated Vol. 14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=mj5FAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA233&amp;amp;lpg=RA1-PA233&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1898&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Practical Engineer. Volume XVII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=cwsAAAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA20&amp;amp;lpg=PA20&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1899&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XXIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gracesguide.co.uk/Pulsometer_Engineering_Co:_1914_Catalogue&#34; title=&#34;Catalogue of Pulsometer&#39;s machines&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pulsometer Engineering Co: 1914 Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=PYdJAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA172&amp;amp;lpg=PA172&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1908&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XLIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pictures&#34;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RAPLIN_Ice_Machine_Cleaned_Up.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine&#34; /&gt; | &lt;img src=&#34;Raplin_Ice_Machine_V2_Cleaned_up.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine V2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
