<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>crime | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/crime/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>crime</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>crime</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/crime/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Haul of Hashish</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-celinebenedico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-celinebenedico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 16th, 1907, Wednesday&amp;rsquo;s issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was released. In this issue of the newspaper, on the third page, there was an article referring to a recent seize of £5,000 worth Hashish from Mr. H.C. Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s home. The article was published in the newspaper next to the Government Measures column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article explained that Mr. Parkinson, the owner of the home, kept hearing strange noises in his house, and when he went to look around he was surprised to see a light on in his kitchen. He brushed it off and went back to sleep, but awoke to more noises. Arming himself with a loaded revolver, he went outside and stumbled over a large sack and soon realized that hashish was being landed. Mr. Parkinson rang the Coast Guard and when they arrived they found eighteen sacks of hashish around the enclosure. The selling price of this amount of hashish costs L.E. 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s suffragee was to blame for the amount of hashish and was taken into custody. It was found that the hashish brought over was from Greece, and ten smugglers were burying it up from Mr. Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s yard when it all belonged to the suffragee. Was it a random act or were the smugglers trying to get Mr. Parkinson in trouble? Was the suffragee trying to get Mr. Parkinson in trouble? No follow ups arised in the future columns, but to my understanding the sufragee is still in jail.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Fingerprint Evidence</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-carolinebanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-carolinebanks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fingerprinting technology was first developed as a method of crime solving for police in 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crimescene-forensics.com/History_of_Fingerprints.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;1901 in India.&lt;/a&gt;
 England was the first country to make this system of classifying and using fingerprints official in its police forces. With Alexandria being occupied by England in the early 1900’s, this new technology quickly spread to Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, fingerprinting was not the foolproof method of crime fighting we know it to be today. In 1905, people in Alexandria were excited about this new technology, but could not trust it fully. The underdeveloped technique often provided incorrect results which caused people to be fearful of wrongful convictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even today, there are problems with faulty fingerprint evidence resulting in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://heinonline.org/HOL/Page?handle=hein.journals/ggulr37&amp;amp;div=10&amp;amp;g_sent=1&amp;amp;casa_token=&amp;amp;collection=journals&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wrongful convictions&lt;/a&gt;
 and the technology has been improved upon for over one hundred years. There is also a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14714787.2016.1147978&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;theory&lt;/a&gt;
 that part of the reason fingerprinting became so popular in England and British occupied countries was that it helped the British keep track of those under their control without any cultural barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingerprinting is a universal way to identify people that does not require those people to speak the same language and therefore is less likely to be deceptive. This article from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; warns the public of the mistakes that can be made when the police are not trained well enough to interpret fingerprint evidence; however, it still supports the use of the technology when done correctly. The view of this article seems to support the British view on the emerging technology of fingerprint evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cairo Motor Car Fatality</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-robertklein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-robertklein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, September 4th, 1907, located on the third page under the column the Financial Advisor, the article explains how pedestrians are frustrated after the death of a native notable. The family opposed the exhumation of their body in order to establish who was responsible. Regulations, in accordance to the speed of drivers, were hoped to be enacted after this seemingly senseless death. People also hoped that drivers would be held responsible if future accidents, such as the one this section mentions, occurred. The article states that a majority of accidents from cars are caused from &amp;ldquo;furious&amp;rdquo; driving. This can be implied to mean that drivers were driving recklessly at the time, due to the minimal amount of driving regulations at the time of the accident. There were a considerable amount of complaints, and the author of the article mentions that they would not be surprised if pedestrians began to take measures into their own hands if laws were not enacted quickly and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Domestic Tragedy</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article tells the story of a divorced couple that ultimately ended in fatality. In attempts to fix his relationship, the spouse tried to convince his former wife to get back together. However, when she refused, he got angry and stabbed her multiple times. After this violent and impulsive reaction had subsided, the man realized what he had done, and thinking he had killed his spouse, he drew a revolver and shot himself dead. However, the woman simply fell unconscious and did not die.
This story has a theme similar to Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; pertaining to the story of a spouse thinking his partner is dead and consequentially killing himself because of that thought. It also shows that people would do anything for love, and that people act irrationally when they are put in desperate situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, domestic violence was not uncommon, as shown in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matthew Cooper&amp;rsquo;s blog post&lt;/a&gt;
. Here Cooper talks about an article on a man who killed his wife with an blow to the head by a bar of iron. Although the context is different between the two instances, it is clear that abuse within marriages was not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Execution</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-squires/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-squires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; shows that &lt;strong&gt;Double executions&lt;/strong&gt; took place in the early 1900s, especially for murder. In this short article, the two murderers jointly murdered Ibrahim Khalif and in return were hung four months later at the prison. Both men claimed they were wrongly convicted of the crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result for double execution showed up only within two articles of &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; including on July 7, 1905 and within my issue in 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of double executions has pretty much diminished in many nations. In Egypt, they still perform 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_punishment_in_Egypt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hanging executions&lt;/a&gt;
, but since each convict has to go before a jury, double executions haven&amp;rsquo;t taken place for awhile. In the U.S. Arkansas was the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/04/24/525385016/arkansas-prepares-for-first-double-execution-in-u-s-since-2000&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;last state to have performed a double execution&lt;/a&gt;
 which was a few hours apart and for different crimes. These &amp;ldquo;double executions&amp;rdquo; are different than what Alexandria would have done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Man, One Horse</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-rodriguez-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-rodriguez-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Murders overall aren’t that common, so it was even more surprising when I found out that there was a murderous horse on the loose! On July 7, 1906, it was reported that a man sneaked into the yard of a resident. Even though his intentions were never discovered it is assumed by the article that his sole goal was to steal a horse. When in the process of untying the ropes of the animal, the horse kicked him square in the face, killing him instantly. This is one thief that never got a second chance. It makes me wonder if there are any other murderous animals in Alexandria, other than the everyday man. If it wasn’t for the horse killing him I believe the owner would have killed him if caught. I came to this conclusion after reading many articles having to do with thieves and criminals. Even if it wasn’t the owner the police would have surely caught him because according to the newspaper they have an excellent arrest rate. Yet the fate of this poor man was surely set the minute he decided to trespass on someone’s property. Upon reading this I am almost certain that thieves all over the city were either scared of stealing any more horses, or that they were just more careful when stealing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
