<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>news</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>news</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest in Peace Miss F. Collins</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-15-austink/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-15-austink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking through my papers and noticed an interesting article that didn&#39;t seem to align with the theme of the local newsletter. In the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, mostly everything is generalized and for the benefit of the reader but there was a section titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baltimoresun.com/news/bs-xpm-2002-02-17-0202160131-story.html&#34;&gt;Obituary&lt;/a&gt; and it was interesting because it was on one specific person. As I read I realized that even though she did just seem like another local, the point of the article was to show how &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalthinkersforum.org/our-impact/each-and-everyone-of-us-is-unique-and-important-and-no-one-is-insignificant/&#34;&gt;every citizen is important&lt;/a&gt; and it made sure to explain how she was a quality person and her death was to be mourned as many of the locals in Luxor and Cairo cared for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Each and Everyone of Us Is Unique and Important, and No-one Is Insignificant”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this fascinating because there are two other instances I found while browsing through the blog posts in which the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; has done this.
For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-baenen-deathofthepasha/&#34;&gt;In the death of Haicalis Pasha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/&#34;&gt;Death of Mr. Hanna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both instances the newsletter is reporting local deaths and it shows that the community do care about its people and that no passing is meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the important things that was pointed out in the Obituary is how Miss Collins spent a majority of her time at church and actually passed while at a Sunday Service. It is safe to assume that she is now in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everystudent.com/journeys/then.html&#34;&gt;Heaven&lt;/a&gt; because not only did she realize God but also lived an honest life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
