<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>murder | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/murder/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/murder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>murder</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>murder</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/murder/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maxim Gorki</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-05-chacon-gorki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-05-chacon-gorki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something that has caught my eye while reading these articles from March 1905 to April 1905 is that on the first issue on the third day, there is a small article about a man by the name of Maxim Gorki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says he is to be prosecuted because charges have been given to him that he drafted proclamations aiming to overthrow the existing state of the Empire. It also says his health has broken down and that he is liable to three years of detention in a fortress. It also then gives the day of the trial. Gorki is said to be in a place called Riga and is under surveillance. I find this curious because I would like to know more information on this matter. I would also like to know how the trial ended up. I also find it curious because it is such a small article about this man&#39;s prosecution. I would think it would be longer. I would also like to know about the place, Riga, that he is in and if he is such a dangerous criminal that he has to be under surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Dates</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-deadly-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-deadly-dates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You love your family but there’s always those cousins that just annoy you so much that sometimes you just want to feed them some poisoned dates so you don’t have to deal with them anymore. Well that’s precisely what one man of Makhadoora village did to his cousins in May of 1905. This nameless man injected compressed dates with enough of a deadly poison to kill those who ate it. He then gave these deadly fruits to five of his cousins, two men and three women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three women ate the dates and “expired in great agony.” Now if you are not a psychopath, you might be confused as to why this man decided to off his cousins and especially in such a cruel and painful way. Did they inherit a large sum of money from grandma while the killer only received the nice china? Did they eat all of the stuffing at Thanksgiving when they knew it was his favorite?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to the lack of information provided about a motive or even a name for the killer, the world may never know. One thing that is known however, is that this event did cause “considerable excitement” throughout the neighborhood due to the simple fact that it was a murder as opposed to an accidental date poisoning. In my opinion, this fact implies that the neighborhood in Keneh where the murders took place was not used to this violence which might mean that it was a fairly well-off neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that the motive could involve money? It could certainly be a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wife Murder</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-cooper-wife-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-cooper-wife-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the twenty-fourth of January, an incident involving a woman and her enraged husband occurred. The man killed his wife by hitting her on the head using a metal bar made of iron and fled the scene. The former clerk from Gabbari has yet to be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motive for committing this heinous crime is unknown. Perhaps his wife was cheating on him or maybe she cooked him a poor meal. I find it interesting that an event of this magnitude is not given a bigger article. Someone&#39;s life has been ended and there is a possibility that others may be in danger. More information should be provided and this news story should not be shrugged off as an every day occurrence. Either way, the suspect is still at large and he needs to be caught before he spreads his mayhem elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Fight between Greeks</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-doublemurder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-doublemurder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of January 3rd, 1905, two men were murdered behind a bar.
The man responsible is around 20 years old and is very physically fit.
His name is Yanni Antonio Stigrigo and was supposedly in love with the
sister of his victims. Ironically, one of the men he killed would have
made a good husband for his own sister. A fight broke out between the
three men and Yanni was quick to take out his weapon and stab the first brother one time, then stabbed the other brother two times. The second brother was taken to the Greek hospital, but died around midnight. Yanni was arrested outside of Cairo Railway Station and was easily apprehended. He followed police demands and quietly allowed them to put him in handcuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who wants to study murderers and their psychological aspects, I would like to know what the fight was about that made him think killing was the only answer. Due to the love interests involved between the three men, I suspect the fight was relevant to marriage. Of course, crimes like this still occur all over the world everyday. Bar fights are very common, mostly because people become angrier when they are intoxicated and cannot control their behaviors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent example took place in 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kjrh.com/news/local-news/police-are-investigating-double-homicide-in-n-tulsa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tulsa&lt;/a&gt;
. Bar fights happen every night and can occasionally turn deadly if someone does not step in soon enough. The most well known murder at a bar recently was the Orlando night club shooting. Of course, this was a hate crime but still comes to show that similar things happen everyday, this case being particularly extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;barfight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bar fight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the double murder that took place in 1905 in Egypt is similar to events in modern day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder In Cairo</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-oulette-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-oulette-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 1905-04-18 Egidio Gerona was ironically murdered upon entering a catholic church in the Mousky. The cause of death came from two bullets fired by a man by the name of Fabio Ninci. Following the incident the murderer was apprehended without resistance outside of the church. The police discovered a few connections between the two men, including their Italian nationality and prior employment. Apparently the murderer had been discharged from the Telephone Company where M. Gerona also worked. The discharge he attributed to M. Gerona, who worked as an electrician the and the murderer sought to avenge himself. In my opinion, the man took his actions way too far, especially over working as a wires-man. With his poor judgment an innocent man was tragically murdered and he put himself away in the central native prison. Two others instances of murder are reported in the paper. First, a Greek band attacked a Bulgarian village, resulting in 15 deaths. The other instance involved the Turks killing 30 Albanians near the town. These reports show  the hectic condition that Macedonia is currently facing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
