<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imperialism | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/imperialism/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/imperialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Imperialism</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Imperialism</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/imperialism/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>English in the Courts</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ooten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ooten/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short article published on February 25th 1907 is about the first time that English was used as the judicial language in a court case. This is one of many language related events that occurred after the British took control of Egypt as an imperial power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Egypt, and Alexandria in particular, there are many different people speaking many different languages, this causes many conflicts throughout the years. This article shows that attempts were being made by the British to push their agenda ahead through the bureaucracy of Egypt and acquire power from both of the other powers competing for control of the territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the courts in Egypt are different than the ones we know today, European powers had already had a fair amount of influence on how the courts were set up and run. Based on this the British clearly already had a basic framework from which to build off of, and during their occupation only took further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite this it still took the British many years to reach the point of where they were able to get English. This allowance and then use of English in the judicial language of the court provides us with an interesting point of reference of just how long it took for Cromer to gain a modicum of control of this part of Egyptian society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be compared to other points of British influence to determine if the British were took a long time to get this far with only this issue or if this was a common time frame for how long it could take for an effort such as this one to come to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://digitalcommons.law.uga.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2283&amp;amp;context=gjicl&#34;&gt;http://digitalcommons.law.uga.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2283&amp;amp;context=gjicl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/British-Imperialism/&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/British-Imperialism/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Imperialism</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-british-imperialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-british-imperialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.historyworld.net/wrldhis/PlainTextHistories.asp?ParagraphID=hkl&#34;&gt;British imperialism&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely crucial topic in understanding the development of world history, particularly during the period spanning the 19th and early 20th centuries. This era is often characterized by historians as &lt;em&gt;Pax Britannica&lt;/em&gt;, Latin for “British Peace.” It is so called due to the fact that Britain’s worldwide domination in the areas of economics, shipping, and military might kept most of Europe and the world in a state of relative peace. However, as the twentieth century came into view, global forces such as liberal ideals and nationalism threatened Britain’s role as the premier world superpower. Questions of how to proceed with its imperial rule began to multiply both in Britain and in its many colonies and territories abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cromer-sane-imperialism.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cromer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the third page of the May 3rd, 1905 edition of the Egyptian Gazette contains an editorial article &lt;a href=&#34;http://biography.yourdictionary.com/1st-earl-of-cromer&#34;&gt;“Lord Cromer’s Sane Imperialism”&lt;/a&gt; that discusses a moderate “third way” of imperialism that rejects harsh materialistic concepts and embraces more liberal ideas of self-determination and government, when appropriate of course. This article maintains that Lord Cromer’s Annual Report on Egypt and the Sudan contain the necessary elements of pursuing a moderate approach for continuing the might of the Empire moving forward. This editorial provides a fascinating look at the prevailing dialogue of the day in one of Britain’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&#34;&gt;most crucial imperial territories&lt;/a&gt; about the morality and governance of British imperialism at the dawn of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.newworldencyclopedia.org/4/48/Map_of_the_British_Empire_in_the_1920%27s.png&#34; alt=&#34;The British Empire at the height of its territorial range&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egyptian Gazette Views on Imperialism</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-08-egyptian-gazette-views-on-imperialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-08-egyptian-gazette-views-on-imperialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although there is a constant sense of British imperialism evident throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the attitude toward this imperialism varies widely throughout the paper. For instance, there are many cases where the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; provides long blocks of texts or ads clearly targeted toward rich Englishmen. The paper then proceeds to provide a sentence-long description of an item or event important to African natives. This follows with the expected traditional convention of the paper, seeing as its intended audience was wealthy Westerners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Cecil-Rhodes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cecil Rhodes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was rather surprising to discover a whole column’s length worth of information on a book regarding the emancipation on Egypt. This article, in the December 26th issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, mentioned both sides of the imperialism conflict, saying the author “devotes a whole chapter to the ‘false position of Great Britain in Egypt.’” The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; also seems to be an influential avenue for charity donations, frequently reporting on giving to certain causes and being used as a means for donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper devotes an even greater amount of room to a cluster of articles surrounding the death of a khedivial princess. These articles discuss the death of this princess, who was the sister of Prince Omar Pasha and Prince Djemil Pasha Toussoun, as well as the wife of General Ahmed Djelaleddin Pasha. Her husband wishes to open an inquiry into the circumstances surrounding her death, documented in a French telegram that is also printed in the Egyptian Gazette. Throughout the collection of articles, the princess is never referred to by name, only as the Khedivial Princess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this great amount of detail is due to the shock value of the event or the genuine interest in the matter by English businessmen is open to interpretation. Much of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is still written about administration, war, and other topics that would mainly be of interest to the white population of Alexandria, but these few tidbits to the contrary were an interesting find.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
