<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>analysis | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/categories/analysis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/categories/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>analysis</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>analysis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/categories/analysis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes towards Germany: Random, Situational, or Seasonal?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-arenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-arenas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1905 was a watershed year in the period preceding WWI. Tensions ran high as Russia was in the process of earning the distinct honor of being the first European nation to lose a war to a non-Western power (Japan), and the great powers were concerned if this, and the nascent but ultimately futile 1905 revolution, meant the decline of Russia as a major imperial power, which would certainly throw the delicate balance of alliances into chaos. But more sensationally, and closer to home, the German Kaiser Wilhelm II openly challenged French claims to incorporate Morocco into their sphere of influence, encouraging the Sultan Abdelaziz to convene an international conference to decide the fate of the kingdom. This is the age of sensationalist press too, where newspapers did not just report news, but had the power to make it as well. Journals mattered, and were a vital means of measuring (or controlling) public opinion, an invaluable tool for historians. Precisely when newspapers are at their yellow-journalistic, propagandic worse is when they hold the most value. The decisions of what stories to run, and how they are written reveal quite a lot about the mindset, values, and beliefs of not just the publishers, but their readership as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the main English newspaper in colonial Egypt, the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; should roughly represent the overall average of British views, but what surprised me the most working on my week was the sheer variety of opinions, and none felt so jarringly dissimilar as those concerning Germany. With this project, I sought to find out whether there was a discernable pattern in when the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; published editorial articles critical or supportive of Germany, and for the most part it seems there is none, and changes in the frequency follow events in the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology-and-structure&#34;&gt;Methodology and Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This investigation sought to do two things; quantify a subjective piece of data (occurrence of a pro- or anti- Germany article), collect the data, and observe whether any patterns emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest potential fault of this investigation comes from the very beginning: how to measure what is an article’s stance on Germany? From the start I wanted to look at one thing in particular, not wires/telegrams, but articles. These were difficult to isolate because in the newspaper itself there is little regularity in which these appear and how they are presented, which means that in the encoded library it becomes that much more difficult to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, I used the following xpath queries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=”article”]//p[contains(.,”Germany”)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=”item”]//p[contains(.,”Germany”)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of a “needle in a haystack” approach. I couldn&#39;t use &lt;code&gt;@element=&amp;quot;wire&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; because that would have only brought up results such as news telegrams, which do not contain the expression of opinion I was looking for. Nor am I sure would more specific queries have gotten me better results, because as mentioned above, what I am looking for is not always classified in the same way, and its page location can vary wildly (especially in 8 page issues).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through these results (which contained many lines from standardized ads or referencing ship arrivals), and read the articles to determine its position. This is unfortunately the most subjective part of the process and thus the one most open to error. I classified any opinion article as pro- or anti- based on two factors. One was whether the article (and being published by the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; arguable the newspaper itself) considered the government or state of Germany as a threat either to the perspective of the writer of the article or as threatening to a third party (and not always a military threat, and it was rarely such an outright sentiment of fear or anger), and whether the article held sympathy for or encouraged the success of the German government or state. Both of these are because what would often happen is that the article would extol the virtues of the “German” while decrying his government, most often in the context of the supposed “failure” of the German state to maintain her colonial empire up to “correct” standards. Germans would be portrayed as successful despite coming from Germany, rather than because of it, which I took as a solid indicator of anti-German sentiment. But again, this is the most subjective part of the process, and I could not succeed in standardizing these criteria any deeper than that. It became a question of “you know it when you see it.” In any case, once I identified an article, I would go into the div header and add the phrase &lt;code&gt;ana=”#german-positive”&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ana=”#german-negative”&lt;/code&gt;. I then ran the queries again to limit the results of the searches to just the articles I intended to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept my data confined to the year 1905 to limit the number of results. That year alone provided me with almost 100 articles. An interesting further avenue of research is if we can see a gradual change in opinion over the course of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I collected the results of these two xpath queries I copy/pasted them into Atom, and by using regular expressions cleaned up the data until each point was just two variables: date, and either positive or negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then went into tableau, and organized the data into two charts, each measuring the results over the course of 1905 by quarter and month. One shows the comparison between positive and negative articles by type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other measures the frequency of each type of article in a much clearer way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this data show us? Ultimately, not much. The only patterns that can be discerned is that articles of both types spike randomly, following events, not pre-determined patterns as was previously thought, and that consistently the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; agreed with Grey’s Foreign Office in considering Germany (usually in conjunction with the Ottoman Empire) as a threat to British interests. It must be noted however, that there is also a consistent publication of pro-German articles, showing that while the imperial agents in Alexandria more or less “toed the line” with the government, this was not universal. Even though a good deal of these pro articles came from German newspapers (as opposed to English or other continental ones for the anti side), their universal publication in English rather than the alternative French which likely would have been more popularly spoken among the other European citizens in Alexandria, could suggest that there was a minority among the British imperial agents in support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there may not be much to show for it, I do believe this question of the representation of Germany in colonial newspapers is intriguing, and well worth further exploration. The two biggest problems facing such future work are the lack of a standardized way to define an article’s position, and with the paper itself: its lack of regularity with these opinion based articles that do not come from Reuter’s or Havas means that they are more difficult to search for in xpath, as they will be encoded in many different ways in the collection itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golf in Egypt in the early 20th century</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-porter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Golf in today’s day in age has come a long way since it was invented in the 19th century. The technology, how it is played, taught and how it is treated at country clubs. There were country clubs that had golf courses in the beginning of the 20th century around the word but the clubs didn’t usually revolve around the golf courses rather than the typical “sporting” club games such as croquet and other games played on nice grass surfaces. Golf has come a long way but it still was more popular in Egypt than most would assume in the beginning of the 20th century. The picture below was one of the first images that showed the initial relevance to golf in Egypt, it was taken at the Mena Club in Egypt and adds a bit of relevance to when golf started up in Egypt when this picture was posted in a golf magazine in 1898.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;porter-egypt-golf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;First proof of golf in Egypt, 1898&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golf was invented in the UK in the 19th century and didn’t really become a popular sport around the globe til the 20th century. The English and the Scottish were the innovators of golf around the world because nobody knew about it until they began to share it with other countries, according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.antiquegolfscotland.com/history.php3?itemid=77&#34;&gt;Places-Golf in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;. In Egypt in 1905, there were country clubs that had golf courses but most of the clubs where golf was popular there seemed to be a large influence of it from English members. For example, in March of 1905 the Suez Golf Club registered a tournament for the members to play in and over half of the contestants were English which shows much influence from them. However, as years went on, golf seemed to become more popular to the Egyptians most likely because of the English and Scottish influence that was relevant in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golf tournaments in Egypt in 1905-1907 were much different than they are today around the world. After searching &amp;ldquo;golf tournaments&amp;rdquo; in the sport and play section in xml I found results from a couple tournaments and the formats of the tournaments were different from most of the tournaments in today&#39;s day in age. This is most likely because of how golf was still a new game and people were still trying to learn how the game was played. The format of most of the tournaments I have read about in the beginning of the 20th century were different from what they are played around the world today. They were played in a “match-play” format rather than a “stroke-play” format like in today’s society. The format of match play is played on a hole by hole basis and is played in a “one vs. one” format. One person plays another and the score from each hole can result in 3 different outcomes; a win, loss or tie. Each hole is worth one essentially in the match and whoever has won the most holes after the conclusion of 18 holes has won the match. Stroke play in today’s day in age is much different because it is based upon a player’s total score over the course of 18 holes and is not played in “one vs one” format rather than a full field of however many players play and whoever has the lowest total score is the champion. Tournaments were played like this most likely because it is more enjoyable and an easier way to keep score against your opponents; it also makes the round of golf take a shorter amount of time and is a much easier way to play for those who aren’t as skilled as golfers are today. After analyzing much of the country club tournaments they are all played in a handicap format as well which is a way a less-skilled golfer can play a better player in a fair format. Handicap is based upon your average score from previous rounds and for those that are less skilled playing a higher skilled player gives them a “handicap” so they can compete fairly. Once again, this makes it more enjoyable for golfers of all skill levels to have a competitive match against anybody. The Suez Golf Club had two tournaments every month for their members; a bogey play tournament and a match play tournament. I configured this information from xml by searching for &amp;ldquo;golf clubs&amp;rdquo; in divisions and finding a sport and play section talking about the Suez Golf Club on October 18, 1905. A bogey play tournament is a format that is not common whatsoever now but was probably a more enjoyable way for those of less-skill level to enjoy competition. The tournaments in Egypt in the beginning of the 20th century were all ran by country and sporting clubs and took time to play. Since match play tournaments are played “one vs one” there were more rounds of golf to be played and this was in the form of a bracket. Therefore, these tournaments would take weeks to complete and those who lost a match would be immediately disqualified from the tournament because they would be knocked out of the bracket. Tournaments now are ran by organizations are much more competitive than they were over 100 years ago mainly because of the popularity of the sport. There was a tournament at Alexandria Sporting Club that included 3 different formats: match play, foursomes and stroke play. The championship format was match play in which M. Logan won 3 up with 2 holes to play. M. Logan also competed in the foursome format which is a 2 vs 2 format and won that to add another tournament title to his record. This information was found by searching &amp;ldquo;golf tournaments in Egypt&amp;rdquo; and was found on the date of February 14, 1906 in xml. The results are posted below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;porter-FullSizeRender.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tournament results from the clubs in Egypt&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading about the organization of the golf clubs, all members who wish to play in tournaments and register their handicaps are to report to a golf steward of each club. The golf steward is one who runs all the tournaments and puts them together. The steward is similar to what the Head Golf professional of each country club today does; they essentially run all of the golf operations and put everything together for the members. The golf steward of some clubs such as the Suez golf club would give lessons just as a professional at a club now a days does. This aspect of the organization of golf at clubs is more similar than I first suspected. The official definition of a steward is “an official appointed to supervise arrangements or keep order at a large public event.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 26, 1905, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; posted an article labeled “Vardon on Golf”. Harry Vardon was one of the most accomplished golfers in the world at the time and in the article Vardon talks about tips of how to play the game and what accounts to the success of very good golfers. This article being published shows that golf was becoming more popular since there was a very long and detailed article on the front page of Egypt’s most popular newspaper. The article also mentions results from the Open Championship which is golf’s most historic golf tournament. Harry Vardon was English and this article transpires back to the fact of how the English made golf in Egypt a relevant and popular sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking for tournament results in years 1905-1907 I only came across of 3 golf tournaments which showed that official tournaments weren’t very popular but also meant that they were significant. Three different clubs held golf tournaments and each tournament had a different outcome. The winner of each tournament did not win by very much meaning there was stiff competition but the winner at Suez Golf Club won by the largest amount which can be inferred that he was probably the best golfer of the three winners and out of all the tournaments. There was just a punctuation for his first name but his name was N. Worthy and he won by the most holes. This is significant because it showed who was the best golfer at the time in Egypt who played in these tournaments. The results are in the chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;porter-FullSizeRender1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tournament Result Chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there weren’t an overwhelming amount of clubs in Egypt in the early 20th century, I figured it would be important to display which clubs there were and what each club had to offer besides golf courses. Country clubs now a days usually have a lot more activities than just golf and so did they back in the 20th century, they often had many games played on manicured grass surfaces. The main sports and activities that the clubs had to offer included golf as the main sport, horse racing, tennis, bowling, croquet and soccer. There were a total of 6 popular country clubs in Egypt at this time and also a few sporting clubs. Every country club had a golf course which shows that golf was a up and coming sport throughout Egypt. However, some clubs didn’t have the stereotypical 18 hole golf courses. Some had 12 hole and 9 hole courses which shows that golf wasn’t the most popular sport at the club but they still had it because it was an up-and coming sport. Croquet was the 2nd most popular activity at the clubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;FullSizeRender2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Country Club Sports&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golf has shown to be an up and coming sport in the early 20th century in Egypt and provided more influence in the sports world than most people would think. However, it is still very different than what it is today. Almost every aspect of different types of golf and how it&#39;s play has evolved which is what sports are supposed to do over time. Golf in Egypt still isn&#39;t very popular to this day but it still is relevant thanks to the English and Scottish that brought it over in the early 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Fashion Trends 1905-1906</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-pustam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-pustam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acquiring data for this project was tough. My data was qualitative, not quantitative, so I couldn’t just find charts with what I needed and call it a day. Initially, I wanted to look at fashion trends and how they evolved within the 2 year period. However, as mentioned before, finding the data was difficult. Whenever I looked up ‘fashion’, it would refer me to a hotel ad. Back then, they used different terms to describe fashion. I had to come up with a way to find them. Eventually, I looked up ‘dress’ and found some wedding articles, so I decided to stick with that since the category of wedding dresses would be more consistent and a better way to compare clothing than normal streetwear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To collect my data, I looked up the word ‘wedding’ within headlines, took all the articles, and copied and pasted them into a different document. I did the same with ‘marriage’, and within that document, I looked up the words ‘dress’ and ‘gown’. I would read the words around whatever came up, and created a spreadsheet of details I found on the dresses. Then I had to look up the article in the content repository again so I could get the date. I had to do this because simply looking up ‘dress’ would have gotten me a lot of articles I didn’t need, and just copying and pasting the results would only get me the 7 words around it, which was way too little information to work with. I logged in details of who wore the dress, who made it, what color it was, material, trim, bouquets, and more. Then I created a chart with as many of these details as I could find. Some of the data I collected was not reported with the other dresses (like with the creator of the dress, or with the bouquet), so these results could not be graphed. Obviously, this research relies entirely on how the newspaper reporter describes the dresses, the reporter could call something ‘pale blue’, when in reality, it could be ‘periwinkle’, or something like that. Most of the dresses are white, as expected, but some are referred to as ‘cream’, or ‘ivory’. I kept those as different colors because I wanted to see if different shades came into fashion at some point, or maybe there was a significance within the shades depending on class. I thought it was an important difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this project I aim to analyze the trends of Egyptian wedding dresses from 1905-1906 (I could not find any articles in 1907) to see what colors, materials, decorations, etc. get used and what trends get repeated, and if there is any change due to season (I’m thinking specifically with the flowers used). I’m hoping to find things that aren’t typically seen with American wedding dresses, and I want to look at what certain things such as material or color says about a bride. In the article Late-Nineteenth-Century Ottoman Wedding Costumes as Indicators of Social Change by Nancy Micklewright, she describes how certain things about a bride affect what the dress looks like “Her choice would have been determined by her religion, her social status (which in turn involved her family and its financial standing), and her education” (Micklewright 1). If these aspects are mentioned in the article, hopefully there is a correlation between the choice of dress and the features mentioned above. I feel like material will definitely be influenced by social standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph of what colors I found to be used and who wears them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said before, most of the colors were white. Wedding dresses are traditionally white, so this is no surprise. There was not a lot of variation within the bridal dresses in terms of color- ivory, silver, white, and crème. There is not a correlation between dates or seasons for these color variations. Additionally, there does not seem to be a difference in the kinds of people who wore this color (there are no descriptions of what kind of position these couples hold in society… one is married to a well-known contractor and that’s it. There’s a wedding of a princess described, and she wears white).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the graph that depicts the materials used in wedding dresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satin was the most frequently used and most consistent material. It appears to be used throughout the two years steadily. One dress uses ‘blonde lace’. This couple got married in London, in the same church that the king and queen of England had attended to view the wedding of Lady Alexandra Acheson’s marriage with the Earl of Derby’s son. The groom was the Captain of the Egyptian Army. Blonde lace appears to signify a very expensive dress. This was a bridesmaids’ dress, and from the article we can see it was very worked up. “charming gowns of white blonde lace on soft white satin, the bottom of the skirts trimmed with Empire wreaths of pink chiffon roses, set in by garlands of blue ribbon… trimmed at the back with little rosettes and short folded ends. A butterfly bow of lace… small green foliage falling at each side. The elbow sleeves were in two, divided by a bracelet of blue ribbon and a single pink rose…”. In 1840, a woman named Angeline Faran wore a dress of blonde lace in Cincinnati, Ohio. She wore this dress 45 days after Queen got married in one similar that brought the style of “simplicity enhanced with lace” (Thieme 2) to the forefront of the fashion world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A trend I noticed was the frequency of orange blossoms involved in the wedding dresses, trims, veils, and bouquets. This flower only appears in the dresses made in 1906. The blossoms could be used around the bottom, or as a flower crown/diadem under the veil. I tried to pinpoint it to a specific season, but it seems to just occur throughout all of 1906. I only have dresses from April and September, too, so with more data, maybe this could be evaluated more. I know someone in our class is doing something about flowers, so maybe this project and hers will be able to be connected to offer a more complete explanation for the frequent use of orange blossoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I really wanted to investigate was the origin of these dresses. Only three of the dresses had a labeled identification of how it was made, which was slightly disappointing. If I had gotten more data on where the dresses were created, I think it would have been really cool to map out the origins of the designers and see what cultures influences Egyptian wedding fashion at the time. I know a lot of cultures were involved with Egypt at the time, primarily Britain, so making a map of these origins would have shown how far each influence was. Of the three origins mentioned, two were described to be tailored (one ‘plain tailored’), and they were both going away dresses. These dresses were worn when the bride leaves the reception or after event of the wedding. The only wedding dress was described as being made by “venture of Milan”. This dress belongs to a ‘Miss Nangovich’, and is described in greater detail than the others. Orange blossoms appear not once but three times- on the skirt/train, the bodice, and the veil. Because her dress is described in so much detail, this leads me to believe that she was pretty important. This makes me wonder if the orange blossoms were an indicator of status, but the other dresses were not described in as much detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any topic, digitizing microhistory makes research a lot easier- if one knows how to properly do it. as mentioned before, finding my data was tough and I had to think of different ways across different platforms to collect it. My main issue was the fact that I was searching within a certain type of article (wedding/marriage) that had no consistent way of being labelled, so I had to copy and paste each article that I wanted to search into a different document, and then look for my data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This erased the dates of the articles, so I had to go back and find them. This is mostly at the fault of the Egyptian Gazette writers, since weddings were not consistently reported on, not the program itself, but it still would have saved me a lot of time and stress if I had a way to search within. That being said, it was definitely a lot better than having to find the Egyptian gazette scans and go through them one by one to find data on weddings. Digitizing the gazette will help research tremendously, as there is a lot of information in there, and newspapers are the most accurate way to get glimpses into the daily lives of citizens, plus they cover very broad topics. I could have done my project on anything due to how many things are talked about in this gazette. If I had to use another source, such as Google or an academic database, it would have been nearly impossible. Even though there was not a lot of data to work with in the two years, I still feel like I was able to pull out a lot of information to analyze. Without the Digital Egyptian Gazette, I could not have gone as in-depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Art of Dress in the Victorian and Edwardian Eras, Otto Charles Thieme &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/1504015&#34;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/1504015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late-Nineteenth-Century Ottoman Wedding Costumes as Indicators of Social Change, Nancy Micklewright &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/1602288&#34;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/1602288&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperatures in Assouan and Port Said</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-beasley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-beasley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this analysis project I analyzed the temperatures of Port Said and Assouan. Specifically, I gathered information about the maximum temperatures and the minimum temperatures. This data was pulled from the section titled ‘Daily Weather Report’ from within the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; newspaper. The section appears in almost every days’ issue and includes information such as the highs and lows in the shade, the humidity percentages, and the rainfall totals of all the major cities within Egypt during the early twentieth century. With the information on temperatures that was pulled from almost every day from 1905 to 1907 I was able to analyze the trends in seasonal changes. I observed to see if there were days or weeks where temperatures were too high or too low, resulting in the possibility of work being postponed or the possibility of people getting sick. Outside sources and credits made this process more fluid and really assisted in gathering information about safety requirements within a work place and the dangers of being in extreme hot or cold temperatures for set durations of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The locations of Port Said and Assouan are the key points of focus for my research. Port Said is a city that is in northern Egypt and located on the Mediterranean Sea. On the other hand, Assouan is in southern Egypt, near the Nile River, and a part of the Sahara Desert. Both cities have vast differences in their climate and these differences are easily recognizable. For example, Port Said is on the coast of the Mediterranean Sea meaning that it gets a sea breeze unlike Assouan. The sea breeze provides outlets for more moisture content to build up in the area, causing the overall weather-like symptoms to be rather humid and seem hotter on some days than it actually is. Unlike Port Said, Assouan is located in the midst of a desert, meaning that the temperatures fluctuate during the day and night. However, the climate of Assouan is notoriously dry and hot. The Nile River does provide some moisture that can increase the humidity, making the temperatures seem like they are hotter than they actually are, and vice-versa with wind coming off the river making temperatures seem cooler and more bearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another locational difference that stands between the cities of Port Said and Assouan is the Tropic of Cancer. The line serves as a peaking point for the sun during the summer months in the northern hemisphere. On June twenty first of every year the sun appears directly overhead of the Tropic of Cancer marking the initial point and start of summer. The southern most city of the two, Assouan, is directly in the path of the sun during this time. The Tropic of Cancer is located on the latitude 23.5 degrees north, and Assouan is on the latitude 24 degrees north. In addition to being in the path of the Tropic of Cancer line, Assouan is also closer to the equator than Port Said is. When drawing a direct line that connects the two cities the distance between them is four hundred ninety-eight miles, or eight hundred one kilometers. This concludes that Assouan is nearly five hundred miles closer to the equator than Port Said is. For a better grasp of understanding on the distance I’ve included a comparison on distance from two cities in the U.S. From Miami, FL to Charleston, SC it is a direct distance of 485 miles. If you are a native of the Southern region of the United States or have ever travelled to Miami and Charleston during the peak of winter and summer, you know how different these climates and seasonal temperatures are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to differences in climate and seasonal changes, the data that I collected and observed for Assouan and Port Said were fairly different from one another. To show the data that was collected and then evaluated based on several averages I made two graphs. One graph is composed of the average maximum temperature for each month that the data was recorded for, and the other is the same, just with the average minimum temperature. Note that all the temperatures within ‘The Daily Weather Report’ were recorded in Celsius and not Fahrenheit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;beasley-graphmax.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;MAXIMUM TEMPERATURE GRAPH&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;beasley-graphmin.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;MINIMUM TEMPERATURE GRAPH&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the graphs, you can see that there are numerous spikes within the data. The spikes occur around the month of July, and the month of January both for the maximum and the minimum temperatures. The maximum temperature spikes for Assouan are around forty to forty-three degrees Celsius. Meaning that the maximum average temperature for the month of July in all three years was 109 degrees Fahrenheit. The minimum temperature spikes for Assouan are around twenty-seven to thirty degrees Celsius. Meaning that the minimum average for the month July was eighty-four degrees Fahrenheit. That is a fluctuation of about thirty degrees per day, which is very common all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maximum temperatures for Assouan in the month of January averaged at about twenty-three degrees Celsius, or seventy-three degrees Fahrenheit. The minimum temperature for Assouan in the month of January averaged at about eight degrees Celsius, or forty-six degrees Fahrenheit. This once again is about a thirty-degree fluctuation in temperature throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we look at the spikes that occur in the data for Port Said they are around the same times as those of Assouan. This means that the two cities have roughly the same seasonal patterns. However, they are in different climates and that is totally recognizable from the data that was collected. Over the three years that we have data from, the average maximum temperatures for the month of August was around thirty-two degrees Celsius, or eighty-nine degrees Fahrenheit, and the minimum was around 24 degrees Celsius, or seventy-five degrees Fahrenheit. As for the winter months we’ll be looking at the month January. The average maximum temperature over the three years for January was seventeen degrees Celsius, or sixty-two degrees Fahrenheit, and the minimum temperatures were about five degrees Celsius, or forty-one degrees Fahrenheit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, this data sums up that the average annual temperature for Assouan is much higher than Port Said. During the beginning of the summer months Assouan is hottest. This is because of the location in comparison to the Tropic of Cancer. During the middle of winter months Port Said is coldest. This also has to do with their location in comparison the Tropic of Cancer, but more so due to the equator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, in The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; we can read about the things that people did for enjoyment, work, and many other things. In particular, we are able to analyze that during the summer months people often left Egypt to go elsewhere. When reading the newspaper, a reader can see a plethora of advertisements having to do with ships leaving and/or returning. A huge sum of these ships leaves during the hottest time of year, and it is no coincidence. Work is abandoned in the summer months and people go off for vacation. This isn’t the case in the winter months because the average daily temperatures were extremely comfortable, and barely dipped below forty degrees, and barely peaked any higher than seventy-five degrees. To see why work might have been abandoned during the summer months in Egypt I did some research about the possible side effects of working in extreme temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many plus sides to working year-round, but there are also factors that put people at risk. Working in the extreme heat increases the likelihood of developing heat stress. Heat stress can occur from being out in the heat for too long, working at a high rate, or wearing the wrong type of clothing. The effect of this is the body trying to regulate its temperature and ultimately starting to fail. Resulting in dehydration and nausea. This is a huge reason why work load was put off in Egypt during the summer months, especially in cities that were closer to the Tropic of Cancer, and the equator. In cities like Assouan there are recorded temperatures exceeding one hundred degrees Fahrenheit. These are not suitable working temperatures and working in these environments can lead to exhaustion and even death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the body’s set point temperature is ninety-eight point six degrees Fahrenheit. Whenever the temperature outside or in the working environment exceeds or goes below this temperature, the body is trying to cool, or obtain heat. In today’s modern time we have technology that allows us to see what the current temperature is at all times. This includes temperatures with or without a heat index to get the ‘feels like’ temperature. However, in early twentieth century Egypt there weren’t weather instruments that were accurate enough to constantly check the weather and its symptoms. All that was given was the daily maximum and minimum in the shade, so there was no way to tell what the ‘feels like’ temperature was. This could’ve resulted in occasions where people suffered heat stroke and other heat related symptoms because they didn’t know what the actual temperature outside was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading through the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; will give you abundant information about Alexandria, the neighboring cities, and Egypt all together during the early twentieth century. As an historian, reading the numbers that are provided in the daily weather report mean next to nothing. However, comparing cities within the report with the help of modern information allows for a better understanding of why the Egyptian community did certain things at differing times of the year. Assouan and Port Said are two of the most separated cities in Egypt and give insight on the conditions of life in Egypt during this time from an understanding perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Semitism in Egypt and Surrounding Countries</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-northcutt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-northcutt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When first reading the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, one can see how many times death is mentioned.  This can be easily understood; as humans have been interested in death for centuries.  However, I wanted to delve deeper into the kinds of deaths that were mentioned in the newspaper.  Unfortunately, I came across a telegram that talked about a Jewish person’s death because of Anti-Semitic reasons.  Because of this, I was moved to look into the Jewish condition in Egypt, as it is a relevant topic today and it had not been looked into my another classmate.  According to the Jerusalem Center for Public Affairs, they believe that “Alexandria in Egypt was the birthplace of anti-Semitism’s ideology. There also the first pogrom in history-as we now would call it-took place” (in 38 C.E.) (Horst). The Center also talks about how the first indication of a negative attitude towards the Jewish people stemmed from the writings of the Egyptian Priest, Manetho.  He writes that “Jews are dangerous and enemies of humankind” (Horst).  But, in an article in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, a writer states that “while the feeling of antagonism towards a race so unlike the rest of the world undoubtedly gained intensity and bitterness from misdirected Christian sentiment and passion, long before the Christian faith had gained ascendancy the streets of cities inhabited by Jews bad been reddened with Jewish blood” (“Egyptian Gazette,” 11/11/1905). Though many of these ideas and allegations happened long before the early twentieth-century, it is easy to see how effects of these beliefs may have still affected Egyptians during this time as well.   Ironically, though, especially before the war, many Jews moved to Egypt to escape the strict regime of the Ottoman Empire, as Egypt was seen as “a safe haven and land of opportunity” (Takla 28). There was an increase in the number of Jewish refugees to Egypt during this time because of the increase in Anti-Semitic ideologies in surrounding countries. Because of this, I would like to see the extent in which Anti-Semitic ideologies are evident in Egypt during this time. Therefore, I will seek to answer the question: what Anti-Semitic ideas or events does the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; include in their newspaper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, I conducted several queries of the entire Egyptian Gazette using a series of keywords, including Anti-Semitism, Jews, Jewish, and Anti-Semitic. Though I did specify in my query that I wanted to look in the telegram and local and general section, I realized that, because there were only so many mentions of Anti-Semitism, this specificity was not necessary for every search.  With those searches, I found 18 solid, relevant results, ranging from articles discussing the Jewish condition in Russia to riots in Warsaw and Anti-Jewish attacks. To organize and analyze my data, I collected all the different locations that telegrams came from and categorized these events into instances of deaths, attacks, rallies, and support, to see what is actually happening in Egypt during the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, I looked at the places where these mentions are coming from, according to the dateline in the telegrams section. Most of the reports came from St. Petersburg and Warsaw; St. Petersburg was mentioned in the dateline eight times and Warsaw was mentioned six times.  This information did present an interesting perspective on the Russian Revolution of 1905 and how that political freedom sparked Jewish freedom and, consequently, Anti-Semitic beliefs.  Because this is such a major event and Russia’s geographical closeness to Egypt, it is understandable why this information made it into the “Gazette.”  Some researchers also say that the freedom that happened in Russia stirred the Warsaw Jewish population to become more organized and prevalent.  Because of the rapid readjustment of power, objectively it makes sense that it would be met with more resistance that would be documented in the newspaper.  The Russian Revolution’s effect on its neighboring countries is also evident in two of the mentions of Anti-Semitic attacks that happened in Riga, which is part of Latvia, and Homel, which was a part of Belarus.  In both of these places, natives pillaged Jewish shops, and, at Riga, the chief of police was killed.  However, both of these events only had one sentence descriptions, which is very small compared to at other places.  Perhaps it is because these cities are a lot smaller and less politically important than St. Petersburg and Warsaw.  This shows that, though the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is interested in documenting tragic events, they do focus on bigger cities and more well-known places.  Therefore, the data I was able to collect may be skewed compared to the actual number of attacks that occurred. It is also interesting though, that Anti-Semitic events are more widely documented in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; than the Jewish political growth.  Perhaps this has to do with most people’s interest in death and other destructive elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anti-Semitism in Egypt was only mentioned once, on February 10, 1906, at Damanhour.    At Damanhour, a number of Jews were making a pilgrimage to a Rabbi’s tomb where they were attacked by some natives.  The attackers ended up being sentenced to prison for one to eight months.  One thing that strikes me about history, especially as I am learning about history, is the fact that we can never truly know the full information about an event.  For instance, it strikes me as odd that there was only one mention of and Anti-Semitic attack in Egypt when Anti-Semitic ideas were on the rise in almost all neighboring countries.  Is it, in fact, that the attack at Damanhour was the only Jewish attack in Egypt? If not, which I doubt it was, why weren’t other attacks mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;? To what extent does the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; censor its information to better present Egypt’s the newspaper’s reputation? Because I only have access to the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; for micro-historical data, I may not be able to answer these questions; but, they do impact the way I look at the information presented.  To see a complete visualization of the places mentioned, see the map included below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I categorized my results based on the information; these categories included articles, killings, pillages, and attacks, as this helped me better see the data.  Though the number of times each category of event is mentioned is relatively spread out between all categories, there were more mentions of riots, attacks, and articles.   Though it is unfortunate that there were so many riots and attacks that occurred and were reported, it is also interesting that there were the same amount of articles talking about the Jewish condition as the attacks and riots.  At first, I thought that this might be a good thing, as there is a discussion about the Jewish situation.  However, upon further reading these articles, only two of them actually discuss the details of the Jewish people; the other one is an Anti-Semitic writing about “the Jewish peril” and how they bring poor to the streets of Egypt (Singer, “Egyptian Gazette,” 1/6/1906). Though there may still be more objective discussion about this situation, the underlying Anti-Semitic attitude in Egypt is made clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that it is also important to note that, even with the updated content of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, there were only eighteen mentions of Anti-Semitic attacks, destructive actions, or articles about the Jewish condition.  Since, as mentioned earlier, there was a huge growth in Jewish political power and Anti-Semitism in Egypt and surrounding countries, it is interesting that this topic did not take up more space in the newspaper over the span of two years.  But, sports events, golf tournaments, art reviews, got mentioned every day.  Though I am still curious about why this is, perhaps it is because, as much as people like to know the dramatic and important events that are happening, they do need a bit of an emotional escape that they can get when they are talking about sports or a show.  I think that that reason is why we have these events in the first place; they distract from everyday life and present a more active and interesting story.  This discovery made me think about the function of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; as well; though it is a way to spread information, it is also about entertainment.  The &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; might have needed a more variety of entertainment to satisfy the readers, which could be one reason why there was such a lack of information about Anti-Semitism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, though, there were several mentions of the Jewish people in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, so the population is not going unnoticed.  In fact, when I queried the word ‘Jewish,’ there were 219 results.  Though the rest of these results were not directly related to Anti-Semitism, they are still of value in terms of how the Jewish people were receiving representation.  Though I do not have the ability to study how many times the Jewish population was discussed in previous years, I would assume that the representation is rising similarly to that in other, neighboring countries as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, though there is some talk about Jewish people in Egypt and surrounding countries, most of it presents the negative side of the situation, with reporting the number of attacks, riots, destructive actions, and Anti-Semitic writing.  Though the harsh Anti-Semitism that occurred centuries ago is well in the past, it appears that some of those ideologies are not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Children in Alexandria</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-richardson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-richardson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;analysis-topic&#34;&gt;Analysis topic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is filled with information from accidents to steamship schedules. Over the course of this course of this class I have read countless articles on Lord Cromer and the Plague, but there has been little mention of children in Alexandria. With the help of Mr. Hanley I choose to further look into an area of history that this class has not studied. There is little known about children in Alexandria during the early 1900&#39;s. A chapter in &amp;ldquo;Childhood in the Late Ottoman Empire and After&amp;rdquo; by Benjamin Fortna gave me the only insight I could find into childhood. He said &amp;ldquo;Girls stayed at home until around the age of five, when they would then begin fetching water and helping their mothers with such work as cooking, cleaning and making fuel cakes. Boys also usually stayed home until the age of five, when they would then begin to take the donkeys to the field or the buffalo to the canal&amp;rdquo; (Fortna). This gave me insight into the expectations of children, but I wanted to know more.Therefore, my analysis question is, how are children described in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;procedure&#34;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finalizing my analysis question, it was important to narrow down what I  was looking for. My first step was to write an Xpath query that would find  how many times child appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. I used &lt;code&gt;//div[contains(.,&amp;quot;Child&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt; and found over 18,000 results. I knew this  overwhelming amount of data had to be better classified, so I choose to use  another Xpath Query: &lt;code&gt;//div[contains(.,&amp;quot;child&amp;quot;)]/@feature&lt;/code&gt;. This Xpath looks in  all the div that contain the word child that fall under a feature in the  Gazette. This Xpath had produced 297 results. I than took all 297 results and  placed them into Atom. After cleaning up the results to only have the date and  the feature name, I transferred the results into Tableau to make a graph.  After looking over the results I realized that there were results that included  information that was not about children. I felt it was important to only  include information that related directly to children. This meant that  I had to get rid of results that included last names. Instead of going through  all the results individually using the Xpath from above, I broke the Xpath  down further. I used the find and replace button on Oxygen. I first entered  in the text to find box the word child and the restriction to Xpath was  &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=&amp;quot;?&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;. The question mark was replaced with any of the words that  feature equalled on the graph. I started with @feature=&amp;quot;army&amp;rdquo; and ended with  @feature=&amp;quot;wire&amp;rdquo;. This helped me eliminate the results that included last names  and information that did not tell me about children in Alexandria. When I  changed the restriction Xpath I found data that was not included in the original  /@feature div, so I was able to add dates and features that were important for  the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tableau-table&#34;&gt;Tableau Table&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Tableau I organized my results into features vs. years. I choose to get remove the year 1907 because there were little results and most of the results were prepaid advertisements. I made this table to see what feature of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; contained the most articles with children in them. If I could better pinpoint a section of the newspaper I could better collect data that would allow for me to see how children were described in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;richardson-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Years Vs. Features of child&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After creating the graph I found out that the most mentions of child was in the local and general section of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Prepaid Advertisements was the second highest, but most of these were advertisements that were repeated throughout the weeks. Advertisements told me about what children could wear and toys they had, but not much information about children themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-and-general&#34;&gt;Local and General&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to look into the findings of child in the local and general section of the newspaper. Overall, the mention of children ranged from a variety of different topics. The most interesting of these findings are: entertainment, child found, hospital, children and accidents and child weddings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;entertainment&#34;&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the local and general section children entertainment was a major reoccurrence. The San Stefano Casino hosted the Children&#39;s ball. The Children&#39;s ball was put on about seven to eight times during 1905-1906. The readings suggested that the ball brought together a large amount of young people. Through the reports made the ball appear elegant, tasty, and enjoyable. contained and The main feature of a ball mentioned on August 19, 1905 was a Massinet pavan, which was danced by children. Children seem to have danced and put on performances a lot for Alexandria events. Alexandria also started hosted matinee&#39;s for children in 1906. Along with entertainment for children there were fundraisers that benefited the well-being of children in Alexandria. On February 8, 1905 The Germania lodge was hosting a ball that collected articles of warm clothing for indigent children. Another fundraiser was reported on April 26, 1906 saying the committee of the Rudolph Home wanted to thank the ladies of the Rudolph Guild for their gifts of Children&#39;s clothing. I thought it was interesting how throughout the years adults were coming together to give back to children, and take care of children in their city. One man, Idris Bey Ragheb who donated fifty pounds on the occasion of his daughter&#39;s marriage which a portion of that money went to education for orphan children. Giving back in Alexandria for the well-being of children seems to be very important, which is still a very relevant in today&#39;s society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;child-found&#34;&gt;Child Found&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A surprising amount of reports in the Local and General section included found   children. Through 1905-1906 six children were found missing. The first report   occurred on July 1st, 1905 when a new born baby was found and brought to the   hospital. All of the children that were found were new born babies that were   left in the streets or in corners of the city. After reading about   all these children, I wonder what was the point of reporting this in the   newspaper? Who would be looking for these found children? New born babies   could not crawl away in the middle of the night, most likely these children   were left there by their parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hospital&#34;&gt;Hospital&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my surprise the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; discussed child mortality rates in hospitals. On May 5, 1906 the Cairo Foundlings Hospital reports that mortality still remains to be very high and &amp;ldquo;Last year, out of 76 children admitted no less than 64 died.&amp;rdquo; This was surprising because on there were no reports of why children went into the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;children-and-accidents&#34;&gt;Children and accidents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to my results children were involved in accidents 15 times over the course of two years. Two children in Alexandria were burned to death, three children were drowned and one boy died of electrocution. Two children were killed by either a railway tram or tramcar while one boy was thrown out of a train but he survived. One child was kidnapped while another was murdered and one was found buried in a cotton field. One chid got bite by a dog, but survived and one little boy had a wheelbarrow fall on him and left him with internal injuries that killed him.In the Journal article &amp;ldquo;An Anti-Serum for Scorpion Venom&amp;rdquo; Charles Todd talks about the many deaths that occur in Cairo every year due to Scorpion stings. He says &amp;ldquo;These deaths are practically confined to Cairo and Upper Egypt, and are almost entirely among children&amp;rdquo; (Todd). In my findings three children got bit by scorpions and died. Accidents with children can often relate to their deaths. Some of these findings the children died at the scene, but some later died in hospitals. Later in the article by Todd mentions that hospitals in Cairo received the serum for treatments of scorpion stings. Todd reported that &amp;ldquo;Out of 23 cases in the town of Cairo which were treated with serum, only one death occurred. This was in a child two years old who was not seen until two hours after having been stung. The child then received 5 c.c. of serum, but unfortunately this only serum available at the moment was a somewhat weak one, over a year old&amp;rdquo; (Todd). Even children today are prone to death by accidents, children in Egypt are no different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;child-wedding&#34;&gt;Child Wedding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting story I found in the local and general section was on October 25, 1905. There had been an arranged Muslim marriage of an 11-year-old boy and a 12-year-old girl. The little bridegroom as they called the boy was taken from his house ad brought to a distant cafe. He was participating in a ceremony called &amp;ldquo;El Huroub.&amp;rdquo; The ceremony entails taking the bridegroom from his home and in his absence the bride was welcomed into the home. The 11 year old boy got tired from the excitement and fell asleep and when they woke him up he fainted. The bride was unamused by the ceremony and the company of her bridegroom&#39;s family that she had left and has never been heard from again. This story was so sad because two children getting married so young is a scary thing, but to have her leave him forever is tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I have learned from the local and general feature is that children seem to be treated like children. They attend schools mostly based on their religion or family origin. They do what their parents ask of them, like get married. They play with toys and attend balls. They are not immune to the dangers of the world they live in. The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; includes children throughout the newspaper, but overall children still need to be further researched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fortna, Benjamin. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1163/j.ctt1w8h1jx.8&#34;&gt;Childhood in the Late Ottoman Empire and After&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. Brill 2016. Apr.16.2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Todd, Charles. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/3858794&#34;&gt;Anti-Serum for Scorpion Venom&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; Cambridge University.Apr. 16. 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egyptian Export Companies</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-ebert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-ebert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My analysis project focuses on two companies that ship goods from Egypt to England. They are Carver Bros Company and Behrend Company. I will compare and contrast the goods that each company exports as well as their levels of success. I am analyzing data from the full content available to me from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, meaning these results range from January 1905 through July 1907. I will also use them to exemplify the Egyptian export industry based off of research I have collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;steps-taken-towards-completion-and-problems-in-the-way&#34;&gt;Steps Taken Towards Completion and Problems in the Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-query&#34;&gt;1. Query:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While coding the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in XML I found an interest in economic topics, such as imports and exports. I wanted to know what goods were being shipped in and out of Egypt and what countries they were coming from and going to. Therefore, I figured it would be useful to use the data from the &amp;ldquo;Export Manifests&amp;rdquo; section. I tried using the xpath query &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=&amp;quot;exportManifests&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; but a very large majority of the results were un-updated templates that had just been copied and pasted. So, with Weber&#39;s help, I came up with a new query using regular expressions. In &amp;ldquo;text to find&amp;rdquo; I searched for &lt;code&gt;behrend.+&lt;/code&gt; and then restricted it to &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=&amp;quot;exportManifests&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;. I did the same for Carver Bros. This gave me a unique set of results for each company that I could work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-results&#34;&gt;2. Results:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I experienced the most difficulty. After copying and pasting the query results into Atom and cleaning it up using regular expressions I could not get my results to paste into Tableau for some reason. One of the companies worked fine, but the other would only paste as a single column instead of separating the data into a table. After some trial and error, Dr. Hanley was able to help produce results that could be transferred to Excel and then to Tableau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-visualizations&#34;&gt;3. Visualizations:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ebert-behrend.png&#34; alt=&#34;Behrend Company&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ebert-carver.png&#34; alt=&#34;Carver Bros Company&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before doing research on scholarly articles having to do with Egyptian exports, I tried to find any additional information on these two companies within the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. I did a query for &amp;ldquo;behrend&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;carver bros&amp;rdquo; in &lt;code&gt;//div[n=&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; but none of the results were very fruitful. The only results for &amp;ldquo;behrend&amp;rdquo; had to do with a rice mill owned by someone of the same name. Perhaps it is the same person, or maybe a relative. For &amp;ldquo;carver bros&amp;rdquo; the query returned results with information about the office of Carver Bros being a meeting place for the &amp;lsquo;British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt.&amp;rsquo; It was also referred to as &amp;ldquo;a great cotton house.&amp;rdquo; Based off this limited information, I would hypothesize that Carver Bros was a larger and more successful company than Behrend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based off of my results and my visualization, I can see that Behrend company exported fourteen products, while Carver Bros only exported eleven. If one were to simply look at the visualizations, one could make the assumption that the total amount of exports is about the same, since majority of the exports for both companies fall between zero and ten thousand units. However, concluding this would be innacurate because the unit type for each product is different. For example, cotton is sold in &amp;ldquo;bales&amp;rdquo; but cotton seed is sold in &amp;ldquo;tons.&amp;rdquo; Other things, such as onions and sugar, are sold in &amp;ldquo;bags.&amp;rdquo; Since it is unknown what constitutes a &amp;ldquo;bale&amp;rdquo; of Cotton or a &amp;ldquo;bag&amp;rdquo; of sugar, it makes comparing products difficult. Due to Behrend Company exporting an immense amount of beans, it caused outliers on the graph. I still want to include the data for beans since it is one of the products that both companies exported, so instead of excluding the outlier I changed the y-axis of the Behrend graph to a logarithmic format to make the graph more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparing specific products, I will focus only on those that are shared between the two companies. These include cotton, cotton seed, beans, oil cake, and onions. Most of these products are shipped several times per year, however I find it fascinating that the Behrend company only shipped beans one time throughout the whole span of January 1905 to July 1907. Not only were beans exported only once, but it was the biggest shipment from the Behrend company in that entire two and a half year span. This makes me wonder if beans could only be harvested and shipped one month out of the year (April, in this case) or if London had another, more valuable, source of bean imports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to tell by looking at the visualizations that Carver Bros is largely a cotton company, with its main two exports being cotton and cotton seed. Although it out-exported Behrend in cotton itself, Behrend actually exported much more cotton seed than Carver Bros.  Carver Bros also only sold 384 units of onions and 126 units of oil cake, compared to Behrend&#39;s 19,997 units of onions and 996 units of oil cake. Based on looking at these visualizations and analyzing the data   one could conclude that Behrend was a much more diverse and probably more successful company. Behrend not only exported more total products, but also exported more different types of products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do these two companies exemplify the bigger picture of the economic world in the early twentieth century? In &amp;ldquo;Europe and the Maritime World&amp;rdquo; author Michael B. Miller notes that the first half of the twentieth century&#39;s global economy was largely shaped by &amp;ldquo;the conquered territories of Africa and Asia&amp;rdquo; that had been colonized in the nineteenth century. He says that even though most trade was still conducted between the major western powers, &amp;ldquo;commerce with formal or informal empire accounted for a very considerable share of the &amp;lsquo;global&amp;rsquo; in global exchange&amp;rdquo; (Miller 2012). Both Behrend and Carver Bros were companies that shipped out of Egypt, which was a colonial territory of Britain at the time. From a micro-historical perspective, these companies seem very large and important, however Miller also notes that London was the top European port until about the 1950s. Both of these companies shipped to London, but they were just two of many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;Agrarian Change and Industrialization in Egypt,1800-1950&amp;rdquo; author Peter H. Bent leads the reader to believe that the early twentieth century was a time of economic prosper for Egyptian exports. He claims that the nineteenth century was characterized by the harsh rule and failed industrialization attempts by Muhammad Ali and that Egyptian industrialization was not successful until British rule in the early twentieth century. However, he states that Britain only facilitated industrialization in Egypt for certain purposes, specifically cotton production. In addition, he adds that Egyptian exports were largely affected by the Great Depression, so based off this research I would assume Behrend and Carver Bros, among other Egyptian export companies, were at their height during the first decade or so of the twentieth century, which is the period of micro-history that we have been studying this semester.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fires</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-meyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-meyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Egypt being located along the Mediterranean Coast, most of their months in the summer is hot and dry in the majority of the country, and humid in the Delta. When temperatures become so high, it can be extremely easy to ignite or cause a fire by heat from the sun. The topic that I am going to analyze for this paper is the fires that appear in Alexandria, Egypt and that are accounted for and the amount of fatalities marked in each. This topic sparked my attention after hearing about the past several years of the wildfires in California. The week that was given to me was the week of February 11th, 1907. With a fire the rate of survival can decrease, and the costs of damage and replacements can increase. The question of interest is if there is a high number of deaths due to fire, is that the reason there is so many insurance company advertisements within the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through issues of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I found several features and advertisements about fire. I was interested to see how many fires were accounted for and the amount of fatalities that were acknowledge within each instance. I became interested in the trends that may also carry over to insurance companies of the Alexandria and Cairo area seeing if the reason there is so many is due to the amount of fire that are counted for in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading a copy of the master content from GitHub, the first preliminary query I ran was for any div type item that contained the word fire, which resulted in coming upon several fire incidents, but as well as a variety of insurance companies. Upon first glance, this information would indicate that there were various occasions of fires in the early 1900s, but with additional inquiry, a lot of those instances of the word “fire” were advertisements for insurance companies. These advertisements are still relevant to my project and will come into play in further explanation. I took into account that where most of the fire instances were being reported was in the “Local and General” section of each issue where there was an outbreak of a fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the primary knowledge of this project being from the repository, I also took it upon myself to research the history of fires in Egypt in the early 1900’s. Much to my dismay, my research came up short when the only incident of fire I came across was in Cairo Egypt much later in the 1950s called the Cairo fire, also known as Black Saturday. Cairo Fire was a series of riots that took place on 26 January 1952, marked by the burning and looting of some 750 buildings. If the riots of Cairo were bad in the 1950’s, there could be a likelihood that they were not as far off in the early 1900’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By looking through the repository with the keywords “fire” and “death”. which focused on the number of fatalities in reported fires, Each XPath query was searched with an item containing the word “fire”. When first using the term, there were over two hundred results, however upon looking through them it is easy to see they don’t fit the article type I need. Some of these articles simply talk about advertising for insurance companies and the rest would only indicate that a fire occurred, but no other details were given. Getting further into my research I soon realized that these findings weren’t the most helpful, there were not a lot of deaths with each report of a fire. At this point I decided to change my research from the amount of deaths reported in each fire instance to the reason of each fire. After doing this I erased my keyword “death” and just decided to look through the “Local and General” section to see the reports of fire and the origin of each one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When discussing with other classmates about their analysis projects, as well as looking on GitHub, a lot of them seemed to have the same problem of having a topic that was so broad, but not knowing how to reduce the results with the proper keywords which is the major problem I ran into. I didn’t know how to reduce the amount of results I was getting back since a majority of them were advertisements without using the word “fire”. So after further discussion, I decided to change where I was looking in the repository. I narrowed it down to only looking in “Local and General” although there were maybe a few reports of fire in “Personal and Social” the majority of the content I was looking for was found in “Local and General”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;meyer-analysis-image.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this graph it shows the percentage of the cause of fires from 1906-1907. With a total of 19 reported fires from 1906-1907, there were 10 that were accidental, 8 that were caused from an explosion, 3 that were caused from a crime, and 3 that were caused from miscellaneous categories. With the section of explosions, the occurrences of fire were either on a boat or from mining. At the time in Egypt, there was a high demand for coal and the use of coal for the steam powered engines on the ships which explains why there were instances of explosions that would turn into a fire in the mines and on the boats. From the graph, you can see that a lot, if not all, of the instances would need to utilize the outside help of insurance companies afterwards to help with damage and repairs, which would explain why a lot of the insurances companies I came across in my issues, as well as other classmates, had fire mentioned in the advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the amount of deaths that were accounted for with each instance of a fire is not significant enough to say the fires are the reason there is so many insurance advertisements in Alexandria, Egypt which is why I changed my research to the cause of each fire. That doesn’t go to say though that the amount of fires reported don’t factor into the amount of insurance advertisements because with each fire comes a large amount of costs and repairs. Although the insurance companies probably do take use in the instances of fire, there are other tragedies that occurred during that time frame in Egypt where insurance companies would need to be utilized.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coolben, Adam. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adst.org/2012/09/the-cairo-fire-of-1952/&#34;&gt;The Cairo Fire of 1952&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; Association for Diplomatic Studies &amp;amp; Training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humidity In Alexandria</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-jones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-jones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;jones-2018-04-16.png&#34; alt=&#34;2018-04-16&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking back on Alexandria, Egypt over one-hundred years ago one would not expect much interest to be taken in the humidity in the day to day lives of the Alexandrians. In reality humidity could have an effect on how these Alexandrians functioned in their daily lives and caused different consequences on the city as a whole. Seemingly small things can be more impactful than as they appear on the surface. In this analysis project research was done to see how these Alexandrians could have been affected by humidity and what other consequences could have resulted due to high levels of humidity. The resource that was used to gather this information was from a microfilm version of The Egyptian Gazette. This was a British run newspaper in Alexandria, Egypt in the early 1900s when Egypt was still under British control. This means that some of the information in the newspaper could be skewed to make the British empire look better, so I chose to go with something that would be unbiased. In the newspaper there is a section called The Daily Weather Report which presents much information about the weather that the Alexandrians experienced on each day. The Daily Weather Report was found a page 2 in many of the editions of the newspaper. This was the main source of information used for the analysis project and the Xpath query I used was able to pull all of the data for humidity for each of these days in order to help further my work on the project. The Xpath query done in Oxygen XML editor was &lt;code&gt;//table[@xml:id=&amp;quot;deg-ta-dawr01&amp;quot;]/row[6]cell[2]/measure[text()]&lt;/code&gt; and it yielded 149 items which is a sufficient amount of data that could be analyzed and allow me to draw conclusions. Through conversations with class members I was able to find out more interesting facts about humidity. My classmates helped me to become more aware of the health effects of humidity on the human body, so I used their knowledge to investigate on the web. The information found in The Daily Weather Report was useful to Alexandrians in the past, but now it is also useful for todays weather experts in order to compare it to the present to see changes in climate and also to see what kind of health conditions these Alexandrians may have been experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;jones-alex02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1900&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When trying to decide what to write about for the analysis project humidity was something that came to mind for me because it seems very relevant when studying microhistory to study something that many others would consider such a minor detail to observe, but is very interesting and thought provoking to fellow microhistorical researchers. Weather is fascinating to me so I figured it would be best to pick one aspect of weather to focus on in order to keep in tune with microhistory and what it studies. Microhistory studies small and miniscule things in order to bring everything back together and form a big picture about the past that can help gain much more understanding about how the world used to function and how the world has changed since that time. When looking at recorded health records at the time researchers can see at what times sickness was more prominent in Alexandria, Egypt and compare that to the humidity levels at that time of year. With this correlation now known it can be assumed that during the times when people were sick or suffered bad symptoms it could have affected Alexandrians workload. In order to further revise and improve what I have proposed I would have to try and make sure that all of the data inputted was recorded correctly in order to make sure that this information is reliable enough to make assumptions about past times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When beginning my study into the humidity levels in Alexandria, Egypt I wanted to make sure that I would be able to find research on a topic in order to be able to apply what I found. I was able to find much information on medical websites to explain what high and low levels of humidity can do to the human body. Information about past humidity levels in Alexandria is important because it is important to see how the humidity levels have changed overtime in comparison to now because keeping track of climate is vital for future generations to come. The climate regulates how much work can be done and the health of the citizens in a specific area, while also regulating people’s moods and emotions. All of this information correlates together by deciding how productive a society can be at all times. Researchers all over the world try to further improve their knowledge on climate so that they can apply it to the society they are studying. Some of these studies reveal many results since their research may study outliers in the climate that they are studying, while many may not reveal much new information at all since what they are studying is too similar to recognize any drastic change showing results. Whatever the case all of this information can be looked at and stringently analyzed so that it can form a big picture when pulled back in with all other sorts of recorded and known information at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem that may arise when studying these past climates is the technology that was being used to record this data. In the past technology was not as reliable as it is today, and this could mean that what was recorded in the past could have been wrong skewing the results and assumptions of past data on humidity. In order to improve research on this past information studies must be done to see how reliable this past technology was and compare it to what is being used today. It is a requirement to know how accurate this past technology was to ensure what is being researched is good enough to rely on. I’ve also wondered if the everyday Alexandrian understood what humidity levels meant and what effect it could have on their day in the past. If they did not seem to care it would give reason to believe that they may have recorded the humidity data less accurately since they did not really understand its importance at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humidity can have negative effects on human health when its levels rise too high or too low. At high humidity dehydration, fatigue, muscle cramps, heat exhaustion, fainting, and heat stroke can occur, while at low humidity people are more at risk of getting the cold, the flu, and other infections. This is according to UPMC Health Beat and SensorPush. With this information in mind it gives a better understanding of what effects humidity could have on the society. At this time in the past people were not afforded the ability to have fancy medical equipment and more informed doctors. This meant that people were slower to recover from an illness that they may have gotten from humidity levels, and lead to an increased chance of death and a decrease in the amount of work output in the community. When observing a single part of the weather it proves that something that may seem small can create a large and prominent effect on a city as a whole. Through studying this data researchers are better able to come up with ways to combat the harms of humidity on the human body and prepare future generations to stay healthy in order to create a healthy and efficient community. There is still so much that needs to be learned on information that may seem irrelevant, but in reality can play a huge role on peoples’ quality of lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various graphs I created using Tableau produced some interesting results that helped to give me a better understanding of the data that I had collected. I preferred the graph that showed the average humidity for each month over the years of 1905-1907. The month that seemed to be the outlier overall was April in the year 1906. The average here was very different from other recorded months of April. I also made a graph of the average of each day over the year and encountered the problem of people not updating their Daily Weather Report section. I discovered this because there were multiple days in a row that had the same repeated value of 76 allowing me to determine that others had not correctly updated there tables to provide accurate data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main issue I encountered when performing the Xpath query and observing the results was that some people did not fill out the weather table correctly or did not input that information at all. My goal was to find data on humidity between the years 1905-1907, but when performing my query the vast majority of the data came from 1905 some from 1906 and a very miniscule amount from the year 1907. This means that my gathered information may not be as reliable as I would like it to be. From what I observed the majority of the data showed that the humidity levels were consistent between 70-90 percent. This did leave room for plenty of outliers with humidity in the high 90s on some days, while on others there was a definite drop in humidity. This shows how drastically the humidity could differ in the climate in Alexandria, Egypt. To put this information into perspective the ideal home humidity level is between 40 and 60 percent in order to maintain maximum comfort and healthy living conditions. This may differ outside but it still allows people to get a better understanding of what preferred conditions are like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very intriguing to see how using technology now such as Oxygen XML Editor, Tableau, and Atom can take information from the past and create a much greater understanding of previously recorded information. New technology has created a great new platform to present information that in the past would be much more tedious and time consuming. With all of this gathered information researchers alike can present this information to keep societies growing with knowledge and to help improve the health and welfare of future generations to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://share.upmc.com/2014/06/effects-humidity-body/&#34;&gt;https://share.upmc.com/2014/06/effects-humidity-body/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sensorpush.com/articles/the-effects-of-low-humidity-on-your-health-and-comfort&#34;&gt;http://www.sensorpush.com/articles/the-effects-of-low-humidity-on-your-health-and-comfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hvac.com/faq/recommended-humidity-level-home/&#34;&gt;https://www.hvac.com/faq/recommended-humidity-level-home/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact from Climate in Alexandria</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-squires/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-squires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The climate in Alexandria, Egypt has always been unconditionally hot.  The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; from the early 1900s provided daily weather reports in  their weekly issues. This newspaper also referenced the many ways the population  escaped from the dreadful summer months. Although Alexandria is still a highly  populated city, the booming city from the early 1900s was filled with many  immigrants. Even though Alexandria is close to the Mediterranean Sea, the  western desert provides much of that dry heat to Alexandria. Many citizens  escaped the heat by going somewhere cool back in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heat gave the residents no relief, even at night. Without modern day technology how did the residents survive? We may also ask ourselves now, was the temperature a factor in activities in Egypt? If an average spring day in Alexandria hit a temperature of 29 degrees Celsius (84* Fahrenheit) in the shade, how hot did it actually get?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Daily Weather Report&lt;/em&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; highlighted the different observed temperatures and conditions throughout different locations around Egypt. The &lt;em&gt;Daily Weather Report&lt;/em&gt; also recorded the moon phases and other station&#39;s conditions. All these values are published in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; once or twice a week. To extract all of Alexandria&#39;s temperatures, I searched through working sets and got the query:  //table[@xml:id=&amp;quot;AlexandriaWeather&amp;rdquo;]/row[contains(.,&amp;lsquo;Max&amp;rsquo;)]/cell[3]/measure to get 1905 daily max. temperatures from Alexandria&#39;s observations.![Max. temperatures from  1905].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I did the query &lt;code&gt;//table[@xml:id=&amp;quot;deg-ta-dawr01&amp;quot;]/row[contains(.,&#39;Max&#39;)]/cell[3]/measure/text()&lt;/code&gt; to get the data from 1906 and 1907, since it used a different template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;squires-graph2.png&#34; alt=&#34;graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;squires-graph.png&#34; alt=&#34;graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This query helped me draw a relationship between the weather temperatures were livable conditions to survive without the technology we have now. The graph I produced from the query shows recorded temperatures around Alexandria. Alexandria&#39;s average temperature mean was 25.81* Celsius or 78.5 degrees Fahrenheit. The coldest temperature is even higher than the average temperature for Earth (57*). These temperatures demonstrate that the climate was much warmer than many other habitable places in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seasons in Egypt are quite minimal. Alexandria is close to the coast so they tend to have a higher humidity than the surrounding desert. Since it is hot all year around, and many people escaped the heat in the summer. Especially the British who were not used to the heat, since the UK has a maritime climate. Winter and summer align with the U.S., since Alexandria is in the northern hemisphere, but Egypt&#39;s location is an important part of the heat they receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the abnormally warm temperatures, precipitation is also an important factor for the climate. Alexandria tends to have a higher amount of precipitation than the majority of Egypt, but rain has always been very minimal to around a maximum average of 200 mm a year. Although Alexandria is close to the Mediterranean sea, the water was not sufficient to drink, nor did they have the proper technology to extract the water for drinking. This means they had to transport most of their water from the Nile. Besides water, shelter is also very important for living. Homes and businesses were built from stone and clay which are materials that help keep the area cooler. Since refrigerators and air- conditioning were not yet accessible during this time, citizens probably had a harder time cooling off during the summer months. Hence, why the wealthier population tended to leave during the summer months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results I received from my data can be conclusive. The average temperature was 25.81*, while the high and low temperatures were 39* and 10.5*. This means that the temperatures were 102.2* and 50.9* in Fahrenheit, giving the average to be. A few data points were taken out of the graph due to being outliers. The first outlying point was a mistake in the _Egyptian Gazette_. The printed high temperature in the shade displayed on the issue from March 5th 1906, said it was 7.5*. This can only be a mistake considering below it says the low temperature was 11.3*. Therefore the point was taken out. seventy-six other values were also extracted due to the inaccuracy of duplicating the template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These temperatures recorded would make it hard to live in especially within the summer months. Without proper electricity and water, Alexandria would be a hard environment to live in. Combining the results of the data with the knowledge of technology and resources, Alexandria was most likely a difficult place to live. The harsh climactic conditions could have contributed to a decline in population after the early 1900s. While many of the people who grew up in Alexandria were used to the climate, Europeans who immigrated there could have had a much harder time adjusting. Although the climate in Alexandria, Egypt was much harder to live in, it doesn&#39;t mean it was unlivable for the early 1900s. The high temperatures and lack of rainfall would make it harder for farmers and the rest of the working class but overall the climate could be deemed acceptable, especially for the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs in Cheap Prepaid Advertisements</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-brown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my analysis project, I decided to analyze job advertisements in the “Cheap Prepaid Advertisements” section of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. The specific contents of the job advertisements that I analyzed were the languages that employers wanted applicants to know, the expected gender of the applicants, and the adjectives used to describe desired applicants. In addition, I considered the amount of job advertisements that were present in different months during 1905 and 1906 to see if there were any noticeable trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used an excel sheet to organize my data into five categories. I placed job titles in column one, the date of the issue in column two, gender mentioned in the advert in column three, adjectives used in column four, and languages required in column five. Overall, I found 129 instances of job advertisements in the issues I searched. I used the Xpath query &lt;code&gt;//div[@element=&amp;quot;prepaidAdvertisements&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; to search my content folder. This brought up places where people used this element tag to describe an item or section. From there, I went through the results and put the data I needed from the job advertisements into my excel sheet. The Xpath query I used was very broad, but I had to use it because there was no way to search for specific job advertisements without yet knowing the names of different jobs. The one disadvantage of using this query is that some people might have put the “Cheap Prepaid Advertisements” section in their file without using the element tag. That said, I decided that my results would provide a good representation of job advertisements in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of the “Cheap Prepaid Advertisements” section in an issue of the newspaper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;brown-prepaidAdvertisements.png&#34; alt=&#34;Prepaid Advertisements&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first way I chose to visualize my data was with word clouds. One word cloud represents the prevalence of different types of jobs in advertisements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;brown-wordcloud1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Word Cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top three jobs advertised make up over 50% of the advertisements overall. Looking at the word cloud, the most commonly advertised job was for a clerk. In order to organize my data, I did not separate each different type of clerk into separate categories. Among the advertisements for this type of job, many were for general clerks, while others were for typing clerks and office clerks. The Merriam-Webster dictionary defines a clerk as someone “whose job is to keep track of records and documents for a business or office.&amp;rdquo; According to Robert L. Tignor in his book &lt;em&gt;Modernization and British Colonial Rule in Egypt&lt;/em&gt;, clerical positions were normally held by people in the Coptic religious community prior to British colonial rule due to their clerical skills. This was especially true for clerical jobs in the government (Tignor 308). Such jobs became held by a wider variety of people during the period of British colonial rule. This happened because Egypt became more modernized during this time, which called for more advanced skills from those working as clerks (Tignor 308). Most of the job advertisements for clerks expected a wide variety of skills from applicants. Applicants were often expected to speak multiple languages, with some advertisements even expecting them to be fluent in five languages. The languages that seemed to be most important to employers were English and Arabic, with many advertisements mentioning that reading and writing these languages was an indispensable quality for employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second most advertised job category was nurse. Many of the advertisements for nursing jobs mentioned that the position was specifically available to women. The word nurse was used to describe a caretaker for children in many circumstances, which is different from the common use of the word. Something interesting I found was that many families would put out advertisements to find a nurse to take care of their children for the course of a ship voyage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of jobs were only advertised once or twice. It was very interesting to see what kind of unique jobs there were during the time period. For example, one advertisement was for a position as a draughtsman who would make plans and drawings for the government. Another was for an organist to play at a church event. The frequency of advertisements for some jobs surprised me. I only found one advertisement for a blacksmith position, and I thought that it would be a more common job during the time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph shows the frequency of each type of job advertised:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I looked at each job advertisement, I wrote down if it mentioned a specific gender preference for applicants. I found that the majority of advertisements did not specify a gender. The only time women were mentioned in job advertisements was for nursing and child care positions. Men were mentioned for a variety of positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a second word cloud to demonstrate adjectives used to describe what type of employee each advert was seeking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;brown-wordcloud2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Word cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many advertisements sought young applicants. The adjective with the most occurrences was experienced. None of the adjectives stood out as unique. The advertisements mostly used generic words such as good, competent, and smart to describe the types of desired applicants. Jobs that involved child care often used the word caring. Education requirements were hardly mentioned in the advertisements. Only a few mentioned seeking well-educated applicants, and none mentioned specific types of education required for employment. The words used in the job advertisements were similar to self-advertisements in the same section, where people seeking employment would state their experience and qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important feature that I analyzed was the languages potential employers wanted applicants to be fluent in. Some postings for seemingly simple jobs stated that they wanted applicants to know three or four languages, which was very surprising to me. Languages mentioned included Italian, German, English, French, and Arabic. Many advertisements mentioned that they wanted an Englishman.  There seemed to be no pattern to which types of jobs required fluency in the most languages. Most advertisements wanted applicants to know one, two, or three languages. Only a few required that they know four or five.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty more advertisements were found in 1906 issues of the paper than in 1905. June was the month with the most advertisements. Looking at a graph of the amount of advertisements over time, there seems to be no pattern to the amount of advertisements during different times of the year. It is hard to tell whether or not there would be a clear pattern if I was able to use a broader Xpath query to get more results. However, such a query would produce too many results to sort through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters to the Editor 1906</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-majonica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-majonica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Immediately upon first glance of the Monday issue of my week in “The Egyptian Gazette,” I was intrigued by the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section. As a history major, I am constantly learning about different time periods and cultures, while desperately trying to grasp the true interests of the people living in these different time periods and cultures. So, when I saw the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section, I imagined the potential for greater understanding of what people were interested in Egypt during the early 20th century. With that being said, when it came time to analyze an aspect of &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette,&amp;rdquo; I knew immediately the &amp;lsquo;Letters to the Editor&amp;rsquo; section was what I wished to know more about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When beginning my research, I first looked at the ‘Analysis Directory’ on our class website, where I noticed a student in a previous semester had already looked into the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section. Since they focused primarily on 1905, I decided that I would look into 1906, and after gathering my data and making my analysis, I would compare our findings to see if public concern had shifted between the two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After constructing my analysis question, I began formulating an XPath query. I looked to my predecessor who relied on the query, &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;LETTERS TO THE EDITOR&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;, and decided to use this as a preliminary search. I also searched //div [contains(., &amp;lsquo;LETTER TO THE EDITOR&amp;rsquo;)] to account for any differences in the way the heading may have varied between issues, as did she. However, I felt that this query was far too basic. Yes, it returned all instances of the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section within “The Egyptian Gazette” but, it did not give me much else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to build on this query and tried to pinpoint the titles of each individual letter within the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section. In order to do this, I started with the XPath query &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;section&amp;quot;][@feature=&amp;quot;letters&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;]. When encoding the digital Egyptian Gazette, each student should have included the ‘@feature=&amp;quot;letters&amp;rdquo;’ for the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section. Thus, when querying this, I was able to pinpoint the exact location of the section. Obviously this returned essentially the same results as my initial query, however, I ran it again and I added //head to the end, allowing it to pick up each individual headline within that section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had quite a few results after this query, but I felt that I needed to take into consideration students different styles of coding, while keeping in mind that not everyone would make the title of the letter a headline. Therefore, I decided to then query, &lt;code&gt;//div[@type =&amp;quot;section&amp;quot;][@feature=&amp;quot;letters&amp;quot;]/div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;]/p[1]&lt;/code&gt;. With this query, I was going into the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section, then into each item within each division and finally looking at the first paragraph in each division. This did not return nearly as many results as the previous query, but it served its purpose by looking for any differences in encoding which may have caused my previous query to miss a title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in order to procure as many titles as possible I ran my previous query again, but changed the ending to /head[1] to compare these results with my first search of the headlines in the section to again make sure that I did not miss any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I finished gathering my data through these queries, I needed to clean up my results which I did in Atom using regular expressions. Once I had a cleaned up version of my results, I was able to cross-check the dates of the occurrences of ‘Letters to the Editor’ throughout the year of 1906 from my predecessor’s query, with the titles of the letters I had acquired with my own query. These were the number of letters I ended up with in 1906:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon looking over my data it occurred to me that querying the digital Egyptian Gazette for the authors of the individual letters to the editor may be useful in determining not only who was writing, but why they were writing—i.e. what interests did they have in a particular topic. However, this immediately posed to be an almost insurmountable obstacle due to the varying ways people encoded their individual weeks of the newspaper. When querying the titles, I had a similar experience figuring out where in the code the title could be; but, the title only had a couple possible locations, while the authors had more than I could count. Every time I felt I had figured out the proper query, or queries, there was always another issue I had not accounted for. The name of the author could be located in any paragraph within the section, all depending on how many letters were in that issue and how many paragraphs the student encoding allotted those letters. The more letters there were, the more authors I needed to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously I could have gone through every paragraph in the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section picking out each individual author but, I began to think about patterns and the way in which each author signed-off. It usually was some variation of this: yours-comma-space-word-word. Now in a perfect world where people always corrected their OCR down to the comma or the space this pattern, when expressed with regular expressions and an X-Path query like this, &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;section&amp;quot;][@feature=&amp;quot;letters&amp;quot;]/div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;]/p&lt;/code&gt;, could have potentially returned most of the authors names. Unfortunately, it did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I compiled the names of the authors that I could with various queries, but I only had a limited number or authors. Ultimately I moved forward and began categorizing the headlines into more broad topics, beginning to think about what people were interested in when writing to the editor of “The Egyptian Gazette.” Now once I got to this step, the budding historian within me abandoned looking solely at the titles and authors I had complied, and instead opened almost every issue containing letters in 1906 to see for myself what they consisted of. This took much longer than if I looked a title and arbitrarily decided what the letter meant. I was able to create much more accurate categories by taking the time to do this, while also compiling the names of the authors I couldn’t find through querying. It also allowed me to remove any errors in my data that otherwise I would have missed. I still utilized a query to make this process quicker, querying the issues to bring me directly to the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section with, &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature&amp;quot;letters&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly I realized that there was no simple way of categorizing the letters. As I read over the titles, and later the letters themselves, the complexities of the ‘Letters for the Editor’ section revealed themselves. I ended up with a variety of different categories to label, or describe, what exactly the letters focused on. I initially hoped to simply categorize them under single terms, however, many overlapped. Some for example, were a response to another letter or to something published in an issue of the newspaper, while also focusing heavily on public concerns. Thus, I felt compelled to try and be as specific as possible to avoid misrepresenting the letters contents. So, instead of labeling it only as a response or only as public concern, I decided to label it as &amp;lsquo;response/public concern,&amp;rsquo; to be as accurate as possible. Below I have included a visualization that explores the categories I utilized and their number of occurrences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for my overall results, I have a greater understanding of what the purpose of the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section was. Beyond its use for free discourse, where people could write into the Editor to share an idea or opinion, the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section provided a place for public discussion without actually having to be in public. For instance, ‘XENOS’ wrote to the editor a total of eleven times, beginning and contributing to many debates under this alias. The ‘Financial Advisors Note,’ ‘Purification of Alexandria,’ and ‘Officials and Civilians’ were all topics dissected over multiple issues of the newspaper, with many contributors and opinions shared to a broad audience, many of whom used alias. The fear of judgment over thoughts and opinions was eliminated to some degree by sharing them through the ‘Letters to the Editor’ section. It reminded me of social media in the modern day, giving many the opportunity to speak freely without being criticized face-to-face over their beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘Letters to the Editor’ section was of interest, as people stood to benefit from being included in this section. There was clearly the possibility for financial gain as seen in the various financial pleas to the public through the section. More importantly however, the section stood as a medium for change. On various occasions, people wrote to the editor in hopes of being published to enact change. For example on May 8th, after a letter on the ‘Cairo Water Supply’ was published the needed increase in water was granted. Further, the writer of &amp;lsquo;Alexandria-Ramleh Railway&amp;rsquo; on August 21st, spoke of the “medium of your valuable paper,” implying that the paper, and particularly this section, allowed for average people to reach a larger audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it is important to note that ‘The Egyptian Gazette’ was written for and read by the British inhabitant of Egypt. The topics of the ‘Letters of the Editor’ section are those that were of interest to the British. This was clearly evident in talks about the future for the natives, or the Egyptians, without them being involved in the discussion. Yet, that does not deny that the section meant something for the people who interacted with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, after reviewing my data, I returned to my predecessors work and reviewed their results. Although we had categorized our results differently, it was still possible for me to compare the two. While I looked more at the individual topics more specifically, she focused on a broader representation if interests, dividing her results into national, international and financial. If I too divided my results into those very categories, developing percentages like hers, I feel confidently that we would have similar results. I agree with her conclusion that national affairs, meaning the happenings within Egypt, were of greater importance than both international and financial. It seems that between 1905-1906, little changed in terms of public interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving now to scholarship, there has been ample work done on newspapers and how people have interacted with them. Yet, even before I began my search, it occurred to me that the letters supported the argument made by both Hanan Hammad, and Nefertiti Takla in their articles regarding sex work. As the purification of Alexandria debate spanning several issues began, there were multiple references to the concerning work women were partaking in. Their words were selected carefully, however, after reading these articles I was able to understand what the public was actually concerned about when writing to the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, according to “The Content of Political Participation: Letters to the Editor and the People Who Write Them,” the authors, Christopher Cooper, H. Gibbs Knotts, Moshe Haspel, looked at letters to the editor to understand political participation similarly to how I looked at the letters in “The Egyptian Gazette” to understand people’s interest in 1906 Egypt. I found their description of the letters to the editor to be interesting, as they wrote “letters to the editor represent a unique place in the public sphere where a diversity of opinions should be represented.” (131) In my research that is exactly what I found. The ‘Letters to the Editor’ section of the newspaper provided me with a look at diversity in thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly however, the letters provide me with the opportunity to research multiple topics at a later date, as any of the categories I designated to the letters in 1906, could be used to build a separate analysis project. It would be interesting to see if the letters actually led to changes within the community favoring any particular opinion and if these changes were reported about later in the newspaper as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, my analysis project gave me insight into what people were interested in Egypt in 1906 as I had hoped. I feel I understand the people who wrote these letters more completely, as they were actual people, with actual opinions, thoughts and ideas that they readily shared and spread through the most accessible medium at their disposal. Below are my results, showing the number of occurrences of each category, combined with the date, title and author of each letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local and General Analysis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-bridges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were many topics to chose from pertaining to the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; however, in my analysis project I decided to look at the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section of the newspaper. I was interested in the topics that showed up most in the section and moreover what topics kept getting printed in the issues of the newspaper. I wanted to know throughout the newspaper what topics were, not so much being read more than the other but, reoccurring actions to be talked or read about in Egypt during the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;word-cloud-photo&#34;&gt;Word Cloud Photo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bridges-word-cloud.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Local and General Word Cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this I decided to create a word cloud to make a visual representation of the headlines of each section of the newspaper. In the word cloud, the headlines that were printed most are the largest in the figure and then following that are the headlines that are posted less which are represented by the smaller words in the figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this data set I created a query that would find only the headlines in the section of local and general and it would also include the date of the issue posted. I used two queries to do this because the &lt;code&gt;@feature&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;@element&lt;/code&gt; tags were implemented and each contained data that I needed to combine to get accurate results. The first query used was as presented &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=&amp;quot;local&amp;quot;]/div/head&lt;/code&gt;, the second query is different by one word &lt;code&gt;//div[@element=&amp;quot;local&amp;quot;]/div/head&lt;/code&gt; . The first query search returned 2,497 items while the second query resulted in 308 items. After this I transferred all the results into atom and refined the visual content that the search gave me. At the end I had two columns of data that was the date of the issue and the headline that was posted on that date in the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section of the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison-and-outside-sources&#34;&gt;Comparison and Outside Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading through other analysis projects from previous students, as well as the discussion of it in class, there was one that stood out to me about the Plague. As I was reading through their project they mention that their search for any &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; in any &lt;code&gt;item&lt;/code&gt; would contain the word &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo; and it only returned 82 items. This search seems to have returned a small number of instances for the return of the word plague considering one of the more prominent words in my word cloud is the word &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo;. They continue to go on to explain the way the word was used and the context of the word in the multiple occurrence in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in relation to my analysis search I want to reference today&#39;s newspapers and/or ways of information in today&#39;s society. We hardly get our information from a daily newspaper anymore, we typically get our intel from either social media or from the form of digital news still found on the internet. There is the more common way of reeling in viewers with a headline that is either a hook or a brief excerpt of what the piece entails. This differs from the way the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; displayed its news. The headlines for the news paper in the section are 2 to 3 word headlines that explain the passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest printed headline was the word &amp;ldquo;Canal&amp;rdquo; and the second most printed headline was &amp;ldquo;Suez&amp;rdquo;. There were other headlines printed that were seen quite often throughout consisting of: Alexandria, Plague, Egyptian, Stray Dogs, etc. There were often topics that were repeated in this section of the newspaper and new information was displayed this way in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a clip of the newspaper that I would find the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section in and it is typically found on the third page of the issue. Also, to conclude this analysis project I think that the way I represented this data works much better visually than any bar graph would have been able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bridges-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Photo of Local and General Section&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lord Cromer in the &#39;Egyptian Gazette&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-pregasen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-pregasen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my research analysis project, I looked at the number of times Lord Cromer was mentioned throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. I first searched a simple XPath query by searching for the word &amp;ldquo;Cromer&amp;rdquo; with the restriction of &lt;code&gt;//div[not(@feature=“advert”)]&lt;/code&gt; to look throughout all the issues and every div except the divs with the feature of advert. I looked through the entire content repository. I found each issue that Lord Cromer had been mentioned at and put that data into the text editor, Atom. Using regular expression, I cleaned up the data to only list the dates with how many times Lord Cromer was mentioned in each issue. I then plotted the dates into a bar graph as depicted below. The bar graph accounts the dates from January 1905 to May 1907 when Lord Cromer retired and was not mentioned further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pregasen-CromerBarDates.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at this data I could see that Lord Cromer is mentioned consistently with high points during the months of January 1905, August 1905, January 1906, August 1906, and April 1907. This means that he was mentioned many times during those months and few times in others. Between October 1906 and March 1907 Lord Cromer is not even mentioned at all. Throughout the latter months of his tenure as Consul General, Cromer was mentioned on average more than during the earlier years cataloged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Cromer, born Evelyn Baring, was the first Consul General of Egypt. He was given this position in September of 1883. He kept this position until May 1907 when he retired due to health reasons. He lived the rest of his life in England. During Lord Cromer’s reign over Egypt, he advocated for more British rule over the lands and dismissed the Egyptian demands for independence from Britain. Lord Cromer instituted mass reforms like the Veiled Protectorate “whereby he ruled the rulers of Egypt, with the assistance of a group of English administrators trained in India, who were placed in key positions as advisors to the Egyptian government” (Marsot). Along with governmental reforms, Lord Cromer helped institute public irrigation works and many agricultural feats that helped with the Egyptian economy and grow industrially. In 1907, a new British Prime Minister, Sir Henry Campbell-Bannerman, was elected into office from the House of Commons. Campbell-Bannerman was more lenient to the Egyptians. Lord Cromer was in Britain during the time of October and March, which is why he was not mentioned at all in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, when he found out about Campbell-Bannerman’s plans. Seeing the news and hearing of plans that would be put into place, his retirement seemed to be the best course of action. Lord Cromer’s health had been deteriorating too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking closely at the data, I noticed that many of the mentions about Lord Cromer discussed his travel across Europe. Many of the articles in January 1905 that spiked the mentions of Lord Cromer all discussed Lord Cromer’s trip across the Nile. Cromer discussed is thoughts on trade in his speeches during the trip. They discussed the prospect of Lord Cromer’s arrival back in Alexandria being delayed by a few days and social engagements Lord Cromer will come back to attend. In August 1905, an article featured titled “Lord Cromer His Life and Work.” The article discussed Lord Cromer’s personal life such as living in an old-fashioned mid-Victorian house and his professional job in Egypt. He was initially given ten years to deal with Egypt. The article specifically praises Lord Cromer’s work with irrigation that helped increase the population of Egypt. In January 1906, Lord Cromer gave a speech regarding opening a Nile-Red Sea Railway. The article praised for Lord Cromer for being a “master of English prose.” In August 1906, Lord Cromer was heavily mentioned. An article criticized Lord Cromer’s reforms and his past actions in relation to the Egyptians.  In April 1907, Lord Cromer announced his resignation. As a result, he was widely discussed. His career and personal life was analyzed throughout months leading to May when he formally resigned his position. Throughout the other months Lord Cromer was mentioned a couple of times. These mentions often discussed his travel plans, his social engagements, and his actions. The only time when Lord Cromer was not discussed at all was October 1906 to March 1907. Lord Cromer was in England for an extended period of time. His health had been deteriorating and these months lead up to his resignation for health reasons. It could be that Lord Cromer was dealing with his health seriously that caused him to formally resign his position as Consul General. It is interesting that January and August were very highly discussed months for Lord Cromer. There does not seem to be a seasonal correlation between Lord Cromer’s mentions and his actions. August and January seems to be the months when big decisions and roles Lord Cromer had to fulfill had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through my research, I noticed that Lord Cromer was often discussed as being the “Honorable Cromer.” He was clearly thought of highly among officials. The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; has written some articles praising his work ethic and ability to lead such a simple life. The newspaper further had called him a great man on multiple occasions in 1905. This is interesting, because Lord Cromer’s favoritism for increased British rule in Egypt was subject to much criticism from Egyptians. Yet, this Egyptian newspaper consistently painted Lord Cromer in respectable and good lights in 1905. The newspaper might have been scared of writing negatively of such an important British official or perhaps paid off by Englishmen. The reason for writing as such is unknown. However, in 1906 Lord Cromer had been criticized at many points. In January 1906, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; called Lord Cromer snobby and claimed that he has almost ultimate power of Egypt. A few months later the article was followed up upon by discussing Lord Cromer’s possible retirement. It discusses his failure in the Denshwai affair in which some British officials and Egyptians began to fight. Taking another 180-degree turn, Lord Cromer was discussed decently highly from March to May 1907. The newspaper seems to be trying to describe him in a positive light again as his retirement neared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this data was especially helpful in gaining an insight in Lord Cromer’s life and reputation in Egypt, the transcription of the articles might have lost some important data. There were many points where Lord Cromer’s name had not been edited correctly and had been written has “Cromor” or “Cnomer.” This would cause some of the data to be lost in certain days where Lord Cromer should have been recorded by my XPath Query. Sadly, this is harder to search for, because there are many different misspellings. Therefore, the different misspellings could cause skewed data that has not been recorded. This could only be corrected by looking through all the issues and correcting the text that had been transcribed incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage, Weddings and Divorce</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-frady/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-frady/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My inspiration for this Analysis project began with my blog post. When looking through my page images for the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I came across something that really peaked my interest, “A Prison Wedding”. This directed my attention towards unions during the times the newspapers were published. I was curious to discover trends in marriage during this time-period to divulge whether prison marriage was a societal norm. It’s not every day in today’s society that I hear of a convict being married in secret to a prison guard’s daughter, and accusingly by the prison guard nonetheless! My goal was first to find who the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was reporting on getting married. I wanted to find whether there were trends in the demographics of those being reported on. To truly give an accurate analyzation of the demographics and marriage during the time, I felt that I must also analyze weddings and divorce. I chose those two words because they closely correlate with marriage and there could be articles discussing marriage that don’t mention the word marriage, and that mention the words wedding or divorce. So, I began by searching for each of those three key words one at a time, marriage, wedding, and divorce. The query I used to search for each word was, &lt;code&gt;//div[contains(.,”keyword)]&lt;/code&gt;. This query gave me results on all dividers that contained the word I entered in the spot “keyword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the basic query, there were a very high number of mentions for the word marriage (543), less than half of that for the word wedding (184), and the lowest number of mentions for divorce (58). I found that while not many articles that mentioned the word marriage used the word wedding, a large amount of the articles including the word wedding did include the word marriage. Though these two words had correlation, articles mentioning divorce rarely spoke of the words marriage or wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;frady-Chart1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Chart1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the large number of mentions, I had to find a way to narrow down my results. The first step I took to narrow down these results and begin to analyze the demographics behind marriage in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, was developing a typology for the articles mentioning my key words. I noticed from skimming through each of my my prior searches that my key words all seemed to appear in the same types of features. These reoccurring features included local, social, wire, notesPortSaid and the khedive. To put in to perspective what types of features my key words were being used in the most, I searched for each feature containing my keywords with the query, &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature= “typefeature”]/div/p[contains(.,’keyword’)]&lt;/code&gt;. This query specified where I wanted to search, in my recurring features, and what I want to search for, my key words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for marriage in the feature local, the query returned 11 mentions. Topics of the mentions included marriage announcements, the word being used as a reference for time (ex: “On the occasion of the marriage of his daughter”), the kidnapping of a young native girl, an obituary, a man murdering his wife for a second wife, the disappearance of a bride on her wedding day, the proprietor of “Al Moyad’s” marriage, a quote in a book announcement, a cinematograph review that included a marriage, and last but not least  and my personal favorite, 11 moslem women divorcing over their husbands refusing to buy them the expensive cakes they wanted. The results showed that the most popular use of the word marriage in the local feature was for marriage announcements. In the feature social there were 5 mentions of marriage. One of these five mentions were on royalty. Other topics in this feature included marriage arrangements and marriage announcements; marriage arrangements being the most popular topic opposed to marriage announcements being the most popular in the local feature. In the feature wire there were 10 items. Nine of these ten items had to do with royal marriages and one with abolishing the church’s rights to interfere in civil marriages. When using my original query to just search for the key word I also found many results in the features khedive and notesPortSaid. After searching with the query limiting my results to specific features, I came up with no results for the keywords marriage or divorce. I also found many more mentions of my keywords in the features that I’ve discussed than what was returned. For these reasons I am leading to believe that there may be manual error in the labeling of the features. This error could alter the authenticity of my analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for wedding in the feature local the query returned 4 items. These topic items included an obituary for the death of the “Newab Begum of Murshi-dibad”, a band of rouges that assaulted a wedding party, a missing bride, and a woman dying after getting knocked over by a horse at a wedding. In the social feature there was 1 item, the mention of a description for an Arab wedding. The wire feature held 5 items, 4 of which were about a royal wedding, and one that was simply figurative language. There were no results with my feature-specific query that mentioned wedding in the feature khedive though mentions for the keyword did show in my basic containing query. The feature notesPortSaid had 2 mentions, both of a royal wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;frady-Chart2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Chart2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for divorce in the feature local the query returned 1 item. The topic for this item was the 11 moslem women divorcing their husbands over the men refusing to buy their wives cakes. This item was also mentioned in the results for the searched key word wedding. There was one mention in the feature wire that simply announced a divorce. The social, khedive, and notesPortSaid features had no mentions of the word divorce when using my specified feature query. Though when using my original query to just search for the key word, I found many results for divorce in the features. Again, leading me to believe there must be an error in the labeling of features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyzing marriage within the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I found that mentions of unions were most prevalent in the Local and General (feature local) than any other feature. Narrowing down my search to specific recurring features containing my keyword helped for me to sift through the content of the mentions. I found that the demographics were more difficult to analyze than what I’d originally thought. The gender of those involved were always a mix of male and female. There were no mentioned unions between genders of the same sex. The race of the individuals involved in marriage were not specified. However, the countries they were affiliated with often were. The mentioned countries were very diverse. The countries with the highest number of mentions include Spain, France, Germany, and Egypt. Other locations with reports on marriage include Arabia, Oneibis, Murshi-dabad, Moslem, Nahier el Lahoon, Sundanese, Ramleh, Sohag, Norway, Battenberg, Oldenburg, and England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that the locations of the reports on marriage were so diverse due to a topic discussed with numbers in mentions substantially larger than others. This topic was the royals. Many announcement, arrangements, and weddings were all being reported on royalty. I’ve included a chart below to show how much higher the percentage of mentions for royal marriages there were opposed to other topics of the results I acquired after narrowing my search. Royalty would effect the reports on marriage because they all rule over different countries, diversifying the results. When considering why royalty is more popularly reported, I would argue that it could be due to the Royals’ control over the media. The media was likely pressured to report news of the royals by the royals. Royals also determined the failure and/or successes of their peoples’ countries. For this reason, readers were likely eager to here of the royal political alliances.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Popular Sports</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-mason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-mason/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I chose to study the most popular sports in Egypt during the early 1900s for my analysis project. As a Sports Management major, this subject is very interesting to me as I can compare how sports culture has evolved and changed throughout the years. Newspaper sections titled &amp;ldquo;Sport and Play&amp;rdquo; frequently appear throughout the issues of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, and many popular sports and sports clubs appear throughout the years. To be clear, I can&#39;t analyze the most popular sports in all of Egypt because the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is primarily geared towards relatively wealthy British colonists in Egypt during this period. For this reason, I will be studying the most popular sports in Egypt specifically among the wealthy British occupants of early 1900s Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began studying the most popular sports in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; by sampling several months of issues in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and finding the &amp;ldquo;Sport and Play&amp;rdquo; section in each newspaper issue. I was able to narrow down the most frequently mentioned sports in Egypt by doing this. Once I had the list, I created an XPath Query for the different types of sports I had found, and compared the totals. By doing this, I found that horse racing and tennis were by far the most frequently mentioned sports throughout the repository with over 1000 results for each. Billiards and yachting were around 400, while cricket, football (soccer), and golf were just under 300. Other sports with less results included polo, swimming, rifle shooting, and rugby. However, with this method I was only able to survey the number of times these sports were mentioned throughout the entire repository including numerous types of divs. For instance, sports such as tennis, golf, and football might have been featured in more ads than horse racing because people tend to buy sports equipment frequently but they don&#39;t buy horses or rifles as frequently. In addition, the results from conducting an XPath on the entire repository were significantly different from those found while just sampling the Sport and Play category, which was originally intended to be the basis for my serial question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my random sample of the Sport and Play categories, the most popular sport by far seemed to be horse racing which was consistent with the larger XPath. Frequently mentioned horse racing clubs included the Helouan Sporting Club and the Khedivial Sporting Club. In the issues that I sampled, horse racing was mentioned in 26 articles. The articles described the results of various horse races, pony races, and donkey races between 1905 and 1907. These articles also described meetings scheduled by the Helouan Sporting Club and the Khedivial Sporting Club, demonstrating that readers of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; were fascinated by horse racing and looked for when the next race would occur so they could find the results. This is likely because most of the readers of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; were English colonists who probably gambled on the races as this was common at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second most frequently discussed sport in the Sport and Play sections between 1905 and 1907, far ahead of the other mentioned sports, was football (soccer). I was originally going to focus on football as the subject of my serial question, but I decided to widen the scope of my search and compare its popularity to the other sports played during this period of Egyptian history. From the issues of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; that I sampled, football was mentioned 14 times, 12 less than horse racing. It was difficult to determine when some of the articles were talking about rugby football and when they were discussing regular football as &amp;ldquo;football clubs&amp;rdquo; can refer to both. Football/soccer clubs such as the Royal Berks Regiment, the Port Said Football Club, the Suez E.T.C. Club, and several others were mentioned numerous times throughout the sampled issues. Though not as popular as horse racing, football was definitely a prominent sport in Egypt during the early 1900s and has remained and even become more popular across the world since this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at other background sources, I found that football seems to be the current most popular sport in Egypt, especially at the moment due to the fact that Egypt qualified for the 2018 World Cup. This is only the third time Egypt has ever qualified for the world cup and it&#39;s also the first time they&#39;ve done so in almost 20 years (Sky Sports). Evidently, football is a huge deal in Egypt and it was likely just as popular in the early 1900s. According to Muhammad Y. Gamal, an independent researcher of the &amp;ldquo;Arab world,&amp;rdquo; ancient Egyptians potentially played a sport similar to football. This idea is supported by ancient paintings in Egypt that show people kicking a &amp;ldquo;round object on the ground with their feet.&amp;rdquo; However, the game was never a prominent part of Egyptian society until the occupation of Egypt by the British introduced the game as we know it today. After watching British soldiers and citizens play the game and establish clubs all over the country, Egyptian citizens became interested and began establishing their own clubs as well. This is just one example of the ways English occupants impacted Egyptian society in a process that can be seen throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third most popular sport from my sample seems to be yachting. The Khedivial Yacht Club was the most prominent yachting club in the sampled issues, and there seems to have been a genuine interest in yacht races during this period of Egypt. Due to Egypt&#39;s occupation by Great Britain during this period, it&#39;s safe to assume the wealthy British citizens who occupied Egypt during this time were more interested in this sport than the native Egyptians. Articles about the Khedivial Yacht Club either described the results of recent races or the dates of upcoming races so that readers wouldn&#39;t miss out. Yachting was mentioned in 7 different articles throughout my sample, more than any of the other minor sports in Egypt at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These 3 regularly mentioned sports were different from the larger XPath&#39;s results in that tennis was much more frequent throughout the repository than all other sports than horse racing. However, when I searched through the results of the larger XPath, I found that tennis was mentioned in ads most of the time and was occasionally mentioned in the Sport and Play section when tennis tournaments were occurring. The company Davies Bryan &amp;amp; Co. was featured in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; often and consistently mentioned tennis in each of their ads because they supplied athletic goods. Because of this, I believe football was more popular at the time because the readers of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; tended to read the Sport and Play section for horse racing, football, and yachting rather than the ads that featured information about &amp;ldquo;tennis balls&amp;rdquo; being restocked &amp;ldquo;weekly&amp;rdquo;. While billiards was also mentioned more frequently than football, it seems it was most often mentioned in ads for the Eastern Exchange Hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the background source &amp;ldquo;topend sports,&amp;rdquo; football, basketball, speed-ball, tennis, and squash are the most popular sports in Egypt today. While basketball, speed-ball, and squash were not mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the interest in football and tennis seems to have remained prominent for over 100 years in Egypt amongst English occupants and Egyptian citizens. After doing further research, I found that the establishment of football clubs in Egypt by English occupants &amp;ldquo;brought football to the Nile Valley&amp;rdquo; and the same can likely be said for tennis and several other sports (ResearchGate). English culture left a mark on Egypt, and the sports they played that are still played in Egypt today are evidence of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other, less popular sports mentioned in the issues of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; included billiards, golf, tennis, swimming, cricket, rifle shooting, and even camel racing and buffalo racing. Most of these sports are still popular today, many of which are played in the Olympics; however, I don&#39;t believe camel and buffalo racing have retained their popularity in the years since. While it isn&#39;t possible to state with 100% confidence which of these sports was definitively the most popular sport in Egypt at the time, it&#39;s clear that horse racing, football, yachting, and tennis were the most prominent of the wide range of sports that were played in Egypt in the early 1900s. By potentially studying other local newspapers in Egypt and accounts of sports at the time it would be possible to narrow down the results, but by using the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; as the only primary source it&#39;s impossible to find a definite answer. Studying Egyptian newspapers rather than English newspapers like the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; would be an interesting way to compare which sports were more popular with Egyptian citizens compared to those popular with English occupants, but these are all just ideas for further research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![Sport and Play](Sport and Play.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Table.png&#34; alt=&#34;Table&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.topendsports.com/world/countries/egypt.htm&#34;&gt;https://www.topendsports.com/world/countries/egypt.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skysports.com/football/news/12098/11299870/world-cup-2018-egypt-team-profile&#34;&gt;http://www.skysports.com/football/news/12098/11299870/world-cup-2018-egypt-team-profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/263848323_The_final_whistle_how_football_terminology_took_root_in_Egypt&#34;&gt;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/263848323_The_final_whistle_how_football_terminology_took_root_in_Egypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polo in Cairo</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-bolger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-bolger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I chose to do my Analysis Project on the performances of different polo players and teams in Egypt and using different xpath queries and analysis to see who is the best polo player and the best polo team in Egypt. For this analysis, I will be searching through the editions of the 1905-1907 &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and determine which of the polo players and teams in Egypt have the better performances through those years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading through my week of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, which is March 5-10, 1906, I was always interested when it came to putting the ‘Sport and Play’ section together into xml formatting and I ended up reading most of the articles in that section. One of the headlines that would always seem to pop up for my week and interest me was the Cairo Polo Tournament. During the Cairo Polo Tournament and other polo games throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, there are usually two games that are played on a given day and the days of the week that the Cairo Polo Tournament was being played were Monday, March 5th, Wednesday, March 7th, and Friday, March 9th, of 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/sports/polo&#34;&gt;Polo&lt;/a&gt; is a game that is played on horseback between two teams, each who use mallets with long, flexible handles to drive a wooden ball down a grass field and between to goal posts. Before reading the articles about the Cairo Polo Tournament, I was uninformed about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.historic-uk.com/CultureUK/The-Origins-of-Polo/&#34;&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt; of polo and how it is played. Now, I am most informed about the sport and can understand terms that are being used in the articles about the games. Polo has aptly been called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/pdf/25485776.pdf?refreqid=search%3Af56393a29453dff0a4f76b5dc4efb7d2&#34;&gt;hockey&lt;/a&gt; on horseback. Each team usually consists of four polo players in each game and one umpire to regulate play of those games. The games are separated into four chukkers and whichever team scores the most goals at the end of the fourth chukker wins the match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.horsetimesegypt.com/pdf/articles/Polo_In_Egypt_Sport_Of_Kings_And_The_Kings_Of_The_Sport.pdf&#34;&gt;historians&lt;/a&gt; of the sport consider that the game was first actively played as a cavalry exercise in Persia as early as the 6th century BC, migrating with conquest both east to China during the Tang Dynasty (7th century AD) and west to Byzantium, arriving in Egypt during the Ayyubid period (12th century AD). When I was reading through these articles, I wanted to know the context of these games, and which of the players and teams were really good and supposed to win and which of the players and teams weren’t as good as the other teams in the tournament. When thinking about what my analysis project should be, I immediately thought about this concept and was intrigued to find out more about the world of polo in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer the questions that I had about polo teams and players, I composed and ran an xpath query in our main repository of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; issues that were already put into xml formatting. The xpath query that I ran to execute this task is &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;page&amp;quot;][contains(., &amp;quot;chukker&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;. I used the word “chukker” as my search word because there are many times where the word “polo” shows up without their being an actual game. Whenever the word “chukker” showed up, there was always a game that was attached to the term. After I ran the xpath query and sorted in the repository to see where the polo games were in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I started to read the articles that consisted of those polo games in Egypt and find out which teams played in each game, how each of the teams performed that game, as well as their players, and who ended up playing the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the polo matches and tournaments were found in the ‘Sport and Play’ section of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, which was located on page five most of the time. The search for my query on the word “chukker” came back with 54 results, which was not as much as I thought it would be, but it is still enough to do analysis for this project. Most of the returning results from my query were from the first few months of 1906 and all of those results came from tournaments that were being played. The results of this query can also be hampered because of the fact that there are some issues that have not been turned into the main repository yet, or some students just didn’t correctly format when they were doing their xml coding. I think that if I had every issue from 1905-1907, correctly formatted and turned in to the main repository, I would have a lot more results for my query and more games that I can use for evaluation to see who ends up being the best polo player and team in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bolger-goals_per_game_teams.png&#34; alt=&#34;Goals per game (Teams)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bolger-goals_per_game_players.png&#34; alt=&#34;Goals per game (Players)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After going through my results, I put together a bar graph showing the number of goals that were scored per game in all of the polo games combined by each of the teams that played, along with players that scored those goals each game. Out of the five teams that played polo in Egypt during this time, the Tourists is the team leading this category, scoring 4 goals per game. The player that had the most goals per game was Captain Stockwell, who averaged 1.5 goals per game. Stockwell plays for the Mosquitoes, who was second in this category with 3.25 goals per game. This gives a visual representation for not only which team scores the most goals per game in all of the polo games, but also which players score those goals each game for their teams and how many goals per game they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bolger-analysis_image.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lead to a polo article from March 9th, 1906, during the Cairo Polo Tournament&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although statistics are a big part of the research for my analysis project, it is not the only source that I will be using to determine who is the best polo team and player in Egypt. When I read through the articles that consist of polo games, I will see what the writer specifically says about each of the teams and the players and how they performed from his point of view, since he was there to watch all the games go down in 1906. I took down notes of what the writer said about each player and put those together with the statistics to figure out the best teams and players that play polo in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bolger-total_goals_teams.png&#34; alt=&#34;Total Goals (Teams)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bolger-total_goals_players.png&#34; alt=&#34;Total Goals (Players)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another one of my visualizations that I used is that I put together some pie charts with the number of total goals from each of the polo teams, along with their players on that team, and see which of the teams and players scored the majority of the goals in all of the polo games that were played. The Tourists were the team that scored the most goals, with a total of 16 goals, along with Captain Stockwell scoring the most goals from all the players on the polo teams, with a total of six goals. This gives a better representation of who dominates in scoring for all the polo teams and players in Egypt for 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data visualization charts that I used above are different because one shows the goals per game by each player and team, while the other shows the total amount of goals of the same players and teams. I decided to use both of these data charts because for the first one, it shows the players and teams efficiency in each game with the average amount of goals they score, while in the second one, it shows the total goals and who is the best overall scorer on each team and the best scoring polo team in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bolger-records.png&#34; alt=&#34;Records of Polo Teams&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next data visualization that it shown is a multi-bar chart for the total amount of wins and losses each of the polo teams have throughout the course of all the polo games that are played. This shows, blatantly, which of the teams that have played are really good or really bad. From this chart, you can also examine, from the teams that have good win-loss records, that most of the good players that play polo are from the teams that have winning overall records in the polo games that they play. The Tourists have one of the best records in Egypt from all the polo games, with four total wins and zero total losses. One of the worst teams in polo is E.A., who have a combined zero wins and four losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, through my xpath query results, along with my data visualizations and analysis research through the many polo game articles, I have found that the best polo team in Egypt is the Tourists and the best polo player in Egypt is Captain Stockwell. The Tourists have not lost a game of polo, with an undefeated record of 4-0, and Captain Stockwell, from the Mosquitoes, leads all polo players in goals scored and is thrived upon by the writers when he plays. Other great players that played polo in Egypt are Mr. Paravicini and Mr. Pickering, who both play for the undefeated Tourists and each scored five total goals from their polo games. Even though there wasn’t as much information for analysis as I thought there would be, the information that I gathered for research was still appealing and the game of polo in Egypt is something that the people who loved sports wanted to read in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainfall</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-degroat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-degroat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microhistory gives the ability to focus on smaller details in history to be able to fully understand why and what happened during that day in time. Microhistory for this class allowed the students to investigate the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; newspaper from 1905, 1906, and 1907 and see details from our certain weeks assigned to us. The week that was given to me was the week of June 17th, 1907. After analyzing six days of this newspaper, we start to see similarities and patterns in the paper overtime. Each day has around six to eight pages and while each page is different, each page of each day has a similar format with different topics. Page one consisted mainly of ads which were pretty much uniform throughout all of the days for my week. Page two has some adds mixed with some text. The page threes are mostly text. They all start with “Local and General,” then the “Financial Crisis,” and then articles about what is happening at the time. Page four mostly consists of charts full of data, ranging from cotons to stocks and shares. Page five is more information about what was happening in their society at the moment. It has two columns of telegrams, a daily weather report, and usually a story highlighting a specific person. Page six continued with more ads along with ads that would normally go on flyers and some data. The daily weather report on page five is my main focus for this assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading a copy of the master content from GitHub, I used it to isolate the daily weather report from the deliverables. Using the daily weather report I wanted to find out all of the inputted values for the amount of rainfall every month for every year. After retrieving the values, I could not fully complete the graph that I wanted to have consisting of months, years. The reason behind it is because some of the data consisted of “Heavy Dew” for some records rather than a number of how much rain. Because it is a text and not an exact amount, the graph could not show the amount of rain each month for each year. However, I computed a graph that shows and added amount of rainfall for the month. There are some months with no rainfall because it did not rain, and it is recorded that it did not rain that day. The day that it rained the most is undetectable because there are two entries of “Heavy Dew” which could be a larger number, we do not know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In analyzing how much rainfall there was over time, after looking at the graph, we can conclude that there was only recorded rainfall for fourteen out of the thirty-six months. After going through a majority of the files to be sure that the data for the rainfall daily was correct, I also chose to read the information under the “Remarks” tab regarding the weather for that particular day. Doing this give me a look to be sure that the value entered is correct. I can determine this because if a value is recorded as no rain for that particular day, but the remarks for that day says that there was heavy pour or “dew”, then I know that the data is incorrect. While I did not read through all of them, because there are an awful lot, I read through one every other Monday. I chose to do it like this because it is easier to stick to one certain day to look at rather than switching days and getting mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;degroat-analysis-graph1.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph above shows the amount of rainfall from 1905 to 1907 each month. The months that have no data are crammed together and not shown because there is no recorded date for those days or months. For the graph, the average rainfall cannot be shown because all of the entered values are not all numbers so the graph can only show the amount of times that it rained every month. After working with Webber in office hours, we came to the conclusion that there was no other possible way to retrieve that data for average rainfall and that the only possible solution was to record the data for how many times it rained per month per year. Using the daily weather report data, not only rainfall for the day is shown. It also consists of direction of wind, maximum temperature, and humidity level for the day, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;degroat-analysis-graph2.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;graph2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph displays the amount of rainfall per month in hundredths of a mm. The difference between the two graphs is that this one disregards the values that say &amp;ldquo;Heavy Dew&amp;rdquo; and only focuses on the numerical values that were inputted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that I chose doing a graph using the data of rainfall recorded in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; for all three years is because I favor the rain. There is no special reason that has to do with my major or what I am interested in, it is simply because I enjoy the rain and I was curious to see how often it rained in Egypt during this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to obtain a graph of the amount of times it rained per month per year in Egypt, I first had to search in the master content folder on my hard drive. The XPath query that I used to get these results is &lt;code&gt;//cell[contains(.,&amp;quot;Rainfall&amp;quot;)]//following-sibling::cell/measure&lt;/code&gt;. Doing this, I was given back the days and values inputted for rainfall each day in the newspaper. The XPath that I used tells Oxygen XML Editor to first look in the second level of cells that contain “Rainfall” and to then to look into the measure to see what the value is. After 73.3 seconds, the XPath came back successful, returning the inputted values and dates for which it rained daily. The data is formatted that each value is measured in millimeters and every “null” value was recorded as no rainfall for that day. The “Heavy Dew” description imputed for the value of rainfall cannot be considered a number because it is unknown how many millimeters “Heavy Dew” can account for. After getting the information from Oxygen XML, I used Atom to take out the information that I did not need to use and took everything out except the date and amount of rainfall for that day. Then, using Tableau, I uploaded my data into the software and computed a graph of how much is rained every month from 1905 to 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strengths and weaknesses of using the content folder of the information from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; can cause problems or be extremely helpful. A weakness about using the master content folder to search through and pull information from is that it is information put into the document by persons, so it is not 100% accurate if even one person did it wrong or left out information. A strength of the content information is that all of the information and data is in one large file that can be searched through completely. Another weakness is that not only could the information be wrong, but there could be information left out of the documents. Whomever transferred the information from the newspaper to the content folder could have left out certain numbers, ads, or articles. When it comes to searching for something, if it is left out of the file, then the information is not there to be found. For example, while searching for rainfall for every day, if someone who was entering the information for May 8th forgot to change the value of rainfall from 0 to 2 mm, then my data is inaccurate based on how much it actually rained that day. Therefore, whatever documents are changed by a person need to be trusted that the information updated is correct information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking at the project titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/analysis/2017/vaverek-analysis&#34;&gt;Making Sense of the Daily Weather Report&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; I looked through the picture that they used, and in this certain one, there was no section for rainfall. There are multiple cases where this occurs. Some of the newspaper issues do not have rainfall in the daily weather report. This could be because it did not rain that day. However, there are multiple times that it is labeled in the paper with a value showing that there was no rain for that day. So the question that arises is, why do some days not have the rainfall tab in it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding an external source, I also looked at the website &lt;a href=&#34;oldweather.org&#34;&gt;oldweather.org&lt;/a&gt; to see if there was any information about rainfall during 1907 and the earliest dates that I could find weather reports on were from 1913 to today. I searched the website for any information regarding 1905, 1906, and 1907 but no information surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reported Accidents, Incidents, Tragedies, and Disasters</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-cannon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-cannon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we think of the day to day lives of people we may think of a consistent schedule that only changes when major events happen.  However, from first hand experience I know the largest disruption to daily life are accidents.  So when looking at the lives of people living halfway across the world over a hundred years ago I wanted to see how they handled these accidents and in what ways they were affected by them.  In this analysis I will be finding the various accidents that made it into the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; between the years of 1905-1906 and will compile the data based on what they were called, what type of accidents were likely to be deemed newsworthy, and to see what sort of long term impact (if any) they might have had on the city of Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I need to do however is to define what I am searching for.  This is where the source came in handy, as even though it was more recent than the time period I will be analyzing it still laid out a format on analyzing accidents.  According to the study, in a group of 500 young Egyptian men around 4.6% of the group experienced an accident within sometime in their lives.  This is helpful in analyzing what types of accidents were most likely to make the headlines as well since the study was also able to gather the percentage of people who experienced various accidents such as motor or fights or even an electrical problem.  When I say the word accident, I will be referring to both accident and any other word that was used to describe such an event.  Another term I looked for when studying accidents was the word “incident,” which it turned out gave a lot of results but not the same kind of news.  While articles with the title accident they focused on an event that was caused by something random or unexpected whereas incidents seemed to be used more for intentional conflicts such as on the frontiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking all the times that the word accident was used in just the headline for an article I was able to gather 103 results.  Many of these headlines were duplicates in the Local and General section such as “Terrible Accident” or “Motor Accident.”  I thus divided these titles by certain features with accidents related to vehicles categorized under &amp;ldquo;vehicles&amp;rdquo; and more general headlines like &amp;ldquo;tragic accident&amp;rdquo; under the &amp;ldquo;general section (please see the graph for Accident Reappearance for a visualization). The most interesting ones were ones that had a specific title next to them, such as those that mention the specific individual by name such as an article from the June 12th, 1905 that had the headline “Mr. Clowes in a Railway Accident” or the “Kafr Zayat Railway Accident” on June 23, 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the year 1905, the month of June saw a large spike in railway accidents with headlines such as the two I mentioned in the previous paragraph as well as those with the title “Cairo Express Derailed” and “Another Railway Accident.”  This indicates a massive problem with the Egyptian rail system if it was a frequent enough disaster to be a cause for discussion repeatedly in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.  Another accident that got multiple articles was when the King of England ending up tearing a tendon in his leg.  According to the articles (one was published on the 17th of November and another on the 18th in the year 1905) King Edward VII had ended up tearing a tendon above his ankle.  The articles focused on separate issues, with the preliminary one giving the details about where the King had his accident, what he was doing, and tried to downplay what exactly happened to him while the follow-up that was issued the following day gave the specific details such as where the injury was, who was surrounding and greeting the King during his rough time, and what he plans to do since he was issued to be in no danger anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two articles help illustrate who was reading the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, cause while the railway accidents and other disasters that frequently made the news were never issued a follow-up (including one of the specific headlines that had a government agent named) the only one to receive one was based on a foreign king.  This points the disparity between using the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; as a source for the common Alexandrian people as this paper was written for an international audience in mind and focused on English events whenever they had any impact on its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another term I was expecting to yield results was any headline pertaining to tragedy, however to my surprise I was only able to pull up 17 headlines containing the word.  The title seemed to indicate that when it was used it was during an act that was either indefensible or an incident that had personal information on the victims.  One such example was on January 4, 1905 when two men were killed by a third when they all wished to marry the sister to one of the victims.  This seems to indicate that the news did not try to stir emotions as tragedy is usually implied to an act that was meant to stir up emotions.  Even when I tried to broaden the search by then going to tragic it came up with even less results with a measly 4.  Most of these events could not even be labeled as accidents as the previous article I highlighted and another titled “M. Cronier’s Tragic Suicide” were intentional and thus do not fit into the scope of the search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last term I decided to hunt for in my topic was the term “disaster.”  This also pulled a surprisingly low number of results with just 16 in the headline.  These events seem to correlate to stories that have no good things about them, such as one from the July 10th edition from 1905 that had a headline for “French Submarine Disaster: Crew Reported Dead” when a submarine was almost saved by a crane only to be dropped back after fresh air was brought in to prolong their suffering.  Most of these headlines also seem to happen to either international areas or to ship accidents with three headlines for Submarine disasters being the most used stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other term that pulled popular reports was the term incidents, that came up with 43 headlines.  Most of these incidents as I mentioned before were based more on international incidents such as frontier skirmishes that happened in areas such as Morocco and the North Sea or happened in international waters such as the “Andromeda Incident” that happened on the 10th of January in 1905.  This language indicates how the term accidents and incidents were used, as while they could be mean events that were caused by something tragic or unintentional they were events that involved only one party and an event that happened on an international level respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these results were gathered by using Xpath’s results features using the find and replace function.  This turned out to be a great way to find what I was looking for, as since my topic was dealing mostly with headlines and the diction that was used in it.  It also helped that the Xpath queries had specifications that I could use.  These involved searching in just the headlines as well as using the &lt;code&gt;\w+&lt;/code&gt; feature to find which words were most likely to follow accident.  These turned out to generate the most results than other methods of searching as this limited this to just articles meant to grab attention with the word accident rather than being used in the middle of a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other ways this search could be improved upon would be by doing both more research as well as using more data.  This could be done by digging deeper into the articles themselves to compare the similarities between articles in terms of the words in the passage.  Perhaps these articles have a certain area in which to occupy and this could be analyzed by comparing the number of words or the similarities in language to see if they all have a connecting theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-visualization&#34;&gt;Text visualization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using Tableau I was able to make the data visible.  The charts indicate the various patterns and occurrences of the term accident itself and when it appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.  The first graph &amp;ldquo;Accident Occurrence&amp;rdquo; was used to show the general trend of accidents from the years 1905 to 1906.  The Table for the reappearance for headlines containing the word accident was used, and the last graph is showing the different categories of accidents and when they appeared in the headlines during these two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These headlines help to paint what this world was like to live in, either through learning about the individual stories that people would have gossiped about in the streets or by even detailing some of the day to day events that impacted the people.  These events are themselves tricky to define as I am sure there were more accidents in the city that did not make it into the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and thus lost to us, but this is a good starting point to gather information on the most exciting and mundane act in an average citizen’s day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;source&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afifi, Raouf M., Sameh Sh. Zaytou, Ahmed A. El Raggal, Amani Qulali, and Hesham A. K. Ayoub. 2015. &amp;ldquo;Involvement of Male Youth into Accidents in Upper Egypt: Pattern and Risk Analysis.&amp;rdquo; Health (1949-4998) 7, no. 8: 965-975.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/124446949@N06/35500328521&#34; alt=&#34;crash&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robberies in Alexandria</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-donofrio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-donofrio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Theft should be considered one of the most selfish crimes, as it is literally the act of stealing from others in order to benefit from their belongings. Whether it is out of desperation, or simply for the rush of adrenaline, robbery should not be a crime that is as common as it is today. However, robbery has not only been an issue recently; as shown in multiple issues of &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; from 1905 to 1906. My main purpose in this analysis is to make evident the prominence of theft in Egypt during the time period previously stated. In doing this, I will try to uncover a pattern with the robberies by analyzing when and where the theft occurred, what type of robbery it was and if the crime ended in murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-accumulation&#34;&gt;Data Accumulation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What influenced me to look into the prevalence of theft in Egypt was my assigned Monday issue. On October 29, 1906 alone, there were three news articles reporting a sort of robbery that had occurred.  This made me think that there would be similar articles in other issues. However, the three news stories I had read in my issue used different wording to describe the robbery. This caused me to realize that if I wanted to get the most results possible, I would have to test multiple different keywords. Therefore, I ended up using five different keywords, which combined, gave me 51 occurrences of robbery to work with. The keywords I used each gave me a different number of results: my first search using the word “robbery” came back with 49 items, “burglary” with 152 items, “thief” with 39 items, “thieves” with 54 items, and finally, “theft” with 102 items. It was not uncommon for these keywords to overlap in an article, so I had to ensure that I was not reporting an instance in my data more than once. I decided the easiest way to collect my data was to make an Excel sheet with four columns titled date, place, type of robbery, and if the crime ended in murder or not. I created a typology for the different kinds of robbery; individual, house, business, ship, post office and train. Most of these are self-explanatory, being that a house, business, ship, post office or train robbery is one where items are being stolen from that particular setting. However, to clarify, an individual robbery is one where belongings being held on an individual are stolen. After collecting this data, I plugged it into Tableau, where I created different visuals to present my data in an aesthetically pleasing way, which is shown further in my project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;date&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An aspect of the robberies that I thought would be interesting to examine was the dates that they occurred. I wanted to see if there was a spike in robberies during a certain time period. However, in doing this, I had to acknowledge the fact that the digitization of &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; during 1906 is not fully completed. This could be the possible explanation as to why in the line graph below, robberies decrease in 1906. However, it could be possible that this information is true and there actually was a decrease in theft in 1906 due to possibly stricter security or punishment, which could decrease the desire for people to steal. Something else that I found to be unique was the drastic decrease and then increase between August and November of 1905. It is pretty much impossible to discover the exact cause for the extremity of going from seven robberies in August, to one in October, then back to seven in November. However, a hypothesis for the reasoning behind this could be that after such a large amount of robberies in August, security became tighter, causing theft to decrease. Then once robberies decreased, people might have loosened up security because they assumed robberies were less likely to happen, triggering an increase in theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;place&#34;&gt;Place&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another significant detail I decided to analyze about the robberies was the city in which the crimes took place. As shown in the visual, the majority of the robberies occurred in the northeast region of Egypt. There are many possible reasonings for this trend, including the fact that the capital of Egypt, Cairo, is located in the northeast. In fact, 16 of the 51 robberies took place in Cairo. Since Cairo is the capital, it can be inferred that the city was considered modernized and urban, taking in an influx of wealthy European immigrants. This could be the reason that the capital was targeted for theft. The northeast also has access to oceans, making ship ports another easy target for burglary. Thieves may have been attracted to the immigrants coming in on ships with valuable belongings, as well as materials being imported and exported through ports, like Port Said which had 3 reported robberies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I found to be important when analyzing the trends in robberies was the type of theft that occurred. I categorized the robberies by whether it was a house, individual, business, post office, train or ship that was robbed. The two most popular types of theft out of my data are house and individual robberies, each occurring 13 different times. I’m guessing the reasoning behind this is the lack of security. The early 1900’s was a time before high-tech security systems, so homes were not equipped with alarms or cameras making them an easy target. Also, the robbery of an individual may seem easy for a thief as it can go unnoticed through pickpocketing. Another popular type of robbery was train robbery. Again, technology was not how it is today, so one of the most popular forms of transportation was by train. People would most likely travel with their belongings, which may include valuables, that can be targeted easily by thieves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;murder&#34;&gt;Murder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;murder-donofrio.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Robberies that ended in murder&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all 51 reported cases of robbery that I analyzed from &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, only seven of them ended in murder. From this we can infer that theft was not meant to be a violent act, and most likely only sparked violence in special circumstances. Of the types of robbery mentioned before, the murders only took place in house and individual robberies. The reasoning for murders occurring only during these types of robberies could be because of human interference. Theft can be considered a desperate act when someone is in need of items, therefor one may do anything in order to gain those items, including killing anyone who gets in the way. While train, ship, business and post office robberies could occur when no one is working a shift, a home burglary is unpredictable, as it is hard to know if someone is in a house at a certain time. The robbing of an individual is also unpredictable, because if the individual realizes he is being robbed, he may fight back, causing the thief to act without thinking and kill the victim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;obstacles&#34;&gt;Obstacles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collecting my data, I had some instances of difficulty, since the topic I chose is not one that can be found with ease using a query search. Therefor it was very tedious work to have to search each keyword and read through every article to pull out the data that I needed. Another issue that I had to be aware of was ensuring that the article I was reading was an actual news article of a robbery. When I would search my keywords, items other than news articles, like advertisements and reviews, would come up containing that keyword, making the process of reading through the results more time consuming. For example, when searching for the word “burglary” an advertisement for “G. Marcus &amp;amp; Co.” insurance company made up over half of the 152 results, as the insurance company also covers “burglary risks.” Something else that I was considering collecting in my data before I started my research was gender of the criminal. However, once I began my search, I discovered that either most articles did not specify gender, or they had not caught the robber yet, making it difficult to use gender as a category in my analysis. Finally, I would like to ensure the clarity of the fact that although &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is a real publication from Egypt in the early 1900’s, the digitization of these issues was done by students, and can most likely contain flawed, misspelled and inaccurate information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robbery was clearly a serious issue during the early 1900’s in Egypt, as 51 cases were reported in &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. The publication also ran follow-up stories on some of the crimes, reporting on whether the thief was caught and updating the public on his sentencing. It was very stimulating for me to look into the data that I collected and hypothesize the correlation between certain aspects of the robberies, like if the place the crime occurred had anything to do with the type of robbery. The frequency of theft in Egypt is just one of the many reasons as to why we have security technology today to catch thieves and more importantly, prevent theft altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stocks and Shares</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-metallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-metallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Expanding on my blog post “Is Egypt In a Bubble?,” I dug through the pages of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and traced the “Stocks and Shares” table throughout 1905 and 1906 with as much data available from 1907 as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This table listed the stock with its stock price as well as its debenture price. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=define+a+share+of+stock&amp;amp;oq=define+a+share&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.2.69i57j0l5.5922j1j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&#34;&gt;stock&lt;/a&gt; is a portion of company ownership that is sold to the public for which the owner of the stock receives a part of said company’s earnings. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?ei=Ky7eWu2DL4WSzwL2_7T4Ag&amp;amp;q=define+a+debenture&amp;amp;oq=define+a+debenture&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..0j0i22i30k1l9.6015.6015.0.6450.1.1.0.0.0.0.114.114.0j1.1.0....0...1.1.64.psy-ab..0.1.112....0.t1UcNE-Mr5I&#34;&gt;debenture&lt;/a&gt;, is similar to a stock, but instead of the value of the stock rising and falling with the company’s wealth, it has a fixed rate of return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this project was to not only compare the stock price and debenture price of any given investment over time but also to compare both a “gilt edged” investment, meaning a strong investment, to one that may have been suffering in the oncoming financial crisis in Egypt at this time period (as explained in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/metallo-is-egypt-in-a-bubble/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What spurred this investigation were the parallels that I was seeing between the Great Recession of 2008 in the US and the articles written about the Egyptian economy in 1907.  It is true that markets are cyclical and have their ups and downs. For the most part, we can see these cyclical trends coming every 10 or so years. This would mean that exactly a decade before the US market 2008, Egypt would have been feeling the sting of an economic crisis similar to that of the one the US experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for information on the Egyptian market failures of 1907, the Panic of 1907, also called the Knickerbocker Crisis, kept appearing as a result of my searches. The Knickerbocker Crisis was a US Stock market dip that occurred in October of 1907 and the effects of this crash were not limited to the US as explained &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/2141305?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=panic&amp;amp;searchText=of&amp;amp;searchText=1907&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dpanic%2Bof%2B1907&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracing the financial articles throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, and as noted in my blog post, it is clear that Egypt felt their economy failing and very quickly what was a “localized” crisis began to spread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, the crisis was felt abroad, as seen in the article below from the introduction to a quote of a French article. Not only is the crisis officially “raging” in Egypt but is felt all over Europe (which, honestly, has the most to lose seeing as Egypt was still under European rule).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/feeling-the-crisis-abroad-19070619.JPG?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;feeling the crisis abroad 19070619&#34;&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the visualization of the results from tracing the “Stocks and Shares” table in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.  The strong stock that was analyzed was The Agricultural Bank of Egypt and the stock that was supposedly losing traction in the market was the Land Bank of Egypt. This is not unlike what most consider the cause of the US Great Recession of 2008 and many other economic recessions throughout history, speculation, in particular land speculation (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/43189952?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=great&amp;amp;searchText=recession&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dgreat%2Brecession%26amp%3Bfilter%3D&#34;&gt;or in 2008 the bundling of blatantly faulty mortgages&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;metallo-sharevdebenture2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;share vs debenture visualization&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this visualization, it is evident, in a loose pattern, that the share and debenture prices seem to mirror each other. It seems, by this visualization, that the Land Bank of Egypt outperformed the Agricultural Bank of Egypt which is the opposite of what is expected given the information found in the financial articles of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. As to why the debenture price of the Land Bank was so much higher in general than the other measure, I cannot say.  This could be due to improper coding of the Gazette or some other underlying force at the time. To speak to the stability of the investments, the only one that seemed to be unwavering was the debenture price of the Agricultural Bank which we would expect from a “gilt edged” security. The share price of the same investment does not stay as steady but is still much more constant than the Land Bank debenture price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big Four Theatres</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-hutson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-hutson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was a well-rounded newspaper containing topics varying from weather, plague, sports, and daily trade. There are so many topics covered, it was Egypt’s source of news in the early 20th century. While going through the newspaper, coding it, and reading the different stories, something stuck out to me. I was coding page four of my Monday issue when I read about a show within a small theatre in Egypt. This stimulated my interest in what shows were like in the 1900s compared to how they are now. With all the different events going on within the newspaper, there was a large emphasis on the arts, especially musical art and theatres. This was interesting to me because I was always around live shows growing up. I wanted to see how things were different over a hundred years ago in a different country than they are today as I know it. Also, I wanted to compare the theatres mentioned within the region the newspaper covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-acquainted&#34;&gt;Getting Acquainted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four prominent theatres that occur throughout the newspaper from the years 1905-1907, although there are more that show up. Most of the appearances from these theatres come during our winter months (December-March), I am assuming because that is when most of the shows happened. The four theatres that show up the most are the Zizinia Theatre, Verdi Theatre, Abbas Helmy Theatre, and the Alhambra Theatre. To look more in depth to these theatres I used the query, &lt;code&gt;//head[contains(., &amp;quot;THEATRE&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;. This searched all the headers containing the word theatre. The all caps were necessary because most of the headers coded for use all caps as the header and also used “Theatre” as a search to find the headers with lowercase letters. After gathering more and more information about what theatres were present and which ones appeared the most, I changed theatre to the different names of the specific theatre to narrow my search. The Zizinia and Alhambra theatre show up the majority of the time compared to the other two. Also, the Zizinia Theatre seems to be widely popular, and by far the most popular out of all of them based on the reporting on it. The Alhambra shows up the most number of times trhoughout the paper. The way these theatres worked was a company would rent out the theatre for a certain period of time and put on shows there. A lot of the time there were operas, but other shows range from dramas or comedies. The Verdi Theatre, for example, is a company and they rent out the Cairo Opera House to do their shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought when reading into these different theatres was where they were located. I thought the location would give me more insight on how each one functioned, and I could draw my conclusions on the overall performance from there. To my surprise, the Zizinia Theatre, Abbas Helmy Theatre, and Alhambra Theatre are all located in Alexandria, while the Verdi Theatre location is in Cairo. Alexandria is on the coast, which means more people coming through the city such as tourists or just passing through. I think there is a greater demand for theatres in Alexandria because of this foot traffic. Cairo is also a large city in Egypt, but the demand for theatre is less there. The trend for this holds up in the actual stories of the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hutson-Visualization.png&#34; alt=&#34;theatres&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;verdi-theatre&#34;&gt;Verdi Theatre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Verdi Theatre in Cairo struggled a lot during this time period, which surprised me because of the magnificent layout the Cairo Opera House was. The Khedive at the time wanted something superior to anything else, so the building cost a fortune, but was well constructed (LePaitre 1963). However, upon deeper research in the newspaper, reading what the editors wrote on the Verdi theatre, my opinion was quickly changed. On one occasion in the newspaper, an editor was begging the people of Cairo to go watch shows there. They said the theatre was empty and the companies did not want to rent it out anymore. At one point the Verdi Theatre even went on strike because of their struggles. There is never anything of this sort about the other theatres in Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The struggling of the Verdi theatre intrigued me. They struggled at the beginning of 1905, as I was going down the dates, another event was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fire&#34;&gt;Fire!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Abbas Helmy Theatre caught on fire in April of 1905. No one was injured, but the whole theatre was destroyed, and this caused a few things to happen. After the sudden decline of Abbas Helmy, the Alhambra Theatre received a lot more coverage from the newspaper, and I think this gave them a lot more popularity. Towards the end of the content (around April 1907) there is reporting of the Alhmabra Theatre getting an upgrade. Another cause and effect was the emergence of a new theatre, the Ezbekieh Theatre. However, this new theatre was located in Cairo. This theatre was built next to the Ezbekieh Gardens, along with another theatre next to it. The Khedive made a lot of money by renting these theatres out to various European companies (Barbour 1935).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consistency&#34;&gt;Consistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular one, the Zizinia Theatre, had a wide variety of shows such as dramas, comedies, and even the occasional biblical one. For most of the two-year time period, they were occupied by French companies. The newspaper would always comment on how the audience reacted so fantastically to all of the plays at this place. Nothing ever negative was really written about them in the paper, the Zizinia seem like the perfect place to go watch a show. I read a journal review titled, “Alexandria: Its Town Planning Development” (Riad 1933) about the layout of Alexandria as a city and the different things going on within the city. The city seems very well put together. It has a wide variety of buildings and grew up on the Mediterranean Sea experiencing a lot of different cultures and travelers coming through. This gave them a diverse culture, as well as a diverse audience for their theatre shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researching this topic was very rewarding as I learned a lot, but it was very challenging at the same time. A lot of the items written about the theatres are repetitive, or not interesting. Since this is a day-to-day newspaper, not everything is exciting all the time. There are a lot of reports on these theatres giving an average show, they give how the audience reacts, and that is it. This repetition over the course of reading hundreds of items on four different theatres was tough. Another challenge I faced was the bias of the newspaper. News in the present day can be very biased and push the audience’s perspective in one way or the other. I am not sure if this is what was going on in the  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, or if they were factual and the Zizinia Theatre was really that amazing, or that the Verdi Theatre really struggled that much. The editors in the paper make it seem like nothing ever goes wrong at the Zizinia Theatre and it makes me wonder if this is just biased reporting because they favor the theatre, or if it was actually a fantastic place to go watch a show. Also, my sample size is only two years, between 1905-1907. During this time, certain theatres could have been thriving while others suffering, but before or after the dates the newspaper looks at, the roles could have been reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;things-learned&#34;&gt;Things Learned&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I learned in general were a lot of European and Middle Eastern companies rented out the theatres. At first thought, I would have expected other African companies to rent out the buildings, but after more thought and research this makes sense. Europe had just decolonized Africa, but this means a lot of European culture was still prevalent in Egypt. Another thing I learned was that there was a certain expectation for these shows. The way editors wrote about them, I could just feel the standard that was set. This leads me to believe that not only the theatre was prominent in Egypt, but the arts as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the reporting is factual, which I assume it is, the Zizinia Theatre is definitely the most popular. The Alhambra theatre shows up the most amount of times, and is also very popular. There are more theatres in Alexandria, and this make sense because of the population, and what that city has to offer. My focus of interest was on events at theatres, that were not actual shows in the theatre. The paper liked talking about these different events such as the strike at Verdi Theatre, the fire at Abbas Theatre. There are also other things mentioned in the paper not a part of the four prominent ones such as an attempted murder that was stopped by the audience, wrestling shows, and another strike. Overall, I think the theatre system back then was the same. In present day, there are more genres and of course more theatres in general. I think the talent level has also increased, with the more variety because actors are expected to be able to portray many different characters, sing, and dance. Whereas in this time period it seems like the level of ability consists of a few genres and mainly singing. However, for the early 20th century, I was impressed with the quality of shows produced and reported on in the Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barbour, Nevill. “&lt;a href=&#34;www.jstor.org/stable/608109&#34;&gt;The Arabic Theatre in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the School of Oriental Studies&lt;/em&gt;, University of London, vol. 8, no. 1, 1935, pp. 173–187.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LePaitre, George-Patrick. “&lt;a href=&#34;www.jstor.org/stable/3393642&#34;&gt;A History Teacher Visits the Cairo Opera&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;em&gt;Music Educators Journal&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 49, no. 4, 1963, pp. 103–103.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riad, Mahmoud. “&lt;a href=&#34;www.jstor.org/stable/40101080&#34;&gt;Alexandria: Its Town Planning Development&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;em&gt;The Town Planning Review&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 15, no. 4, 1933, pp. 233–248.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;www.timemaps.com/history/egypt-1215ad/&#34;&gt;Egyptian History 1215 CE&lt;/a&gt;.” TimeMaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Egyptian education system in the early 1900s</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-clark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-clark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will explore the Egyptian education system in the early 1900s. This project will include the locations of schools that make headlines in the news, including the schools that are being advertised. This will also include what months of the year education seems to be of most importance in the newspaper. I will also look for trends in the school system, such as common problems (Sailer, 1912) or modernization (Saleh, 2012). Keep in mind throughout this paper the changes that Egypt is going through during the early colonization period of 1905. Britain was occupying Egypt during this time and many other countries were represented in Egypt making Egypt a melting pot like America. Education and schools in Egypt were overall successful between 1905 and 1907 because of the new schools built, resolved conflicts, and excellent displays of intelligence from the children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first preliminary query I ran was for any div type item that contained the word school, but that resulted in too many vague answers that were repeated and not entirely relevant to my purpose. Ultimately my query boiled down to school* in any headline within the master content folder which returned 234 results. Upon first glance this information would indicate that education is something that the Egyptians took seriously in the early 1900s, but with further research, a lot of those instances of the word school in a headline were simply advertisements for those schools. These advertisements are still relevant to my project, however, because it proves that the school system itself was interested in persuading the parents that were reading this newspaper to send their children off to school through mere exposure advertising. The school that advertised the most was the Berlitz School of Languages, which offered lessons in languages such as French, German, Arabic, and others. I also noticed off the bat that there wasn’t much of a pattern in the months that schools showed up most in the newspaper. The only months that were slightly above average in displaying the word school were July and October, and I will discuss why later in the paper. This lack of dominance by any specific month proves that education was pushed evenly throughout the year, therefore represented well in Egypt throughout the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After skimming through all of the results I noticed that there were certainly a lot more schools that were successful than there were schools that were failing. This was due to the increase in the number of children interested in learning and the many advertisements for schools in Egypt during this time. Even though most schools in Egypt were doing great in this time, the parents and students wanted more funding to come from the Government. The Egyptian Government, however, was pouring all of their money into different public buildings and physically building new schools because the current schools are overcrowded. There were, in fact, four schools that were either built or planned to be built between 1905 and 1907 in Egypt including the fourth secondary school and an Italian school. This progress of the school system proves that the population in Egypt was growing during this time and these people that were coming to Egypt wanted to go to school and learn which is positive for this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on to the schools that showed up the most in the newspaper, the Berlitz Schools of Languages showed up in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; 110 times between 1905-1907. This means that the Berlitz Schools took up almost half of my results from my query. For the most part, the Berlitz Schools were simply advertising for their individual language lessons, and the other times they showed up in the newspaper it was for an award they received for doing such a great job teaching. The reason that the Berlitz Schools advertised so often was because it occurred year-round, that is there was no start date and end date so the ads played through every month, because it was more similar to a tutoring service for those who wanted to learn a new language. This is important because it really proves that many different cultures were flooding into Egypt and it was best for people to understand and speak several languages so that they could communicate with each other. The progress of Egypt as a country was clear in population, economy, politics, and most importantly, education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there were a few schools that showed up many times in the paper for prestigious reasons (Berlitz, Zeitoun Blind School, several girls’ schools), there were a couple of higher education schools that gathered fame in the paper for their students’ disobedience. More specifically, in 1905 and 1906 the Polytechnic school and the Khedivial Law school students went on strike against the administration. It was the Polytechnic schools that went on strike first in 1905 because the students were simply unhappy with the way the school was run, but the strike was short lived after the administration threatened the disobedient students with expulsion. However, the absence of strike in the Egyptian schools was short lived because in 1906 the Khedivial Law school students went on strike because of the wrongful expulsion of four students. These law Students were firmer in their strike than the previous Polytechnic students. The Law students released a list of demands, some unreasonable, some manageable, that ultimately resulted in some change is the schools. The Law students went on strike on and off with coming and going support from other students from different schools, such as the Polytechnic School, the Agricultural School, and the Ras-el-Tin school. These strikes were the lowest points for everyone, students and administrators, in the education system because during these strikes there were no students learning what they needed to be learning and the administrators were losing money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on the flaw that is the disobedient students, the lack of funding, which was one of the causes for the students to strike, was another huge problem in the Egyptian Education system. According to T.H.P Sailer who visited Egyptian schools in 1907, the schools were dirty, with not enough desks and no real learning materials in the elementary schools, or kuttabs. The Government was still trying their best, however, and it was displayed with how they constructed their higher education schools (with sufficient supplies), and how they pushed teaching as a great job, by not making education majors pay for their higher education (Sailer, 1912). So again the theme of underfunded schools is displayed throughout the younger schools, but in the newer schools, that were built based of the European models, the students and teachers reaped the benefits of the small amount of money that they did receive from the Government.
Furthermore, into today’s Egyptian education system, there are still money problems. The Egyptian government spends 3.5% of their GDP on education which is lower than the international average. Unlike in 1907, however, the Government has stopped persuading children to even attend school as it is still easy to get a job without a degree if the children just focused on honing their skills for civil service jobs (Fahmy, 2008). This lack of interest from the Government along with the continued lack of funding 100 years later is why parents and students are fed up with the Education system in Egypt. Today the school system certainly seems far less successful than it was 100 years ago, because at least in 1907 the schools were advertising for themselves in the newspaper and many new schools were being built. This article proves, however, that a lack of funding from the Egyptian Government has always been an issue for Egypt’s schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the Egyptian education system was doing its best to teach the all of the young, diverse children living in Egypt. Many schools did an excellent job of molding their students into intelligent and respectable young adults. For example, the St. Andrew’s Girls’ Schools (upper and lower), and the Church of Scotland Schools held exhibitions at the end of the 1905 school year where their students and teachers could show off their work from the semester. The end of the school year was typically sometime in late July. So, the students had a small ‘summer break’, if you will, between the months of August and September before school started again in October. All of these exhibitions proved to be important in deciding whether or not the staff of the schools were successful in educating the students, which they were successful for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Egypt’s school system between 1905 and 1907 were as successful as it could be in teaching the diverse group of children at the time. Language skills were pushed on to the children because of the influx of different cultures into Egypt at this time. Although a lack of funding and sometimes out of line students got in the way of a good education, at the end of the day and at the end of the school year, the children proved that they learned something valuable from the schools, which should be the goal of all school systems even today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fahmy, A. (2008, October 1). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brookings.edu/opinions/egypts-education-system-parents-and-students-emerge-as-a-new-force-for-reform/&#34;&gt;Egypt&#39;s Education System: Parents and Students Emerge as a New Force for Reform&lt;/a&gt;. Retrieved from Brookings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sailer, T. H. (1912). &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/j.1758-6631.1912.tb00684.x&#34;&gt;Problems of Education in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;. Retrieved from Wiley Online Library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saleh, M. (2012). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tse-fr.eu/sites/default/files/medias/doc/wp/iast/century.pdf&#34;&gt;From Kuttabs to Schools: Educational Modernization, Religion, and Human Capital in Twentieth Century Egypt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fascination with death</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-fitzpatrick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-fitzpatrick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans have a natural sense of curiosity about them, and this curiosity can be innocent such as the fascination with a person they’ll never meet and instead reading stories about them, but it can also be darker and the focus can be on murder and torture. The source of our curiosity stems from a trait of human species call neoteny, according to Tom Stafford of BBC. This trait means that we as a species are more childlike than other mammals and tend to want to explore, whether it be physically or mentally. This trait could explain why the stories about death and murder seem to be some of the most popular articles in the  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since death is such a popular topic among readers, the newspaper probably liked and even encouraged articles and advertisements to write about it because it would please the readers, which in turn would result in more people reading meaning more money for the company. There is a common advertisement found in almost every day’s issue which is titled “The  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;” and is the subscriptions and advertisements article which has information on prices. One of the topics suggested in the advertisement sections is “death” showing how popular and common it was to find articles about it throughout the newspaper. The idea of death is almost a form of entertainment for humans. We love to know how the person died, where it occurred, and if it was a murder, who did it and what motivated them to do so. Criminal forensic psychologist Paul G. Mattiuzzi talks about this concept in his article, saying, “In the real world, there is in fact a practical duty we share in understanding the means and the motivations for crime.  Understanding is necessary for prediction, prevention and protection. But the popular fascination with homicide goes far beyond the practical.  The story lines are a staple of art and literature and a subject for both drama and comedy.  The murder mystery is often most compelling when it abandons reality and is framed in fantasy.” When reading stories about death and murder it is our natural instinct to put ourselves in that position, either the person who was killed, or the person who did the killing. We want to know as much information as we can get our hands on and putting ourselves in those positions allows us to see the different sides. By doing this we begin to think about if faced with a murderer the possibility of escaping or fighting back. Or vice versa think about if you would be capable of committing such a horrendous crime based on the motives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject of death and how frequently it appeared in the newspaper peaked my interest and prompted me to focus my paper on death throughout Alexandria. Although there have been similar topics, I will be looking at death with a more broad perspective. For my query I chose a fairly simple one to run. At first I tried using the query &lt;code&gt;//div[@n=&#39;4&#39;]//div[contains(., &#39;death&#39;)]/head&lt;/code&gt; to try to get a fairly large pool of data from page four of the different issues containing the word death because page four usually contains the telegrams which sometimes contain news of an important person&#39;s death or an interesting death such as murder. It also usually has a few articles on the page which also sometimes contain a story about a death or several deaths, but this resulted in only 48 results which was too few to work with and resulted in such a broad range of items that would be difficult to work with and get the best results possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this failed attempt I settled on a more simple query to ensure that I got a large sample of data to work with. The query I used was &lt;code&gt;//div/p[contains (., &#39;death&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;. This looked in each paragraph within a div and found any item that had the word &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo; inside. It resulted in 953 items from which I took the dates from each time it occurred and made a frequency graph to find which months the most deaths occurred. From this data I came up with this graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From these results we see that the months with the highest death rates are June through September for both the years 1905 and 1906. The highest deaths total was in September 1906 with 68 deaths. This isn&#39;t a huge surprise because there is usually a high birth and death rate during the month of September, even to this day. These results show that this window in time is quite possibly a sick season and the reason for the high amount of deaths could be from an easily contracted and spread illness. There&#39;s a possibility that since this time is around the holiday season that families could be together and there could be tension among relatives that could possibly result in murder, or it is also a high stress time which could cause heart attacks and other natural causes of death. These are just assumptions and the sickness theory is the only trend to be easily identified because death is hard to predict and can be caused by many factors. With this in mind I wanted to find what some of the main causes of death were. To do this I used the same query but instead of death, I put in different words such as &amp;ldquo;Murder&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Stabbed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Shot&amp;rdquo;. The following pie chart shows these results along with the percentage of deaths caused by each category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fitzpatrick-methods-pie-chart.png&#34; alt=&#34;chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chart shows that the most common form of death was from being shot followed by poison then murder and the plague tying for third. Stabbings and a general sickness each caused only 3% each of the deaths. The low percentage for sickness makes sense because the Bubonic Plague was also a fairly common disease at this time and many of the people who died from being sick were probably caused by the Plague which is a separate category. The remaining sickness I presume was from Typhus because I read several articles where it was mentioned as a cause of death. The high results for murder, the plague, and being shot seems reasonable but the very large 26% for poisoning seems strange and inaccurate. This could be caused by misinformation or that there was a popular advertisement or article that talked about poison and was found in many issues of The  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to keep in mind that the results could be skewed due to a lack of updating each issue. There could be duplicates of stories, or if there was a popular advertisement that appeared often it could tamper with the results and cause an unusually large pool of false information. The contents of the  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; are continually updating, so there is a portion of important information that is missing that could help clear up any uncertainties and offer a wider data set to compare trends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plague in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-medina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-medina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;medina-plague.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Plague Epidemic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; delves into detail about the plague and its various forms. The cattle and bubonic plague both created epidemics in Egypt especially from 1905 through 1907. The spread of the bubonic plague swept through Egypt during the early 1900s. Regions across the nation including districts of farms, small towns, hubs, and port cities were all infected by the mass illness. The epidemic did not only hurt the well-being of residents of Egypt, but it resulted in a change in agriculture, markets, the economy, and the habits of everyday life for the residents of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gathering-data&#34;&gt;Gathering Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frequent articles under the “Local and General” section prompted me to discuss and analyze the different plagues in Egypt and how they correlate, if a correlation does exist. I began this analysis by first narrowing down the searches of the plague into a reasonable number of returns to search through. The query I used, &lt;code&gt;//div[@element=&amp;quot;local&amp;quot;]/div[contains(.,&amp;quot;plague&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;, searched through the Local and General section of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; for the keyword “plague”. This search came up with 133 results. I then organized these searches into three categories based on the most frequent words that came before the plague using the regular expression search of “\w+ plague”. The most frequent words used before the plague were the words “the”, “bubonic”, and “cattle” along with other variations of words that can be found in this word cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;medina-word-cloud.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Plague search word cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While searching through the variations of word combinations with the plague, I noticed many of the results came from the same articles that used the word “plague” multiple times. Therefore, I changed my xpath query to &lt;code&gt;//div[@element=&amp;quot;local&amp;quot;]/div[contains(.,&amp;quot;plague&amp;quot;)]/head&lt;/code&gt; to search only in the headings of the “Local and General” section. This search resulted in 47 queries with 31 results being “the plague”, 9 results being “cattle plague”, and 7 results being “bubonic plague”. From these headings, I was able to get a better understanding of the frequencies and dates of both plagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bubonic plague epidemic began in the early 1900s with a sweeping illness that resulted in 843 cases of the plague in 1904 and 501 deaths as a result. Throughout Egypt, methods of preventing the plague and its spread began to arise to prevent further fatalities and sicknesses that occurred as a result of the plague. The most prominent reason why the plague was being so quickly and widely spread was because of the strong trading business that occurred in Egypt during the early 1900s. Top locations that showed the highest fatality and contractions of the bubonic plague typically incorporated port cities of Egypt and large hubs. Alexandria, Suez, and Port Said were some of the main cities that had the highest records of the bubonic plague in Egypt. As a result, beginning in 1905, cases of the bubonic plague struck Egypt and its citizens through contractions from other nations. The bubonic plague became a record-breaking epidemic in Egypt. The average rate of contracted illnesses that were a result of the plague was approximately 7 per week and approximately 4 deaths per week from the plague. Nations and regions including India and Upper Egypt have spread the disease through merchants and traded goods between the two locations. As distinguished by Sir H. Pinching and Dr. Cresswell the “infection conveyed …. had been infected themselves by goods coming from India or Upper Egypt”. Through the use and distribution of these goods the plague impacted many civilians such as one case in January of 1905 that caused the illness of fifteen people and three deaths caused by the bubonic plague. This resulted in a search and cleaning of multiple ships and shipments that may have been affected by the plague. Many ships were seized if they were found to have traces of the plague and taken into quarantine. The search and seizure of many ships that had goods that were impacted the plague also resulted in different maritime procedures and a delay in times for the passages of ships – resulting in delayed voyages and arrival of traded goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the bubonic plague, another form of plague quickly spread across Egypt as well. The cattle plague came across Egypt from Sudan and infected the cattle of Egypt and the produce market as well. The outbreak first came across Sudan and then impacted Egypt through imports from Sudan. The epidemic only affects cattle and cows directly and causes the death of these animals in large quantities. However, the cattle plague does affect humans indirectly also. The lack of cows leads to a lack of products that result from cattle causing a shift in the Egypt economy, market, and dietary habits of the people of Egypt. The cattle plague also affects the residents of Egypt since the consumption of milk and other products that originate from cattle may result in illnesses to the individual who has digested it. Although the cattle plague was still a significant epidemic in Egypt, it did not affect as many humans as the bubonic plague did. In two articles of the “ &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;” that discussed the cattle plague, readers can analyze how long the cattle plague was a significant epidemic in Egypt and surrounding regions. Articles from January of 1905 indicate that the cattle plague began in late 1903 and continued severely through the middle of 1905. Although, the cattle plague lasted until 1906 with scarce and spaced out incidences of cattle plague diagnoses. In 1904, 5,065 deaths in January were recorded as a result of the cattle plague. In 1905, the total cases reported in January of the cattle plague were 146,791. However, in 1905 measures to end the cattle plague began which resulted in less cases being reported and less fatalities as a result of the cattle plague. One measure taken in order to end the plague was having the cattle being treated with vaccinations to immune them from the illness. In the same time period in 1905, 884 animals were treated with the vaccine. The treatment of animals to prevent the cattle plague overall worked in certain regions in Egypt. In 1906, the cases per week shifted from hundreds of reported diagnoses into an average of 3 per week in May. However, as certain regions became clear of the epidemic, other regions began to break out in the epidemic if the government did not choose to prevent the plague before it arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both the bubonic and cattle plague, the peak season for cases was during the summer months of 1905. The two peaks for each type of the plague were in July. However, the bubonic and cattle plague have no direct correlation to each other as represented by the data from the reports of the  &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. The graph depicted below shows the correlation between the bubonic and cattle plague in Egypt and how they have similarities in ranges but no direct correlation. If there were a direct correlation, the peaks of both lines in the graphs would have been more in sync that they currently appear to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;medina-correlation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Correlation between Bubonic and Cattle Plague Graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of the plague in Egypt through the articles of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was useful since it offered a direct source of the plague and its effects of the people of Egypt. However, varying sources of information from a different lens would have also been useful in addition to the newspaper. Since the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; typically holds the lens of a journalist to inform readers, other point of views that could have been vital to an analysis of the plague of Egypt could have been those found in a medical examination or historical research paper. Additionally, because this is a form of micro-history dating back to a century ago, some data may have misprinted or lost while creating the microforms of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Such information may have improved my analysis since there are months without updates of the plague that may have skewed results found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chabad.org/library/article_cdo/aid/1653/jewish/The-Ten-Plagues.htm&#34;&gt;The Ten Plagues &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4506964/&#34;&gt;Plague in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ccsenet.org/journal/index.php/ach/article/view/23836&#34;&gt;Plagues, Epidemics, and their Social and Economic Impact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theatre</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-castro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-castro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/templates/#calendar-of-coming-events&#34;&gt;Calendar of Coming Events&lt;/a&gt;, Alexandria had many events listed and lined up from Monday to Saturday. Typically, these events consist of many different activities including people going to the theatre, listening to the orchestra, or dressing up to attend glamorous galas. I noticed that in the Coming of Events Calendar there were many reoccurring theatre names. I decided to research the different types, and the most reoccurring theatres in Alexandria between 1905-1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to locate the different types of theatres within Alexandria, I ran an XPath query searching in element of the Coming of Events element. I received about a little more than hundred. I also used the regular expression to search anything with the word theatre within the template. In my original XPath I searched through the whole content file, but I realized that I did not have it updated. This caused my search to include the element tag instead. As a result, I had to update my content folder and then began my XPath search again. I received a little less than my original XPath search, but I copied my work and placed it into an atom document. I also used regular expression to be more specific with my search and took at all the mentions of theatre within the Calendar of Events. My XPath query result then was the following: &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=&amp;quot;comingEvents&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; with regular expression &lt;code&gt;\w+ theatre&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in atom, I deleted everything that was not labeled or named theatre. I realized that there were a couple of misspellings and I corrected them. Overall, nine theatres were constantly contracted and used for different events. These theatres including the following: Esbekieh, Eden, Theatre des Nouveautes, Alhambra, Esbekieh Garden, San Stefano, Zizina, and Abbas. Based on the four most mentioned theatres in Alexandria, I decided to do another XPath search. I wanted to understand the different importances of these reoccurring theatres, and I began to research the number one theatre, the Esbekieh Garden theatre. Then, I continued my search by exercising multiple Xpath searches by using the Calendar of Coming Events tag and placing the specific name of each theatre from my original search. Although it was difficult because the Calendar of Coming Events has a specific template, I excluded the items that did not have a description following. However, I did keep the theatres which had the type performance such as Italian comedy or French comedy. Initially, I only had a couple of theatres under the year 1905, but after searching through each individual theatre more results were gathered for that year. As I gathered my results in a tableu worksheet, I discovered that most shows were seasonal. Most of the theatres occurred during the fall beginning in August and ending in January or February. My data ranged from the year 1905 to 1907, but the majority of my results were within the first two years possibly because most of the class encoded their issues from 1905 and 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the novel &lt;em&gt;Egypt and How to See it&lt;/em&gt; written by Lamplough, the Ezbekieh Gardens was a small threatre, where during small intervals of time small French plays performed for the Egyptian people. The author also recognized another one of the reoccurring theatres in my XPath query search named the Abbas Theatre. It is clear that Egypt held a vast majority of culture such as French and Islam. These types of evidence can be seen throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;; for example, the &lt;em&gt;Notes de Critique&lt;/em&gt;, which are often written in French. However, in the Abbas Theatre, they shared many different cultures, as well. According to Lamplough&#39;s novel, the Abbas Theatre held many Italian opera, grand, and light, and French opera. It is stated that these French and Italian operas were very successful and held nearly twelve hundred people, and the author even mentioned that the seats were quite comfortable adding to the Abbas Theatre&#39;s attraction. This is understandable because Egypt did not have particular demographic. In fact, during the 20th century, the population of Egypt included Jewish, Islamic, and other races and cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reviewing all the different types of theatres, it appeared that most of them held different types of appeals either comedy or drama. Additionally, according to the essay &amp;ldquo;Theatre in Egypt Before and After the Revolution,&amp;rdquo; Egypt transformed due to the rise of independent theatre at the beginning of 1990s. As a result, my XPath search indicated that within the first couple of years of the 20th century the threatres in Egypt were very prominent. Furthermore, the author of the article Joseph Fahim states that the &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; theatre we know today had its roots in the folk traditions and streets of Egypt. In fact, the theatre began to boom in the 20th century when Egypt became the cultural hub of the Middle East. I can tell from the articles that Egypt and its cultural society held an important impact both culturally and socially. This is shocking because many people would not consider Egypt as a cultural prosperity because Egypt is often recognized during the Roman Era and Cleopatra&#39;s reign. Egypt in any other light including as the central attraction of the Middle East and hub for culture and entertainment in the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued my search towards other theatres and it appeared that the Zizinia Theater held more activities than any other theatre. I began another XPath search for only the word Zizina Theatre with the Calendar of Coming Events and many different types of activities occurred during the month of October such as benefits during 1905 and 1906; for example, including Money Benefit for the Jewish Hospital and El Owa el Woska Benefit Performance. According to my research and data, the theatres were scheduled between the months of October to February possibly due to benefits and other seasonal events. I decided to further investigate the Zizinia theatre and these types of benefit events. According to the article written by the Free Popular University in Egypt, on Sunday 26 May 1901 this particular university was declared officially opened at the Theatre Zizinia in Alexandria, thus, making it one of the most frequent and common theatres in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, according to the biography &lt;em&gt;Omar Toussoun: Prince of Alexandria&lt;/em&gt; by Sahar Hamouda, El Owa el Woska was an Islamic Benevolent Society. Therefore, the Zizinia theatre became an important part of the Prince of Alexandria&#39;s social and charity work. The article demonstrated that the theatres in Egypt, especially the Zizinia Theatre, were a great source of revenue and social axis. It is evident the Prince of Alexandria supported the arts and theatres which, in turn, created a source of income for Egypt. The introduction of the famous and royal citizens using the theatre must have greatly contributed to constant appearance in the Calendar of Events and, overall, increased the popularity of the theatre to the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the article also stated that events at the Zizinia Theatre often occurred during the start of the year and during spring around April. This supported my data visualization because most of the theatres within Alexandria were in production from October to April including the Zizinia Theatre. It appeared that these were the times when most of the benefit performances and holiday performances occurred, thus causing most of the theatre events to be circled around winter through spring. For example, the Prince of Alexandria, Omar Toussoun, placed many of his benefit performances during the months of spring such as April. Additionally, the theatres had other specific genres such as comedy or drama. Throughout my search, I discovered that most of threatre, when not hosting charity events or galas, held either Italian or French comedies and dramas. According to the &amp;ldquo;Ideology and Culture of Power in Late Ottoman Egypt&amp;rdquo; by Adam Mestyan, the Egyptian culture included theatres of different language and events such as the French and Italian operas which were quite common during the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the theatres within Alexandria and Cairo became an important factor for Egypt. I was surprised to realize Egypt was the center hub for many cross cultural and artistic events. It is evident that the theatre was an important development for Egypt for economic reasons, but it was also important culturally because it created the foundation for the &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; theatre seen today. The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is a great source to analyze and discover the different types of cultures and social relations within the people of Egypt during the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding and Funeral Flowers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-ell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-ell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see similarities between funerals and the type of arrangements mentioned in the articles. I took notice of the date these weddings were happening, and if orange blossoms were used. I did research that showed during the 1900s orange blossoms and myrtle flowers were very popular in royal weddings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topic&#34;&gt;Topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through issues of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I found many features about weddings and funerals. I was interested to see if trends were popular during certain seasons during 1905 and 1906. Having a wedding announcement in the newspapers may also require a position of authority. I became interested in the trends that may also carry over to weddings outside of the Alexandria and Cairo area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;importance&#34;&gt;Importance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finding information about &lt;em&gt;Queen Victoria’s&lt;/em&gt; wedding in the mid-1800s, showed that she had a crown of orange blossoms, which started a trend into the 1900s. Royal weddings are always of interest to people reading in multiple different countries. I also found information about orange blossoms and their role into Chinese wedding celebrations. “There are few trees so prolific as the orange; it is one of the rare that blooms and bears fruit at the same time, thus becoming symbolic of fruitfulness. During the Crusades, the custom was brought from the East first to Spain, then to France, then to England in the early 1800s.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Victoriana.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interested&#34;&gt;Interested&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wedding have always been of interest to me because they are such a happy celebration. Flowers are also one of my favorite things, I love to look at them and help my mom with the garden at home. In present times flowers are a focal point for weddings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;x-path&#34;&gt;X-path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by looking through the entire repository with the keywords &lt;em&gt;“wedding”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;“flowers”&lt;/em&gt;. However, these findings weren’t the most focused or helpful. I then tried using &lt;em&gt;“marriage”&lt;/em&gt; and was able to find more articles with descriptions of the wedding ceremonies. Upon talking to Professor Hanley, we decided to also look for funeral information. I then searched for &lt;em&gt;“funerals”&lt;/em&gt; and looked through the articles for flower arrangements. Once I found specific articles I was planning to use, I also searched for &lt;em&gt;“orange blossoms”&lt;/em&gt; to see what results came back and see if they corresponded to articles I had already found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While doing x-path queries it was fairly simple as far as finding articles, and then narrowing down my results. When first using the term &lt;em&gt;“marriage”&lt;/em&gt; there are over six hundred results, however upon looking through them it is easy to see they don’t fit the article type I need. Some of these articles simply talk about advertising for marriages, deaths or illnesses, and other simply say that a marriage occurred. Using &lt;em&gt;“wedding”&lt;/em&gt; narrowed the result to one hundred and forty-three articles, which offers a lot better descriptions on the ceremony and decorations. “Orange Blossoms” brought back ten results that were the most helpful in this analysis project. On the opposite side, &lt;em&gt;“funeral”&lt;/em&gt; brought up a fair amount of results, two hundred twenty-four, which had a mix of good and bad articles. Again, some simply talked about funeral advertisement space, and others gave information about services. The search that gave the most confusing results, was &lt;em&gt;“flowers”&lt;/em&gt; this is such a common word that it comes up in battles, market shops, and as names. I decided to specifically look at orange blossoms instead of the generic flower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resultsdifficulty&#34;&gt;Results/Difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found over one hundred results for both weddings and funerals. Some of these instances had the flowers specifically named or how they were arranged, but the majority didn’t mention either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ell-flower-word.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;word cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was not any direct correlations between the date of the weddings and if they had orange blossoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quotes&#34;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“One remarkably consistent usage was the symbolic meaning of “Chastity” attached to orange blossoms. Queen Victoria elected to wear orange blossom- her only floral adornment- at her marriage to Prince Albert on 10 February 1840.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; -&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.royalcollection.org.uk/collection/65305/headdress-from-the-orange-blossom-parure&#34;&gt;https://www.royalcollection.org.uk/collection/65305/headdress-from-the-orange-blossom-parure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Orange Blossoms are also popular in other countries around the same time. Garlands and crowns were used in Greek weddings, that included olive branches and herbs, as well as white flowers and orange blossoms, which stood for sweetness and happiness.  Rome couples followed a similar custom to Greek wedding flowers, weaving greenery and blooms into garlands and crowns, scented with orange blossom, roses, thyme and basil which wards off evil and&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; -&lt;a href=&#34;https://weddings.lovetoknow.com/wiki/History_of_Wedding_Flowers&#34;&gt;https://weddings.lovetoknow.com/wiki/History_of_Wedding_Flowers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication is the way</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-pierre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-pierre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research topic is communication and travel in Alexandria/ Cairo, through means of Telegraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div//head[contains(.,&amp;quot;EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO. LTD.&amp;quot;)]//following-sibling::table[contains(.,&amp;quot;FROM&amp;quot;)]//following-sibling::cell[1]//string()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Code was used to acquire the information analyzed and assessed in the paper. It reads every cell after the first cell of a table containing “FROM,” within a headline that contains “EASTERN TELEGRAPH CO. LTD.” Inside of each division of all the pages of every file inside of the content folder of the repository from the course website. The data is given in a form containing the date and desired data of the pages assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pierre-Figure1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Table&#34;&gt;
Figure 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pierre-Figure2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Table&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pierre-Figure3.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Table&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pierre-Figure4.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Table&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this research is to analyze records of messages - asked by the people whom inhabited the area - to be sent to Glasgow, Manchester, Liverpool, and London. The information will be displayed in various forms throughout the paper and will be analyzed in relation to events occurring around the time, more so understanding the actions that would have occurred in Alexandria/ Cairo from 1905 to 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 1905 time, the British Occupation Army began to become more so relaxed in Alexandria causing the citizens to feel slightly lied to as they continued to show their authority over the people of Egypt by making decisions regarding their land and relationships. The data collected showed two areas that sent the messages to the other areas of the world. The first location was referred to as “The Company’s Office H.M.” The slight variation regarding period of time for messages sent from this group likely means that it had been used by more private companies/ industries. The other location was “The Postal Telegraph Office H.M.” A company that seemed to send messages from the citizens of Alexandria as well as the British Occupation Army Soldiers and Officials. Each of the locations seemed to be used by different members of the area due to the different amounts of time that it would take for each to send messages to the cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Records of Telecommunication during 1905 seemed to be healthy, likely being used by some citizens and soldiers – whom knew people in Glasgow, Manchester, Liverpool, and London. A similar period of time for messages had been sent during that year in relation to other years. Though, the times were different for each year’s month, the same areas received the fastest messages. The country of London has been observed to have the most messages being sent in every month of every year (other than February 1907). This large period of time for messages recorded information being sent to a city shows the population of the army, which would have likely lived in the differing locations with the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaders of the British Army in Egypt and the soldiers they were with during the time would do messages sent to London. Many messages were likely sent in the years during which the Egyptians would have noticed they were not going to leave peacefully without being confronted about the problem. As stated by Stephan Luscombe, “as the Suez Canal continued to grow in importance… the conviction grew that the British had no intention of leaving.” This seems to be rather true in relation to the plans made with France, causing the Northern area of Africa to be Great Britain’s Share and the lack of Egyptian members of the parts of the government, which made important decisions for Egypt and its people. The “temporary” guests from a foreign land were already sowing the seeds of anger in the land of Egypt. The action resembles someone asking to stay in your home, but then sleeping with your husband/ wife. Their actions were clear, to establish complete control over Egypt’s government then its people; the next event which occurred showed this to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While assessing the data, the highest amount of time for messages were sent to each of the areas directly before and after June 1906. The month seemed to be the period of great unrest and interest for the people of Cairo. After assessing the information, I began to perform some research on the time. The day of June 12, 1906 (Figure 1) was the day of the Denshawai, soldier incident; there have been several iterations of the story told about the event since the time of its occurrence. A general summation would be some soldiers came back from the hunting pigeons and met a crowd of citizens who needed the birds for food, there was a fight and then a woman had been shot by a soldier causing the citizens to become more upset and on soldier was injured and left the group of soldiers. He later died due to exposure from the sun during his attempt to return to the camping ground, he was found next to a citizen whom had been attempting to help him. The man was thought to have killed him and was beaten by another group of soldiers, fifty other members from the group of citizens were then judged and had received punishments for their acts. Two people were sent to death and the others were given prison time and 50 whips. The actions, which occurred toward the people in the town were not just or fair, they were the way the colony controlled many of the areas they inhabit. As the views and thoughts on the Denshawai incident varied the manner of which it had been told to other people also varied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the event messages sent from the two locations in Alexandria to the cities in Europe were done so at more similar speeds for both postal areas but still not the same. Though, the citizens would still be able to send messages, they would likely. The assumption is that the soldiers from London going on their month-long breaks then returning to the area two months before the event; continuing their communication with their friends and family after they returned. This would be shown in the large increase of the times of messages recorded and sent during April and May 1906(Figure 1). During June the amount of time for message’s speed increased to a time that was rather distinct from the other points, this had been likely due to the imposition of the soldiers on the people. After the Denshawai incident the citizens were highly upset with the British Army and the ways that the event was handled, along with the strange manner of the punishments to the people who were considered innocent. As expected for the two months following the events of the Denshawai Incident, the amount of time taken for messages sent out to other areas had increased and had been the largest amount of time taken for messages during the three-year period. This was most likely due to the British leaders sending messages to their officials about the event, soldiers speaking with their friends and families, and the Egyptians whom desired as many people to know of the British forces’ acts against their people. As well as the amount of pressure put onto the telegraphs that would not have really been done in the year before. The British may have also given the citizens slower telegraphs on purpose to be able to give the citizens in Glasgow, Manchester, Liverpool and London their views on events before everyone else, first impressions are everything…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though after the incident, there was likely less use of the areas to send messages due to the punishments the government had been giving some of the citizens who spoke of it in journals. The amount of time taken for messages sent to Glasgow, Liverpool, Manchester, and London during the rest of the year and during 1907 had been the least during the years. The reason may have been the lack of events that occurred in the area causing soldiers to send messages to their friends and families. Many of the citizens would no longer have a need to send information to the areas within Europe after the time. Though, the cause of the decrease may relate to the Nationalist groups that had been created, and the soldiers whom were likely told to arrest any members they might have been found committing any acts against the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of data had been sufficient in determining the changes in the times needed for messages to be sent to the assessed locations from Alexandria/ Cairo. Though, if the research were to be continued on the topic the manner of collection would need to be improved. To attain the data a program had been made which analyzed data in an excel document and converted it into a format that could be converted into a chart. The current data being added onto could be done so with more efficiency by utilizing a general text editor to organize the information that would forma it in the correct manner to be converted into a chart. Attaining more information on the actions of the British Occupation Army such as the times they returned and the thoughts of the soldiers in relating t the incident and the way that it had been treated. Though, the messages had been sent it was rather difficult to attain one that would have kept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was attempted by the current researcher but was not able to be performed due to technological miscommunication of information of different systems (Mac and Windows). To improve the presentation of the information in a visual context different forms of the time presented could be used, as the other styles would cause the information of the graph to be too large to quickly observe.  Along with this the use of the map feature would aid in providing a vivid example of the data in relation to the areas in the United Kingdom. Also assessing the units would aid in conserving time and increasing understanding of the information analyzed. Along with assessing data as true by association of similar information, though the actuality of the events may be properly represented in the data. Although as time, years, increases the performances and speed of the devices would likely increase causing the amount of time to decrease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luscombe, S. (n.d.). Egypt and the British Empire. Retrieved April 02, 2018, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in Colonial Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-wallace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-wallace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-brainstorm&#34;&gt;The Brainstorm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world in the twenty first century is one that is connected, by the internet, but also by the seas. As Michael B. Miller said in his book, Europe and the Maritime World: A Twentieth Century History, that “commercial maritime world helped to shape the modern world’s organization of consumption and production”. The topic of how shipping works and how it affected the world then is in reality, a study of how our world has came to be. The world economy is driven in part by the movement of goods across large bodies of water. The twentieth century was no different as this is when shipping people and goods became something that a middle class person could do. As someone with a minor in geography, how people interact with others on a global scale is of great interest to me. When I learned we would be doing a project such as this in the class I knew I wanted to do something with the globalization of trade. This is the era of the steamship, as shown by the plethora of ads showing off the prices of travel. The steamship revolutionized global trade as it opened up new trade routes that were previously unavailable due to wind patterns. As it is quite obvious how important these steamers are, that raises new questions. Where are these ships going and when? What is on these ships, people or cargo, or both? Did the proportion of ships with humans versus cargo change throughout the years? What about the overall volume of ships going back and forth, did that change? These questions are the ones that this analysis seeks to answer. This is a history class, in part at least, and this microhistory blends well into the overall fabric of industrialization of the twentieth century. Each ship makes up a tiny story in the sea of history (pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-information&#34;&gt;Background Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get this raw data in the first place, my fellow classmates had to use Microfilm which possessed the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; on it. We all collectively have scanned this newspaper using microfilm machines, specifically the ScanPro 2000. A very tedious process begun after scanning this pages, because it was necessary to split the page into fourths in order to get better image quality. You then had to stitch up these fourths into one image again so that you could finally OCR (program that allows you to scan an image and convert it into text). This is the graft that a microhistorian has to do in order to get the historical information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;serial-question&#34;&gt;Serial Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the questions listed above are relatively specific, considering the scope of the source material. This topic though can be pulled back a bit to find something that can be applied more generally. My goal is to learn how shipping from and to Egypt changed over the three year period in which the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is available for research. Unfortunately the findings of this study can&#39;t be too intensely generalized to the shipping world in general because of the scope of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. In light of all of this, I arrived at the question of “What is the usage and frequency change in shipping in 1905-1097 Egypt as represented by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xpath-query&#34;&gt;XPATH Query&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to search the full contents of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, a Xpath query had to be formulated. This allowed the total contents of the newspaper to be searched in its entirety from 1905 to 1907. This XML search needs two things to be successful, a where and what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; was relatively easy, find anything to do with ships right? No, because that gets every ad and listing in the paper, which there are many. The search needed to be refined, so the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; changed to &amp;ldquo;shipping&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;ship&amp;rdquo;. This still wasn&#39;t good enough to be used in any substantial way. Finally the solution was found, the xml id for a section of the paper called &amp;ldquo;shipping movements&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;where&#34;&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The xml id of shipping movements made the where easy, I just then needed to get the content out of the division. This was done by searching for every paragraph inside of the feature &amp;ldquo;shipping movements&amp;rdquo; by using the query of &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=&amp;quot;steamerMovements&amp;quot;]//p&lt;/code&gt;. I collected the data after updating the working sets to the most current pages. This was done on Wednesday, March 28th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of the sections that were pulled for research were OCR&#39;d correctly so they had to be either corrected by hand if they could be figured out what they were supposed to say, or they had to be deleted if they were too poor to even guess. Often times place names, one of the essential parts of the question, were incomplete or misspelled. There would be awkward spacing or formatting issues, as well as sometimes where the section would be the same for a couple days, showing that a person most likely copy and pasted the same template from either their own issue or from someone else for several days and didn&#39;t bother to change the values and content to reflect what the their specific issue said. There is a big possibility for missing out on many instances of the section if people don&#39;t use the xml id, as this is the hinge that holds this search together. The actual extracting of the data from the sentences were no easy feat either. Regular expressions were able to help but copious amounts of effort was put into getting the data by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Xpath query, there were 698 instances where the xml id for &amp;ldquo;shipping movements&amp;rdquo; were used. Each paragraph contains a listing of the name of the ship, usually the company, where its going/when its getting to Egypt, the date of arrival, and what they had on board the ship either people, cargo, or both. Sometimes the ship will list some specifics of what cargo they were carrying, listing the amount with its unit measurement ex. (1000 bales cotton).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;visualization&#34;&gt;Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to better visualize the data, a word cloud was created in order to display the frequency of destination to and from Egypt. The bigger the word, the more often it occurred in the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wallace-world-cloud-v2.png&#34; alt=&#34;world cloud v2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, looking at the hard data, the top ten is as follows, with number of occurrences provided,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;292	Malta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;273	Alexandria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;207	Liverpool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;85	Manchester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;74	Marseilles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;49	Antwerp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very interesting results on their own, but they will eventually contribute to a overall patch work of the wider question. One peculiar thing to come out of this search is the fact that Malta seems to be the top destination for ships to and from Egypt. Looking at bit deeper creates some doubt to the validity of this finding. Malta was very small with a tiny permanent population of people, how could they be the biggest trading partner for one of the biggest colonies of the British Empire? Looking even deeper into the actual text of the newspaper, often times the listings include that the ship will be going somewhere via Malta, probably due to its location in the Mediterranean. Malta is a good stopping point to restock and get ready for the second leg of their journey. Alexandria comes next in the list, most likely because that was the principle port for the Egyptian colony, even shipping to other parts of Egypt. The first real destination listed is Liverpool, this isn’t too surprising as it was one of the busiest shipping ports in the United Kingdom. Manchester is next on the list, as one of the first industrialized cities in the world, it possessed the need for raw cargo. This shipping route from Egypt helped supply this demand, and via the Liverpool and Manchester Railway, the two cities were incredibly connected economically as well as physically. In order to get a picture of the entire scale of this shipping operation, a map was created using the coordinates of each city to plot them geographically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wallace-Map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Map&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Note: In the newspaper, all ports in the USA were listed as “American Ports”. The coordinates of Boston were used to represent all of these American Ports.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is three general regions to categorize the places in which these steamers were headed. The Mediterranean region,  the British Isles region, and the Far Reaches region. The first two are self explanatory, while the Far Reaches are used to categorize the ports in Australia and the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steamers carried lots of things to and fro, but three main categories emerged in the newspaper, passengers, mails, and cargo. The cargo is further broken down into the types that were shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wallace-ShippingCargoBarYear.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shipping Cargo Bar Year&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Note: The onions, cotton, timber, and coal are all part of the overall category of cargo, so they are included in the total number on the bar graph above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo was the clear winner as one would expect, while passengers are second, followed by mails. Cotton was the most common type of cargo with coal coming after. This graph however does not allow for comparison over time because of the lack of data in 1906 to a degree and especially 1907. Smaller intervals of time have to be used to compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wallace-ShippingCargoQuarter.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shipping Cargo Bar Quarters&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph shows that there is a pretty constant level across all three categories until you reach the third quarter where there is a jump in mails while passengers and cargo rise but not to the same degree. This makes sense as the third quarter is the ending of the summer months and the fall, a time of year where many crops were harvested. Cotton is a good example of this, as it rises significantly in the fourth quarter. After all the harvesting and processing were done, they were able to be shipped out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wallace-ShippingPlacesBarMonth.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shipping Places Bar Months&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to look at the change in place over time, a bar graph was made, plotting by month. The findings of this graph make sense with the other evidence that’s been presented so far. The summer months have a lull as people left Egypt to escape the summer as well as a lack of significant crops to be harvested during the summer months. The fall and early winter months have a flurry of activity of cargo shipping and people coming back after the hot summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In asking the question about shipping, valuable trinkets of information can be gleaned from the data. The main port cities that Egyptian steamers shipped to and from like Liverpool, Manchester, London, Marseilles, Mersina, etc. This reinforces the current ideas about British shipping, using it mostly for self production but then also selling goods on the world stage. As for the change in cargo specifically, we are able to track not only when the Nile floods but also when summer is by deriving patterns. The Nile flooded during the summer and cotton was planted, and then harvested in the fall/winter months. Passengers rose and fell with the coming and going of the summer months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, this data turns out to be basically what you would expect. This window into the past was very enlightening and I’m glad I had the opportunity to conduct microhistorical research. I would hope however that a student down the line can polish up my data and go further once 1906 is complete and 1907 has some meaningful data. My methodology was strong but the lack of substantial data over a longer period hindered my results. The biggest hurdle was trying to extract the data that was needed out from the sentences, and the next scholar to try and tackle this question, I implore you to find a better pattern than I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael B. Miller, &lt;em&gt;Europe and the Maritime World: A Twentieth Century History&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotels in Cairo</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-chapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-chapple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-hotels-were-visited-the-most-in-cairo-egypt&#34;&gt;What hotels were visited the most in Cairo Egypt?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;chapple-map-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hotels in Cairo between 1905-1906&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/@30.0302842,31.1812774,13z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!6m1!1s1DunCjoyI8KrRBpKhOk1C7EDsJijzv3J3&#34;&gt;Link to live map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-and-cultural&#34;&gt;Social and Cultural&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my results, I was able to find that in the summer months the amount of visitors visiting the hotels increased. In Egypt tourism became a vital part of the Egyptian economy after the construction of the Suez Canal had been completed. The hotels included in my results are all along the Nile River and the opening of the Suez canal made it much easier for people to get in and out of Egypt from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;During the second half of the nineteenth century, a new system had emerged, one that would subsequently be applied to Egypt and Sudan. The new centerpiece of this new structure was the &amp;lsquo;Resort&amp;rsquo;. Resorts were dedicated to tourists&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;querying-results-and-haptics&#34;&gt;Querying Results and Haptics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The query that I used to find the hotels listed in Cairo is Query: &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &amp;quot;Cairo”)]/head&lt;/code&gt; and in text to find I put &amp;ldquo;Hotel&amp;rdquo;. Finding the query that would give me the answers that I wanted took me a long time. I initially asked myself where I would be able to find hotels in Cairo within the Digital Gazette. The answer that I came up was in the advertisements section, Local and General, and the Social sections of the issues. I began by trying to run the query &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; that would give me the titles of all of the hotels within the advertisements section. This was unsuccessful because the query was not answering my question of what the most common hotels in Cairo were. The query that I was running was not specific enough toward the location and gave far too many results to decipher. The next query I began to run was specific, however it was far too specific when trying to answer my questions because it did not give me any results. Many of the queries I tried to run failed because some of the results were in element or feature, which made it hard to find a full set of data. The biggest issue that I ran into was being specific enough to generate a query, but not too specific where I would get a small number of results. After trial and error, I was able to finally retrieve the query Query: &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &amp;quot;Cairo”)]/head&lt;/code&gt; with the text finding the word hotel. This query finds an advertisement that contains the word Cairo in the head and hotel somewhere in the text. This query is not perfect, however it did assist me in answering the question that I posed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The query that I was able to retrieve for the hotels answered my question of what hotels in Cairo existed in Colonial Egypt, however this query still did not give me an accurate representation of the people who attended these hotels. I further had to construe a query that would answer the question of who visited the hotels and when the people visited these hotels. When coming up with a query to answer this question, I discovered the element: &amp;ldquo;visitList&amp;rdquo;. When making a query for visitList, this was difficult because I wanted to make the results specific, yet attainable. I began with the query of Query: &lt;code&gt;//div[@element=&amp;quot;visitList&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;, this query gave me results that stated yes, meaning that that there was a visitList element in the issue. I needed to make the element much more specific. I generated the query &lt;code&gt;//div[@element=&amp;quot;visitList&amp;quot;//persName]&lt;/code&gt;. This did not give me results as it still was not specific enough. I generated results to find persName within the visitList attribute with using regular expression &lt;code&gt;\W\w+ \W\w+&lt;/code&gt;. This regular expression would give me the results for people within the visitList that were tagged with persName. The results for this test came up for me, however many people that coded for the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in XPath did not use this tag. I generated results for only a couple of dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/visitList/Story1?:showVizHome=no&amp;amp;:embed=true&#34;&gt;Visitors in Cairo Egypt in 1905&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strengths that I found with using Xpath and generating results using regular expression were that it was able to find a specific answer for me if I asked it the right question, however if I asked the right question some of the results would not populate if others did not put on their end the same exact XML markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When thinking about a topic such as hotels in Egypt, it is important to find scholarly reviewed text for a more accurate understanding of the topic at hand. I was able to find three articles to assist me in answering the question about tourism and hotels within Cairo.&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/23062746?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=hotel&amp;amp;searchText=colonial&amp;amp;searchText=Egypt&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoAdvancedSearch%3Ff1%3Dall%26amp%3Bf3%3Dall%26amp%3Bq1%3Dcolonial%2BEgypt%2B%26amp%3Bacc%3Don%26amp%3Bed%3D%26amp%3Bsd%3D%26amp%3Bc3%3DAND%26amp%3Bq0%3Dhotel%2B%26amp%3Bgroup%3Dnone%26amp%3Bc6%3DAND%26amp%3Bq2%3D%26amp%3Bf4%3Dall%26amp%3Bc1%3DAND%26amp%3Bf2%3Dall%26amp%3Bf5%3Dall%26amp%3Bf6%3Dall%26amp%3Bf0%3Dall%26amp%3Bq3%3D%26amp%3Bisbn%3D%26amp%3Bq5%3D%26amp%3Bpt%3D%26amp%3Bq6%3D%26amp%3Bc4%3DAND%26amp%3Bc2%3DAND%26amp%3Bq4%3D%26amp%3Bc5%3DAND%26amp%3Bla%3D&amp;amp;refreqid=search%3Adb8b6213b82816d7b3da77e796434632&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;THE THOMAS COOK ARCHIVE FOR THE STUDY OF TOURISM IN NORTH AFRICA AND THE MIDDLE EAST&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
explains how tourism in the Middle East and North Africa took a dramatic incline during the 1880s. The essay details how “Mass tourism is synonymous with the name of Thomas Cook and Son Ltd.” Thomas Cook and Son Ltd. helped pave the way for tourist coming in and out of Egypt after they developed “the Nile transit service while simultaneously opening up Syria/Palestine to travelers.” This information is important because it explains why the hotels included in this visualization were popular during their prime. The visualization depicts five hotels in Cairo, and all but one of these hotels are all situated near the Nile River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another scholarly article that I have used as reference is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/4289940?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=hotel&amp;amp;searchText=colonial&amp;amp;searchText=Egypt&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoAdvancedSearch%3Ff3%3Dall%26amp%3Bf6%3Dall%26amp%3Bc1%3DAND%26amp%3Bed%3D%26amp%3Bq0%3Dhotel%2B%26amp%3Bacc%3Don%26amp%3Bf4%3Dall%26amp%3BcurrentPath%3D%252Faction%252FdoAdvancedSearch%26amp%3Bf2%3Dall%26amp%3Bpage%3D2%26amp%3Bsd%3D%26amp%3BsearchType%3DfacetSearch%26amp%3Bf0%3Dall%26amp%3Bf1%3Dall%26amp%3Bc5%3DAND%26amp%3Bc2%3DAND%26amp%3Bc3%3DAND%26amp%3Bc6%3DAND%26amp%3Bc4%3DAND%26amp%3Bgroup%3Dnone%26amp%3Bf5%3Dall%26amp%3Bq1%3Dcolonial%2BEgypt%2B&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tourism and Empire: The Thomas Cook &amp;amp; Son Enterprise on the Nile, 1868-1914&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This article details how tourism is a widely Western phenomena. &amp;ldquo;A product of the industrial revolution, modern tourism was founded, developed, and perfected in Britain, western Europe, and North America during the second half of the nineteenth century&amp;rdquo;. Tourism in Egypt was a new concept during the early twentieth century. This concept is important to think about and analyze within the Digital Gazette because the citizens of Cairo and neighboring cities like Alexandria were trying to understand tourism as a means to stimulate their economy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
