<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/sophiametallo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/sophiametallo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Digital Egyptian Gazette</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/sophiametallo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stocks and Shares</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-metallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-metallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Expanding on my blog post “Is Egypt In a Bubble?,” I dug through the pages of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and traced the “Stocks and Shares” table throughout 1905 and 1906 with as much data available from 1907 as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This table listed the stock with its stock price as well as its debenture price. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=define+a+share+of+stock&amp;amp;oq=define+a+share&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.2.69i57j0l5.5922j1j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&#34;&gt;stock&lt;/a&gt; is a portion of company ownership that is sold to the public for which the owner of the stock receives a part of said company’s earnings. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?ei=Ky7eWu2DL4WSzwL2_7T4Ag&amp;amp;q=define+a+debenture&amp;amp;oq=define+a+debenture&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..0j0i22i30k1l9.6015.6015.0.6450.1.1.0.0.0.0.114.114.0j1.1.0....0...1.1.64.psy-ab..0.1.112....0.t1UcNE-Mr5I&#34;&gt;debenture&lt;/a&gt;, is similar to a stock, but instead of the value of the stock rising and falling with the company’s wealth, it has a fixed rate of return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this project was to not only compare the stock price and debenture price of any given investment over time but also to compare both a “gilt edged” investment, meaning a strong investment, to one that may have been suffering in the oncoming financial crisis in Egypt at this time period (as explained in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/metallo-is-egypt-in-a-bubble/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What spurred this investigation were the parallels that I was seeing between the Great Recession of 2008 in the US and the articles written about the Egyptian economy in 1907.  It is true that markets are cyclical and have their ups and downs. For the most part, we can see these cyclical trends coming every 10 or so years. This would mean that exactly a decade before the US market 2008, Egypt would have been feeling the sting of an economic crisis similar to that of the one the US experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching for information on the Egyptian market failures of 1907, the Panic of 1907, also called the Knickerbocker Crisis, kept appearing as a result of my searches. The Knickerbocker Crisis was a US Stock market dip that occurred in October of 1907 and the effects of this crash were not limited to the US as explained &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/2141305?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=panic&amp;amp;searchText=of&amp;amp;searchText=1907&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dpanic%2Bof%2B1907&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracing the financial articles throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, and as noted in my blog post, it is clear that Egypt felt their economy failing and very quickly what was a “localized” crisis began to spread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, the crisis was felt abroad, as seen in the article below from the introduction to a quote of a French article. Not only is the crisis officially “raging” in Egypt but is felt all over Europe (which, honestly, has the most to lose seeing as Egypt was still under European rule).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/feeling-the-crisis-abroad-19070619.JPG?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;feeling the crisis abroad 19070619&#34;&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the visualization of the results from tracing the “Stocks and Shares” table in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.  The strong stock that was analyzed was The Agricultural Bank of Egypt and the stock that was supposedly losing traction in the market was the Land Bank of Egypt. This is not unlike what most consider the cause of the US Great Recession of 2008 and many other economic recessions throughout history, speculation, in particular land speculation (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/43189952?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=great&amp;amp;searchText=recession&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3FQuery%3Dgreat%2Brecession%26amp%3Bfilter%3D&#34;&gt;or in 2008 the bundling of blatantly faulty mortgages&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;metallo-sharevdebenture2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;share vs debenture visualization&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this visualization, it is evident, in a loose pattern, that the share and debenture prices seem to mirror each other. It seems, by this visualization, that the Land Bank of Egypt outperformed the Agricultural Bank of Egypt which is the opposite of what is expected given the information found in the financial articles of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. As to why the debenture price of the Land Bank was so much higher in general than the other measure, I cannot say.  This could be due to improper coding of the Gazette or some other underlying force at the time. To speak to the stability of the investments, the only one that seemed to be unwavering was the debenture price of the Agricultural Bank which we would expect from a “gilt edged” security. The share price of the same investment does not stay as steady but is still much more constant than the Land Bank debenture price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Egypt In A Bubble?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-metallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-metallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economies are cyclical. Fact. They will experience ups and downs. Fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the headlines of “Financial Crisis” glaring from the pages of the “Egyptian Gazette”, it is safe to assume that Egypt will be heading for an economical decline. As 1907 progresses, the financial situation in Egypt seems to be falling to great depths, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the May 5, 1907 edition of the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; claims were made that the downturn was only impacting Cairo and Alexandria, it was “only confined to Alexandria and Cairo.” The positivity, as seen in the article below from May 1907, was meant to keep the entire country from panicking, preventing a self-fulfilling prophecy of a complete market collapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;financial-positivity-19070521.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;financial positivity 19070521&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By June of 1907, only one month later, the country began to feel the effects of the crisis spreading further from the localized markets of Cairo and Alexandria. Banks began to suffer, stock prices began to drop, and the country was searching for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image below is a screenshot from June 1907. It is now apparent that something needs to be done to solve the slipping economy.  The Alexandria Stock and Shareholders Association brought it upon themselves to attempt to curb the fall by creating a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?ei=6i7BWsOpLIX3zgLq6auwAQ&amp;amp;q=define+deputation&amp;amp;oq=define+deputation&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..0j0i22i30k1l7.22758.23978.0.24069.10.8.0.0.0.0.226.613.0j1j2.3.0....0...1.1.64.psy-ab..7.3.611...35i39k1j0i10k1j0i22i10i30k1.0.SinQKTgLTj8&#34;&gt;deputation&lt;/a&gt; and appointing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eldon_Gorst&#34;&gt;Sir Eldon Gorst&lt;/a&gt; as their deputy to lead them in their efforts.  Gorst was the controller of taxes and undersecretary of finances in Britain and was sent to Egypt to work along side Egyptian financial officials to fix their inevitable market meltdown.  He was also tasked with promoting native Egyptian responsibility in government positions (this did not happen and he would become hated by the old British rulers in Egypt and distrusted by Egyptain officials).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sir-eldon-gorst.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;sir eldon gorst&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, in the June 19, 1907 issue of the paper, the crisis was felt abroad, as seen in the article below from the introduction to a quote of a French article. Not only is the crisis officially “raging” in Egypt but is felt all over Europe (which, honestly, has the most to lose seeing as Egypt was still under European rule).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;feeling-the-crisis-abroad-19070619.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;feeling the crisis abroad 19070619&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
