<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cairo | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/cairo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/cairo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cairo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Cairo</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/cairo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cairo Police</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-kennethhills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2020-03-10-kennethhills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This story is straight-up the plot of a comedy. The opening line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So much has been said and written about the incompetency of our Cairo police in the local papers,   that it is quite a pleasure to be able to report a really smart capture recently effected by the greatly maligned arm of the law&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story telling in this piece is fantastic and by the end of the story, the person who reported the stolen bank notes refused to compensate the police 10%, so the police decided to hold the money indefinitely. This story appeared in the Local and General section in the July 25th, 1907 edition of the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this story, major conclusions can be drawn about the state of law enforcement in Egypt at the time. The efficiency of the Egyptian Police was greatly hindered by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oxfordislamicstudies.com/article/opr/t125/e409&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitulations&lt;/a&gt;
 imposed on the Ottoman Empire by European powers. These 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capitulations&lt;/a&gt;

exempted foreigners from local laws and thus, the local authorities had to tread carefully around making arrest and upholding the law. This could be the &amp;ldquo;maligned arm of the law&amp;rdquo; referenced earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many instances of the Egyptian police displaying inability to act from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/31110632/_Alexandria_1898_Nodes_Networks_and_Scales_in_Nineteenth-Century_Egypt_and_the_Mediterranean._Comparative_Studies_in_Society_and_History_59-1_January_2017_127_153&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;anarchist&lt;/a&gt;
 or

&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-barrett-donkey-drivers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;obnoxious beggars&lt;/a&gt;
. With the Capitulations being a tool of European imperialism in Egypt, many European foreigners would commit crimes and get away with it due to the layers and layers of paperwork needed to make an arrest. Under the Capitulation System, European life and well being was the primary concerns of the state. This led to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.executedtoday.com/2017/06/28/1906-four-egyptians-for-the-denshawai-incident/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;drastic inequalities&lt;/a&gt;
 in the justice system.  This story is one of many that can be traced back to the societal inequalities posed by European imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggos</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 18th, 1907, Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was released to the public. In this issue of the newspaper, on the fourth page, under the section labeled &amp;ldquo;Letter to the Editor,&amp;rdquo; a person wrote to the editor about his / her referring to Canis Major&amp;rsquo;s recent letter. The letter written by Canis Major is posted in the newspaper above the Letter to the Editor – Police Dog Service. Canis Major’s letter discussed the treatment of dogs when getting closer to death. Major stated that “[he] thinks that the matter should be looked into, and something should be done, to make the life of [the] dogs, during the time they wait for death, less painful for them.” In response to Canis Major’s letter, a “Lover of Animals” commented how a friend of theirs dog suffered from a disease “contracted in the black hole of Boulac.” The animal suffered through death, and the person who responded to Canis Major’s letter wanted to make a statement agreeing with him, that dogs should be treated better in their last days and minutes. Having this section, “Letters to the Editor,” allows the public to develop their thoughts and issues about society to the newspaper. This gives them a chance to speak up. Even though, the newspaper most likely cannot put in submissions that will cause a riot, they still put in some that have a small amount of concern from the people which keeps everything well balanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing another search about dogs, not animals, there were only a few articles that came up about the cruelty in their treatment. While there are other blog posts about different animals and dogs, I saw no record of any with an emphasis on the treatment of dogs during their dying stages. Regarding the SPCA, I ran multiple xpath query’s and all were returned with no results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donkey Drivers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-barrett-donkey-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-barrett-donkey-drivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You see them on the horizon. Look down. Avoid Eye Contact. Do not acknowledge them. Fake a phone call. Start crying. Alas, your effort is futile. Whether you like it or not, the dreaded moment will come where you are clotheslined by an arm trying to get you to buy perfume from their kiosk in the middle of the mall. Turns out, this isn&amp;rsquo;t just a modern day frustration - we&amp;rsquo;ve been suffering worldwide for over 100 years, minimum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although 1905 Cairo didn&amp;rsquo;t have an infestation of pushy perfume salesmen, they did have &amp;ldquo;donkey boys&amp;rdquo;. These guys would call after you, bothering you, insisting you use their donkeys to get to your next location. Our complainer who wrote the correspondent was offended they’d think he’d even consider taking anything but a cab. Donkey boys seem like our kiosk worker on steroids; the only thing that’s stopping the residents of Cairo from hitting them is the fact that there’s a police officer too close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution sought is to get a &lt;em&gt;shawish&lt;/em&gt; (meaning Police or Army Sergeant) to make a law against their badgering solicitation. As the complainer remarks, &amp;ldquo;“No reproof has any effect unless it be to bring a flow of filthy language”&amp;hellip; which might be the most British way to say “cussing them out is all that works!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder In Cairo</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-oulette-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-oulette-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 1905-04-18 Egidio Gerona was ironically murdered upon entering a catholic church in the Mousky. The cause of death came from two bullets fired by a man by the name of Fabio Ninci. Following the incident the murderer was apprehended without resistance outside of the church. The police discovered a few connections between the two men, including their Italian nationality and prior employment. Apparently the murderer had been discharged from the Telephone Company where M. Gerona also worked. The discharge he attributed to M. Gerona, who worked as an electrician the and the murderer sought to avenge himself. In my opinion, the man took his actions way too far, especially over working as a wires-man. With his poor judgment an innocent man was tragically murdered and he put himself away in the central native prison. Two others instances of murder are reported in the paper. First, a Greek band attacked a Bulgarian village, resulting in 15 deaths. The other instance involved the Turks killing 30 Albanians near the town. These reports show  the hectic condition that Macedonia is currently facing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
