<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ABBYY | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/abbyy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/abbyy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ABBYY</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>ABBYY</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/abbyy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCR OCSucks</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-sain-technical-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-sain-technical-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the whole process of learning new word processing and encoding programs was challenging, the most frustrating aspect was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.abbyy.com/en-us/finereader/about-ocr/what-is-ocr/&#34;&gt;OCR&lt;/a&gt;. It is supposed to be a faster way to translate the newspaper pages into plain text, it turned out to take up about as much time as it would have to hand type it all. I felt as if no matter how many times I scanned the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nedcc.org/free-resources/preservation-leaflets/6.-reformatting/6.1-microfilm-and-microfiche&#34;&gt;microfilm&lt;/a&gt; images and changed the focus, brightness, contrast, or zoomed in on the page, it would not run through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.abbyy.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;ABBYY&lt;/a&gt; in the way I was expecting it to. I was hoping to have to make minimal corrections after the scanned images were OCRed, but with all the pages I have done up to this point, I have had to make a minimum of two hours’ worth of corrections per page. The word processing software may read a majority of the words (I would estimate around 85%), I still spent a majority of my time in this class fixing the mistakes the OCR made. I also found the other programs in this class easier to use than ABBYY. Sometimes while editing a word, the image it received it from would disappear, I also found the ordering of the paragraphs challenging at times. Overall, the program may have saved me some time, but another OCR processor may be more efficient, from my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
