<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>curiosities | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/categories/curiosities/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/categories/curiosities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>curiosities</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>curiosities</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/categories/curiosities/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Performance</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-karl-frederickroche/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-karl-frederickroche/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to investigate the music side of the Egyptian Gazette. This is because I found it rather interesting and wanted to see how the people as well as the newspaper itself reacts to musical literature. To my surprise I found that they are much more candid than I would have otherwise expected. When looking at my Monday issue I found an article on a fifth annual musical entertainment scene. They described the pupils there as well as gave the readers insight into some of their hardships as well as how they improved from last year’s performance. Due to this, I can also safely assume that this must be something that regularly occurs since this is the fifth time they have had such an entertainment. As stated, the writer is very candid and explains the downfalls and concerns they had over the performance. For example, the chorus sounded too forced and containing a lack of vibrancy. However, the writer did not only explain shortcomings. He also gave ample credit when he felt it necessary. This happened during a duet for the soprano and tenor which he labeled as “pleasant”, along with a violin solo which he said was given in a manner that was “most commendable”.  It was also stated that this chorus came from Macbeth, which gives me insight into what the Egyptian audience liked to listen to at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading this article, I remember &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pierre/&#34;&gt;the blog post&lt;/a&gt; that I read before this. It is similar to this one, however, it looked at the individual artists and the culture rather than the performance as a whole. Nonetheless, it provided me with very helpful information, such as how the Egyptian musical culture is different from our own. He also found it interesting to see how the writers explain events such as what I noted with how candid they were. It does indeed make someone wonder if that is how the audience felt. Though this will most likely be a question that can’t be answered simply because we cannot go back to that exact time and see for ourselves. Until then, this is all we have to go off of and we must take it as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sultan&#39;s Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the month of September issues of the Egyptian Gazette, the newspaper talks about the Sultan&#39;s illness. Specifically, in page three of the September 21st issue of 1906, the Sultan is mentioned and the author says he has Bright&#39;s disease. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bright%27s_disease&#34;&gt;This disease was named after Richard Bright, a physician.&lt;/a&gt; It was a disease pertaining to the kidney, but was later discovered to be a classification of a variety of kidney diseases that were unknown at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kidney.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brights-Disease&#34; title=&#34;A kidney with Bright&#39;s Disease&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A patient with this disease could experience swelling, convulsions, blindness, and coma. A lot of patients with this disease may have also had high blood pressure, heart disease, or diabetes. The newspaper mentions Dr. Nafiz, and Dr. Noureddin Pasha as the primary physicians of the Sultan, but it mentions that they had to consult Professor Bergmann for assistance. Bergmann was the one to diagnose the Sultan with Bright&#39;s disease, and ordered an immediate surgical operation. He also says that he is suffering from &amp;quot;other complications,&amp;quot; which may be anything from diabetes to heart disease to kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160915235645/https:/www.guideline.gov/summaries/summary/36900&#34;&gt;Today, a patient with the same symptoms would be likely diagnosed with chronic nephritis, which is an inflammation of the kidney.&lt;/a&gt; However, in the Thursday issue, it is mentioned that the Sultan was suffering from a stone. This means that he may have had a urinary tract infection. The most common cause of a UTI is  Escherichia coli, or similar fungi. Other causes may include genetic predisposition or being uncircumcised. What exactly caused the Sultan to be ill is unknown, however, the diagnosis at the time was based on similar cases. Richard Bright attributed the disease to high blood pressure and diabetes, which could have been true in the Sultan&#39;s case, as he mourned the recent death of two high functionaries, one of which &amp;quot;enjoyed his majesty&#39;s confidence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Look Into The History of Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-tryfontheophilopoulos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-tryfontheophilopoulos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills were originally advertised as &amp;ldquo;miracle pills&amp;rdquo;, which claimed to treat a variety of ailments. There were not a large quantity of advertisements that advertised to do a similar thing, but the main two were Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills and Dr. William&#39;s Pink Pills. Due to the fact that medicine at the time was still developing and overall understanding of illnesses was relatively unknown, actual medical professionals weren&#39;t able to properly diagnose and treat many  of their patients properly. This resulted in many individuals going and using these untraditional methods of treatment. In general, kidney function was not well understood, resulting in renal diseases being broadly categorized as &lt;a href=&#34;https://raycityhistory.wordpress.com/2011/03/15/george-emory-swindle-sought-cure-at-buffalo-lithia-springs-va/&#34;&gt;Bright’s disease&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raycityhistory.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/doans-box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills&#34; title=&#34;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the similar alternative to the Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills, Dr. William&#39;s Pink Pills were eventually realized for their true worth and removed from the market. I was originally expecting a similar result for Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills, although it appears that these pills are actually sold today even. It appears at some point the deceptive and untruthful advertising was changed to only advertise for the true effects of the pill. Sometime during this timeline, the ingredients of the pills were switched from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjFkaux-KvmAhUHnOAKHT6vBmYQFjACegQIDBAI&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.urbanremainschicago.com%2Fsingle-rare-antique-and-all-original-wall-mount-porcelain-enameled-metal-thermometer-advertisement-for-doan-s-pills-remedy-for-kidney-ailments.html&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw0S9N9AfJ1HZbQYcHul184I/&#34;&gt;oil of jupiter &amp;amp; potassium nitrate&lt;/a&gt; to magnesium salicylate, a mild analgesic and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug. The differences between the two are that potassium nitrate is used today mainly in explosives and fertilizers, whereas modern Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills actually contain a substance that has been proven to help with pain and inflammation. It is frightening to see Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills avoided the same fate as Dr. William&#39;s Pink Pills, despite not being a placebo capsule and instead containing substances such as potassium nitrate which have been proven to cause &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjvmPKV-avmAhVhkeAKHXBACG0QFjACegQIDRAI&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftoxnet.nlm.nih.gov%2Fcgi-bin%2Fsis%2Fsearch%2Fa%3Fdbs%2Bhsdb%3A%40term%2B%40DOCNO%2B1227&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3vK1ctvthIXB-LB4F7JVDi/&#34;&gt;violent gastroenteritis, anemia, methemoglobinemia, or even nephritis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Similar blogs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/&#34;&gt;Miraculous Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34;&gt;Pink Pills for Pale People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to Law Against Foreigners in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This ad in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper provides readers with a quick synopsis of a book called The Law Affecting Foreigners in Egypt by James Henry Scott, a lecturer at the Khedivial School of Law, Cairo. The book is an introduction to Egyptian Law as it affected foreigners and provides information on history like; the law of the Ottoman Empire and the Ottoman Capitulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book that the ad speaks of discloses Egyptian law as it once affected the foreigners of Egypt. For instance, from the list of topics the ad provided us with, it can be noted that this book provides us with information on events such as the mixed codes, mixed courts, the capitulations of European states, and the commercial privileges given to the people of Egypt. During the Anglo-Egyptian War, the country of Egypt was not only occupied by British forces but it was colonized by the British from 1882 when the war started, until 1956 when the war ended and the last British forces withdrew in accordance with the Anglo-Egyptian agreement of 1954 after the Suez Crisis. During this past age of time, several legal problems that were present in Egyptian law came about and were also seized with the limited powers of independent legislation. Insights like this about international historic events that has happened internationally has always intrigued me. I believe that international law allows students like myself to form bits of knowledge into the worldwide legal system and its effect on both national and international policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=gKIuAAAAIAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA288&amp;amp;lpg=PA288&amp;amp;dq=Mr.+Scott,+of+the+Khedivial+Law+School+Cairo&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=nHjRElq7vn&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U2u2ymFGRhBOm1CgfETFkwPHePcSQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjOs6Gz_K7mAhWPxVkKHcgTCikQ6AEwAXoECAYQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=Mr.%20Scott%2C%20of%20the%20Khedivial%20Law%20School%20Cairo&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;this review&lt;/a&gt; that gives an opinionated review and summary of the book itself. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/367847?seq=1&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; describes the social tensions and the how tht teaching of European law was in Egypt before 1900. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encyclopedia.com/history/encyclopedias-almanacs-transcripts-and-maps/capitulations-middle-east&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; describes how the capitulations were in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discrimination Against Dogs in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-nangelisrivera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-nangelisrivera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was completing my deliverables and combing through page images, I came across an interesting article in the &amp;ldquo;Letters to the Editor&amp;rdquo; section of the June 14, 1907 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. In this article, an individual described their experience in which their gentle dog was harmed and seized, right as they were about to get into their home, simply because it was not wearing a muzzle. In this time in Egypt, it was required for dogs to wear muzzles in public, but this individual was not able to place a muzzle on their dog because it was so small and no muzzle would fit it. The typical punishment for dogs not wearing muzzles in Egypt was death. As this individual went through the process of getting their dog back, they witnessed a vast area and said it was &amp;ldquo;like searching for pins in the Catacombs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treatment of dogs in Alexandria was completely different than the treatment of dogs in today&#39;s society. Today we treat dogs as if they are our own children and only muzzle them if they show aggressive tendencies. In Alexandria, if any dog, no matter how small, nice, or cute, was seen without a muzzle in the open, the police would hit them, or kill them, and even seize the dogs and contain them in an ironic facility labelled the &amp;ldquo;Infirmary : Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.&amp;rdquo; The individual that submitted this letter did not understand Arabic, so they could not understand what two police officers were trying to tell them before the writer&#39;s dog was seized or even the papers that needed to be signed before the dog went back into the writer&#39;s custody. This type of treatment would not be accepted today in the United States since pets have become so near and dear to humans. Pets are now even ironically used as police dogs all around the world, contrary to the letter that discussed how police were abusive towards dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, someone discussed this same letter, &amp;ldquo;Police Dog Service&amp;rdquo; and stated that someone responded to this letter agreeing with the writer and stating that dogs should be treated better, especially as they get closer to passing away. However, in this time period in Egypt, dogs were not commonly thought of as dearly as they are now, so they were kept in terrible conditions and left to die a horrible death. In another &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-sain/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I saw even more evidence of how dogs were yet again mistreated and not cared about as much as they are today. The creator of this blog post mentioned that they discovered that there was a section in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;Stray and Ownerless Dog&amp;rdquo; that provided little information on the actual dog and when they were set to be poisoned. In this time period in Egypt, if dogs were found and did not seem to have an owner, a vague announcement was made and as a form of controlling the overpopulation of dogs, they were euthanized right as they were caught. Today, we provide owners with a longer time to find their lost dog and if a dog does not have an owner and is in a no-kill shelter, workers at the shelter try their hardest to advertise the dog so that it can find a loving home. This is interesting because we can see the development of the relationship between man and man&#39;s best friend in the United States in the early 1900s and Egypt in the 1900s, Americans have domesticated dogs and thought of them as family members whereas Egyptians saw them as a hassle and pests. According to an &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.biodiversitylibrary.org/2017/07/cats-dogs-nineteenth-and-early-twentieth-century-perspectives.html&#34;&gt;Online Blog&lt;/a&gt;, during the nineteenth and twentieth centuries dogs were still not as near and dear to individuals as they are now. Dogs were kept mostly for completing tasks such as hunting, not usually for enjoying their company and having a companion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through reading these blog posts about how dogs were mistreated in twentieth century Egypt, I decided to conduct more research to see if the treatment of dogs has improved today in the twenty-first century. I first found an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.egypttoday.com/Article/1/3793/Gov%E2%80%99t-poisons-1K-stray-dogs-in-3-months-denies-shooting&#34;&gt;Egyptian News Article&lt;/a&gt; that discussed the cruelty of the Egyptian government towards dogs. Since Egypt is overpopulated by dogs, the government poisons the food by stray dogs and leaves them to die and lay in the street. There have even been rumors that the Egyptian government has shot dogs and lets them lay in their own blood on the ground. Through reading this Egyptian News Article, it is obvious that Egyptians in the twenty-first have the same disregard and cruelty towards dogs as Egyptians in the twentieth century. In this &lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.913.7476&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/a&gt;, a positive light is shed on the relationship between Egyptians and dogs as it highlights the useful tasks that dogs helped humans with. According to this article, dogs were seen as very productive in the Egyptian community because they assisted with hunting, protection, and herding livestock. Contrary to the writer of the &amp;ldquo;Police Dog Service&amp;rdquo; article in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, this article on the relationship between individuals and dogs in Egypt states that &amp;ldquo;ottoman officials indeed actively encouraged the increase and maintenance of dog populations by providing them with food and water and by punishing those who committed violence against them.&amp;rdquo; This is very surprising and ironic, considering that the &amp;ldquo;Police Dog Service&amp;rdquo; article literally stated how someone harmed an innocent, miniature dog due to it not having a muzzle. These differing opinions could possibly be due to different cities in Egypt having different policies and opinions on dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Prepare for an Outbreak</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An article in my January 30th, 1908 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Protection Against Cholera&amp;rdquo; speaks on the Alexandria Sanitation Department issuing a statement on what steps they will take to stop the spread of cholera.  I find this interesting because when an outbreak of anything happens today, the CDC for example, might send out a similar statement.  What also interests me is the difference between the two organizations that would issue such a statement.  In Alexandria, the sanitation department seemed to have authority over the control and prevention of disease spreading.  This goes on to suggest that early 20th century disease control was thought to be based entirely on sanitation.  In the United States, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/about/organization/mission.htm&#34;&gt;Center for Disease Control&lt;/a&gt; (CDC) has authority over the research and prevention of infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article says that its primary goal was to inform the readers of the preparations they can take to guard their own safe being. The following is what the article says the Sanitary Department Suggests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash our hands after every visit to &amp;ldquo;lieux d&#39;aisance&amp;rdquo; and each time before eating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat only well-cooked food; avoid altogether unfiltered water, uncooked milk and butter vegetables and fruits which can be neither cooked nor peeled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid all excess of food, generally, and too cold drinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call in the doctor immediately on the slighted suspicion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch your servants; do not allow them to go out without changing their clothes and washing their hands on returning; do not allow the boabs to have any persons not belonging to the building with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These precautions are interesting because a lot of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/cholera/preventionsteps.html&#34;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; are commonplace today.  The second portion of the article describes the actions that the sanitary department will do to inspect the town of infectious diseases.  They will inspect establishments and tell them to disinfect with carbonate lime.  This will also result in a number of wells being closing down throughout the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the article, it is mentioned that a &amp;ldquo;Coastguard cruiser&amp;rdquo; is patrolling the waters of the Red Sea, to prevent pilgrims crossing into Egypt.  This article was published towards the end of the Islamic Pilgrimage to Mecca.  Also in this time period are many reports from Mecca of reports of Cholera.  History also has also seen throughout the 19th century that &lt;a href=&#34;https://origins.osu.edu/article/hajj-and-europe/page/0/1&#34;&gt;cholera&lt;/a&gt; has spread from Mecca during Hajj.  Therefore the coastguard trying to keep the pilgrims from entering Egypt might be a good way to keep Alexandria safe from the threat of cholera.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest in Peace Miss F. Collins</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-15-austink/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-15-austink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking through my papers and noticed an interesting article that didn&#39;t seem to align with the theme of the local newsletter. In the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, mostly everything is generalized and for the benefit of the reader but there was a section titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baltimoresun.com/news/bs-xpm-2002-02-17-0202160131-story.html&#34;&gt;Obituary&lt;/a&gt; and it was interesting because it was on one specific person. As I read I realized that even though she did just seem like another local, the point of the article was to show how &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalthinkersforum.org/our-impact/each-and-everyone-of-us-is-unique-and-important-and-no-one-is-insignificant/&#34;&gt;every citizen is important&lt;/a&gt; and it made sure to explain how she was a quality person and her death was to be mourned as many of the locals in Luxor and Cairo cared for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Each and Everyone of Us Is Unique and Important, and No-one Is Insignificant”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this fascinating because there are two other instances I found while browsing through the blog posts in which the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; has done this.
For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-baenen-deathofthepasha/&#34;&gt;In the death of Haicalis Pasha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/&#34;&gt;Death of Mr. Hanna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both instances the newsletter is reporting local deaths and it shows that the community do care about its people and that no passing is meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the important things that was pointed out in the Obituary is how Miss Collins spent a majority of her time at church and actually passed while at a Sunday Service. It is safe to assume that she is now in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.everystudent.com/journeys/then.html&#34;&gt;Heaven&lt;/a&gt; because not only did she realize God but also lived an honest life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleepy driver results in fatal accident</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-peytonsmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-peytonsmith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One incident that I found very curious to research upon was one that I found in my Wednesday issue, in the Telegrams section that writes about an accident that happened in a town named Shrewsbury, located in the Mid-west part of England. As a train was traveling from Crewe to Bristol, it got into this accident in this town located right in the middle of the two cities and resulted in the death of 19 and injured 40.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the incident occurred, the cause of what happened is still uncertain. In an article, found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.revolvy.com/page/Shrewsbury-rail-accident&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, the officials at the scene examined the driver, and found out that he was not intoxicated nor under any influence of drugs, making the situation even more difficult to pinpoint. In another article, found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shropshirestar.com/news/nostalgia/2017/10/14/sleeping-driver-mystery-of-shropshires-worst-crash/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, they have another spectulation on why the incident came about, many officials believing that he was sleepy. The article reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot was that approaching Shrewsbury, sleep overcame him. He passed Harlescott crossing and Crewe Bank without knowing it, and did not see the signals at danger, and on the downward gradient coming in to Shrewsbury the train picked up speed rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident itself, even after 100 years, is something to always keep in mind. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/england/shropshire/7044176.stm&#34;&gt;another article&lt;/a&gt;, a member of the Shrewsbury Railway Heritage Trust, Dave Giddens, believes that the incident should never be forgotten. In his own words he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&#39;s very good, even after 100 years to still remember the people who were involved in it and the people that lost loved ones,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, there are other incidents in the Egyptian Gazette that also involves train crashes, in one &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-clark/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Gavin Clark, another incident involving a train accident was published in the newspaper in 1906. But instead of it being an actual crash, the train caught on fire. In another &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-story-theuntimelydeathofprincemohamidibrahim/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, made Will Hanley himself, entails an incident where a Prince was killed in an unusual car accident as he was hit by a train. Just from this, it can be concluded that train safety has definitely advanced in the 100 years. Nowadays, you rarely hear of a train crash, resulting in the death of people, where back then it seemed as if this was a common occurence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, one might ask &amp;ldquo;Why would a train accident be newsworthy in an Egyptian newspaper?&amp;quot;. The answer is simple, Britain took control over all parts of Egypt back during the time this was written. Acting as a protectorate under British rule, this lasted from 1886 to 1914. Because of this, it was very common to find British news all throughout the contents of the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette,&amp;rdquo; where the editors themselves were often at times British. At the same, for this incident specifically, it was located in the Telegrams section, where they report news from all around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RailwayAccident.png&#34; alt=&#34;Railway Accident&#34; title=&#34;Photo of the Railway accident in Shrewsbury as officials are investigating the scene.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Downfall of Thomas Cook Group</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-20-alvinchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-20-alvinchen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;thomas_cook_logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;thomas_cook_logo&#34; title=&#34;Thomas Cook Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Thomas Cook was an English businessman. He started up his business from a small local shop in London. The shop sold traveling related products such as guidebooks, traveling wears, and maps. Several years later in 1872, he expanded his business with his son John, reformed the company as “Thomas Cook &amp;amp; Son”. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/travel/tours/history-of-thomas-cook/&#34;&gt;(1)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course, we found that Thomas Cook &amp;amp; Son travel company had frequent updates on their advertisements. And they also sponsored the Egyptian Gazette profoundly by putting their advertisements on the title page banner. The company had various travel package options in the Middle East. It was the early age that civilians could afford the expenses and take ships to another continent. In parallel to the analysis of advertisement on the Egyptian Gazette by Olivia Evanoff &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-evanoff/&#34;&gt;(2)&lt;/a&gt;, she wrote that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;people could pay the fees that go along with it in that period.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is plausible the early 20 Century is prosperous era in economy. As the company grew, it also owned hotels in Britain primarily, Western Europe, North America, and Middle East. Suggested by a blog post by Kailen Chapple &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-chapple/&#34;&gt;(3)&lt;/a&gt;, the company had an enormous impact in the 19th Century. Kailen also remarked,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is a new concept … a product of the industrial revolution.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;company_ceases_trading.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;company_ceases_trading&#34; title=&#34;Thomas Cook ceases trading&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the glory of this family business could not thrive with the competitions in travel markets in 2019. Nowadays, people have more options for traveling. They gradually not rely on package-tours or travel agents. The way people used to travel is changed since it has became more accessible and easier to go foreign places without tour companies. Thomas Cook failed to transfer its tactics with modern travel behaviors, was defeated by other LCC (low-cost company) airlines competitors. It was bought in low stock value due to its 2.1 billion U.S. Dollars debt &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-thomas-cook-grp-investment-explainer/thomas-cook-collapses-why-and-what-happens-now-idUSKBN1W804O&#34;&gt;(4)&lt;/a&gt;. The bankruptcy also interrupted approximate 500 thousand travelers’ plans. And about 30 thousand Thomas Cook employees lost their jobs. Here is a footage about a pilot of Thomas Cook Airlines in his last day job &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGyd8jtroHo&#34;&gt;(5)&lt;/a&gt;. The company sinks into debt, but its employee tries their best to serve their passengers with professionalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it is the oldest travel company in Britain, the British government refuses to offer it bankruptcy protection. It may no longer have value to people, and the government can’t waste taxpayers’ money on an obselete industry. Let it pass with history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;References&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/travel/tours/history-of-thomas-cook/&#34;&gt;(1) History article, &amp;ldquo;The history of Thomas Cook, from tours for teetotallers to boozy packages in Spain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-evanoff/&#34;&gt;(2) Blog post by Kailen Chapple, &amp;ldquo;Hotels in Cairo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-chapple/&#34;&gt;(3) Blog post by Olivia Evanoff, &amp;ldquo;Advertising in Alexandria Egypt 1905&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-thomas-cook-grp-investment-explainer/thomas-cook-collapses-why-and-what-happens-now-idUSKBN1W804O&#34;&gt;(4) News article, &amp;ldquo;Thomas Cook collapses: Why and what happens now?&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGyd8jtroHo&#34;&gt;(5) Youtube video, &amp;ldquo;Thomas Cook Crew Gives Emotional Speech to Passengers After Touching Down in Mancheste&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Swindling Don Juan</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-robertthomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-robertthomas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to write my blog post about an interesting article I found on the first day of my assigned week. This article was about how an older wealthy lady named Waghida Hanem seemed to have had her feelings captured by a young man, whom her family believed was only after her substantial finances. The young man successfully convinced Ms. Waghida to leave for Zagazig to meet and marry him along with jewels and money valuing around 20,000 pounds. At the news of the marriage the family of the bride demanded the revocation of the marriage and subsequent divorce of the bride and groom which was granted through the correct legal proceedings. Ms. Waghida was left in the care of her brother which she refused and took refuge with her lawyer however she has now disappeared without a trace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was interesting to me for a number of reasons. One being that you don&#39;t hear many cases today of young men trying to get with older women for their money, most of the time it&#39;s the other way around with young women trying to find that rich lonely man to latch onto. Another thing I found interesting was how the family was able to literally nullify the marriage without the consent of either the bride or the groom and the fact that it was completely legal. There has been ongoing debate and trials regarding ways to legally nullify marriages in the U.S as outlined &lt;a href=&#34;http://eds.b.ebscohost.com/eds/pdfviewer/pdfviewer?vid=5&amp;amp;sid=ed4cddda-385a-463f-9405-36c8c02418ee%40pdc-v-sessmgr01&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, though I know of no way in America for someone who has no part in the marriage to nullify it against the bride and groom&#39;s wishes so the fact that this was allowed amazes me. However &lt;a href=&#34;http://eds.b.ebscohost.com/eds/pdfviewer/pdfviewer?vid=2&amp;amp;sid=ed4cddda-385a-463f-9405-36c8c02418ee%40pdc-v-sessmgr01&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; it is shown how in India a marriage may be nullified for a variety of reasons including if either the bride or groom was declared mentally unsound. This could be attributed to the laws in India that require a woman to have a male guardian so they are seen as less than women are seen in America. I read an article &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/kerala-high-court-hindu-muslim-islamic-state-979157-2017-05-25&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on how a marriage was made null and void by a court in India over the fact that it was believed the daughter was forcibly converted to Islam. Apparently this isn&#39;t extremely uncommon for countries other than the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough I found a blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pustam/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where the author decided to write an article about the fact that marriages were seen as a way for women to be happy and the author seemed extremely upset with that belief. I found it ironic considering Mrs. Waghida&#39;s family forcibly put an end to her marriage even though she inferably was happy. You could say that her family was trying to prevent her from getting her heart broken by this swindler or just hurt in general because as outlined &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where a man attempting to fix his relationship with his wife ends up stabbing her out of anger, domestic violence was not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-18-vanessagrimaldo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-18-vanessagrimaldo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-shift-in-education-in-egypt&#34;&gt;The Shift in Education in Egypt&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to research the word “education” from the whole contents of previous issues. In the history of the education in Egypt, I learned that just as I thought, schools were only for boys (1905-09-26), and all thy learned was the basics of their religion until they finished and took the trade or possession of their father. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/3443092?seq=2#metadata_info_tab_contents&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across and was impressed to see the small bits that came up. While I was expecting there to be education mainly for men or higher public figures, but actually found that education is important to the people of this time in this area, and education for orphans, children of the lower classes, and even young boys (making more elementary schools)(1905-04-14). There are even scholarships being offered, as seen in 1905-05-06, and there is desire to keep improving the educational standards of years to come, and desires to make use of the educational facilities such as the &amp;ldquo;Museum,&amp;rdquo; one of the most famous schools in Alexandria (1905-04-12). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.copticchurch.net/topics/patrology/schoolofalex/I-Intro/chapter1.html&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905-01-12, it is stated that Medicine, Law, and more liberal studies were professions that people strived to improve in. In it is celebrated that parents are allowing their daughters to receive primary education (1905-06-06 and 1905-07-12), and it is said that men who are educated want wives who are educated, too (1905-12-20). This time period seems to be the time for advancements in education in which fund are being put out to make educational buildings, everyone is beginning to get an education, and education is valued. At this time in Egypt, education has made tremendous improvements like an increase in the literacy rate and by a drop in the number of kids outside of school, but still faces some challenges such as the size of school not being able to accommodate the amount of children in Egypt and social issues arise in schools that get in thee way of the higher education of students. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wenr.wes.org/2019/02/education-in-egypt-2&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of a Review of a Review of a Book</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-18-baileeku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-18-baileeku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;article_image.png&#34; alt=&#34;photo of the article&#34; title=&#34;Caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Secret History of the English Occupation of Egypt: Being a Personal Narrative of Events&lt;/em&gt;, written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://mypoeticside.com/poets/wilfrid-scawen-blunt-poems&#34;&gt;Wilfrid Scawen Blunt&lt;/a&gt;, was given an uninspiring review in the Egyptian Gazette. This short piece, found on the third page of June 4, 1907, was comically scathing in its evaluation. Whoever wrote the review said that the publication “appears to contain nothing startling”  and “is as feeble as Mr. Blunt’s last notorious pamphlet.” Given Blunt’s usual mix of erotic poetry and political statements, I wonder which apparently uninspiring work is being referenced here. The reviewer condemns the focus on “accounts of Mr. Blunt’s own interventions,” an odd criticism given the book’s clear self-identification as a “Personal Narrative,&amp;rdquo; as well as his numerous mentions of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/biography/William-Ewart-Gladstone/First-administration-1868-74&#34;&gt;Prime Minister Gladstone&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; opinions. Gladstone&#39;s name is indeed referenced 109 times within the book. However, seeing as Gladstone had an immense amount of influence over British politics in the late 19th century, his inclusion in Blunt&#39;s narrative seems fitting. As no information about the author is provided for the review, there is little way of deciding whether the reviewer’s disdain of Blunt is due to literary or political reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilfrid Blunt held &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2019/jul/29/poem-of-the-week-prison-sonnets-by-wilfrid-scawen-blunt&#34;&gt;such contentious opinions&lt;/a&gt; as supporting Celtic and African freedom from the British empire. As the Egyptian Gazette was highly supportive of British imperialistic efforts (it was, after all, written for Englishmen and Frenchmen residing in Egypt), it makes sense that the writers would disapprove of Blunt. Blunt had a long and tumultuous history with Lord Cromer, consul general of Egypt and darling of the Egyptian Gazette. Blunt was Cromer’s political enemy. In a time when few British individuals opposed colonialism, Blunt encouraged opposition to the British agenda. Oddly enough, despite their political differences, Blunt and Cromer seemed to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://bewley.virtualave.net/blunt.html&#34;&gt;friends of a sort&lt;/a&gt;. Cromer even accompanied Blunt&#39;s daughter Judith at her wedding in Blunt&#39;s place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wilfrid_scawen_blunt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;photo of Wilfrid Scawen Blunt&#34; title=&#34;Caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I question whether the reviewer actually read the book, as he relies heavily on another newspaper’s thoughts. This is what caught my attention the most. It is a review based on another review of a book. It begins with the words “The ‘Daily Chronicle’ publishes an advance review of Mr. Wilfred Blunt’s book…” and ends with “From the review in question I would consider…” I suspect that any attempts to unravel this mystery would have to begin by examining the political leanings of the &lt;em&gt;Daily Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.questia.com/read/4898002/secret-history-of-the-english-occupation-of-egypt&#34;&gt;the work itself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abnormalities in the Mines</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-alainhernandezcorrales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-alainhernandezcorrales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fire has been around since the dawn of time. The use of fire in different aspects has increased but the dangers of being around it still are eye opening. On December 23, 1906 during the process of fire-setting, they had not taken into account the length of the fuse. This error in calculation led to the death of two of the miners and injuries to four more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article functions as a way to show the hardships that can be endured in certain jobs and to be careful with fire. From what I have researched on fire setting, it is a very simple procedure which shouldn&#39;t have too big of a risk factor. While deaths mining are a common occurrence, the cause of death is usually something less controllable. The awareness of the dangers of fire have a larger impact on the community rather than just in the mining field. This occasion makes the citizens of Alexandria question how well they are prepared in the case of a fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article also shows how the community cares about those impacted by these tragedies. It states the condolences of the author to the families affected by this accident and to express their sympathy for their losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-to-other-sources&#34;&gt;Links to Other Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-cannon/&#34;&gt;Analysis Cannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-meyer/&#34;&gt;Analysis Meyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/41496587?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents&#34;&gt;Ancient Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.persee.fr/doc/paleo_0153-9345_2000_num_26_2_4715&#34;&gt;Use of Fire in Prehistoric Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworldcounts.com/counters/environmental_effect_of_mining/health_effects_of_mining&#34;&gt;Environmental Effects of Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Elegant Wedding </title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-emilyseguin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-emilyseguin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 5th of October 1907 Captain Charles Massie Blomfield finally married Miss Hirell Clarence in a &amp;ldquo;fashionable wedding&amp;rdquo; that struck a chord with those in attendance. Held at St Paul’s on Wimbledon Common, the wedding itself was not the smallest, nor the biggest; it was the perfect size for the new couple. Many family members from both the bride and the groom were in attendance along with the groom’s army colleagues and battalion. The service was conducted by the godfather of the groom and was completely choral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss Hirell Clarence, the bride-to-be, wore a gorgeous white satin gown paired with a long veil made of tulle and a headpiece with orange blossoms perfectly arranged on it. On the other hand, the bridesmaids wore colorful gowns. Each gown was cream colored, decorated with gold tassels and gold thread, and was paired with dark green satin hats. Their bouquets held yellow roses and were tied off with a cute green ribbon, which complemented the bridesmaids&amp;rsquo; hats. As his gift to the bridesmaids, the groom gave each of them a white enamel and gold bracelet with small, purple amethysts on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the lovely ceremony, the wedding party moved to the location of the reception. The reception was held at Castle Towers, and to make the day even better, the weather was perfect which allowed the reception to be held on the patios of Castle Towers. The newlyweds also hired the Royal Warwickshire Regiment who played some lovely music and gave a romantic mood to the newlyweds&amp;rsquo; reception.  At the reception, the newlyweds were given a number of wedding gifts such as a silver pepper-port, a stamp box made from copper, a silver mounted jack jug, and many other useful presents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ell/&#34;&gt;another blog post&lt;/a&gt;, a different wedding is reported with the same title. This one describes the marriage of Captain Charlton and Gwendoline Whitaker, who also wore a crown of orange flowers to her ceremony. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jarmon/&#34;&gt;This blog post&lt;/a&gt; hits on the facts that even now, marriages are normally not publicly broadcasted unless it is a wedding of importance. The marriage of Captain Charles Massie Blomfield and Miss Hirell Clarence was published in the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; along with very personal details of the wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was published in the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo;, so the question still remains: why would people in Alexandria want to read about the marriage of two London locals? After conducting some research, it appears that the groom, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warwickwarmemorial.org.uk/wwi-names/blomfield-charles-george-massil/&#34;&gt;Captain Charles Massie Blomfield&lt;/a&gt; was born in London, but lived in Port House, Alexandria until the age of nine. His father was the man in charge of the Port of Alexandria and then Director General of all ports in Egypt. With this kind of history in Egypt, it is hard to imagine that Captain Blomfield and his new wife would not have an article of their wedding published in the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo;. To the people of Port House, Alexandria, Charles Blomfield is basically a local.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warwickwarmemorial.org.uk/wwi-names/blomfield-charles-george-massil/&#34;&gt;additional information on Captain Charles Blomfield&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Paul%27s_Cathedral&#34;&gt;more information on their wedding venue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drowning in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-ashleycrisafulli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-ashleycrisafulli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A prominent topic in many issues of the “Egyptian Gazette” is that of death. There are many different occurrences of death and they occur in all different ways. The one that stuck out to me the most was drowning. On page 3 of the Monday February 25, 1907 issue the story “Well Known Minister Drowned” caught my attention. This article talks about the death that occurred during sea travel from Liverpool to Alexandria. A reverend gentleman had fallen overboard during a storm. However, this was not the only death stated in the article. A few days prior the ship&#39;s carpenter had drowned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is a common topic in this paper, I wonder why they don’t go into detail about what happened to the minister that drowned. They merely state the fact that he went overboard during a storm. It is also interesting that there were two occurrences of drowning on the same boat in the same time. This makes me wonder how many others were effected in this same way. I went to explore more about death by drowning or shipwrecks and struggled to find data specific to Egypt. However, I did come across a source that showed many shipwrecks that occurred between 1833 and today, showing that shipwrecks were more common in this 1900s period. This could also be because ships were used to transport exports such as cotton. Egypt shipped cotton and other materials to Britain using ships. Although these would not be the same ships as the one the minister drowned on it is important to note that they were commonly used for many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this death occurred during travel which is something that has happened to many people in 1900s. In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/&#34;&gt;“Cairo Visitor gravely Injured”&lt;/a&gt;, the article examined also looks at death that occurred while someone was traveling. They also questioned how in-depth incidents were investigated at the time. Death was also talked about in other blog posts. In many cases there are posts about the plague, which appears to be a more common way to die at this time. From all of these article we see how death was reported and how it ranged in how in depth it was investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty in Pink</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-breannaheflin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-breannaheflin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early 1900&#39;s casualties were in abundance due to a lack of understanding of the human body. Disease and illness became an everyday battle for those who had been discharged as “incurable” with no hope for a healthy life. Marketing ploys done for many “patented” drugs, such as “Dr. William’s Pink Pills for Pale People”, fed on this vulnerability not knowing that many diseases did not even require medical intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pink Pills for Pale People” grew immensely in Great Britain and North America for their shiny pink coat and claims to cure TB, rickets, kidney diseases, and even &lt;a href=&#34;https://macdonaldtownbicycleclub.com/2017/04/24/mrs-e-j-curtis-paralysed-with-rheumatism-restored-to-active-health-by-dr-williams-pink-pills/&#34;&gt;paralysis&lt;/a&gt;. A new “miracle” drug had been invented that seemed to cure fatal diseases in a matter of days,  purifying the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kshs.org/kansapedia/pink-pills-for-pale-people/10240&#34;&gt;“bad blood”&lt;/a&gt; that resulted in muscle and nerve disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One case was that of a young daughter named Sophie Caspeele who suffered from a severe case of anemia: chronic weakness, loss of appetite, and poor digestion. Claiming to cure female ailments, marketing practices such as this one tugged on the heart strings of parents and suffering women. The pills became well-known and named for the healthy complexion that they restored to its patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bmh19/blog-posts/master/2019-10-17-Breanna%20Heflin/Pink%20Pills.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sophie Caspeele&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, the famous “Pink Pills” were discovered to contain merely “extract of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wellcomelibrary.org/2015/03/dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34;&gt;Barbadoes&lt;/a&gt; aloes enclosed in a thick coating of sugar, colored with pink carmine”, yet continued to be sold into the 20th century. The “Pink Pills” were eventually exposed for quackery and withdrawn in the UK in 1970.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though still flawed, this case of medical negligence shows the improvement needed and made within the pharmaceutical industry relied on by many even today. Marketing strategies fool us similarly in the 21st century as they did in the 20th with physical appeals and claims of the unbelievable happening, because it is not actually happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;similar-blog-posts&#34;&gt;Similar blog posts:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34;&gt;Pink Pills for Pale People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/&#34;&gt;Miraculous Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Careless” Train Workers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-damiangrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-damiangrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“ROYAL TRAIN DERAILED” was the headline that caught my attention in the October 30, 1907 issue, in which the train carrying the King and Queen of Spain and their infant prince son came off the rails as a result of the “carelessness of a local engine driver.” Shortly after this story, within the same page,
was another story with the headline “Train Collision” with yet another description of a “careless employee.” I became curious if there existed a trend in accidents being caused by “careless” train workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I performed a query to find all instances of the descriptor “careless” found in the same division a “train” was mentioned. My results provided 6 instances of a “careless” individual or group being responsible for a train related accident or issue – 5/6 whom were train workers. Half of the accidents resulted in no injuries, while the other half resulted in severe injuries or death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In searching other blog posts, I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-clark/&#34;&gt;another train incident&lt;/a&gt; in which a train “caught on fire due to an exploding lamp in one of the first-class cars” and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-thompson/&#34;&gt;data analysis&lt;/a&gt; that showed that “train and car wrecks/accidents” accounted for 6% of all deaths recorded in 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As explained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwww.dailynewssegypt.com/2013/05/08/egypts-railways-past-present-and-future/&#34;&gt;the Daily News Egypt&lt;/a&gt;, the construction of railroads in Egypt began in 1834, making it the first railway system in Africa, with a route connecting Alexandria to Cairo and Suez beginning in 1851. Throughout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikes.railhistory.railfan.net/r050.html&#34;&gt;railway&#39;s history&lt;/a&gt;, different companies and organizations would control different portions of track, such as the Egyptian State Railways Administration and the Delta Light Railway Company, resulting in the multitude of railway ads found throughout the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alhough not every incident I found occured in Egypt, the country still has a long history of railway accidents, and, unfortunately, they continue to this day, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ble-t.org/pr/news/headline.asp?id=2877&#34;&gt;the deadliest accident&lt;/a&gt; occurring in 2002 in which over 370 people died when a train caught fire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Mummies? A Midlife-Crisis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-15-faynberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-15-faynberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing screams excitement more than finding a new &lt;em&gt;Mummy&lt;/em&gt; to add to your cherished collection. Well, at least this is the case for novelist Pierre Loti who seems to have struck gold in the next piece of his mummy collection. Yes, you read that correctly. Pierre Loti possessed a collection of ancient Egyptian Mummies. This new mummy is said to hold a young princess and Loti claims it is one of the best in his collection, but never explains in what way. Best preserved? Best wrapped? Either way, Mr. Loti seems to be excited about his find. In Loti’s book &lt;em&gt;La mort de Philae&lt;/em&gt;, he records his visit to Egypt and the Museum of Antiquities in Cairo as can be seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://anubis4_2000.tripod.com/subpages1/Loti.htm&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierre Loti was born in 1850 in Rochefort, France. His birth name is Louis Marie-Julien Viaud with Pierre Loti being his pseudonym. He was raised in a very religious family, reading the Bible every day and originally aspiring to become a pastor. His career path changed as he desired to adventure around the world. More information about Loti&#39;s upbringing can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.museeprotestant.org/en/notice/pierre-loti-1850-1923-2/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superstitions run high in Egypt during this time and touching the dead is a big no. With religion being a focal point in Ancient Egypt, mummification was believed to be a way to preserve the body for resurrection as described by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.historymuseum.ca/cmc/exhibitions/civil/egypt/egcr06e.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/&#34;&gt;Blog post &lt;/a&gt; by Claudia Richardson mentions that the dead were buried with an abundance of food for the afterlife. Gwen Lofman in her &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-29-egyptology/&#34;&gt;Blog Post&lt;/a&gt; titled &lt;em&gt;Egyptology &amp;amp; Archeology&lt;/em&gt; mentions how the newspaper served as a medium to share the discovery of these mummies. Loti explains how none of his servants would lay their hands on the body, which resulted in Mr. Loti having to transport it himself. Only when he arrived upstairs with the mummy did he realize he was holding on to a corpse. Either way, he added it to his study just as a kid would add a trophy to his trophy case and went along with his day. A typical day apparently in the life of Pierre Loti. Now if all this didn’t give off enough of an ominous vibe, right by Mr. Loti’s desk in his study resides the mummy of a three year old girl who watches as Loti writes. What an awkward study date that must be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;PL.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PageText&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosquitoes Suck</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-aaronkamata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-aaronkamata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;TheMosquitoInEngland.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;article&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is, in a nutshell, an informational piece on mosquitoes. Despite being written in the early 20th century, the facts presented in this article are very consistent with the science we see to be true nowadays. The author states that a mosquito does not actually have a poison gland, but instead delivers some sort or irritant through its saliva. While that is true, we have more information regarding that matter now. We know now that the irritant is actually a protein in the mosquito’s saliva to which most humans tend to have an allergic reaction to, as stated &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/mosquitocontrol/general-information-about-mosquitoes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The article states that only female mosquitoes “bite” people, which is supported in modern times as well, shown &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aaaai.org/conditions-and-treatments/library/allergy-library/taking-a-bite-out-of-mosquitoes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It also claims that more of them tend to be found around swampy areas, which is supported &lt;a href=&#34;http://vectorbio.rutgers.edu/outreach/habitat.php&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As we can see, the information provided in this article is factual and not outdated. This allows it to be a very functional expository piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the article is also humorous and almost satirical. Because of certain pedantic and condescending phrases such as “we in England”, “if you prefer it”, and “that other annoying parasite”, the author seems to have an inflated sense of self. When they describe the mosquito’s saliva and how different bites come with different magnitudes of discomfort, they follow it by saying that it does not matter since people are bitten regardless. They abruptly shift from giving information to completely dismissing its relevance. Things like this would normally indicate that they think they are above the reader in all possible ways, but due to it being so excessive and exaggerated, it is clear that they are using and arrogant tone to convey some sarcasm. The humor in this article makes it a lot more digestible, since the information itself is not actually that interesting to most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/17-analysis-ferguson/&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is another blog post in which a student analyzes the mosquito control efforts specifically in Egypt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-28-nunez-blogpost/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is one that describes a miracle product that could heal anything, including mosquito bites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Russian Revolution of 1905</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-oscar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-oscar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Russian Revolution of 1905 began with Tsar Nicholas II attempting to transform the Russian government from an autocracy to a monarchy (Smith). His attempt for a new system of government led to political and social unrest across the Russian Empire. Although this movement originally began many years before 1905, the &amp;ldquo;Bloody Sunday&amp;rdquo; massacre on the 22nd of January of that year is known to have sparked this revolution (Shimazu). When a bunch of workers, specially the poor, took on the streets and made their way to Tsar&#39;s Palace in hopes of presenting a petition for better working conditions, they were welcomed with gunfire. Worker strikes, urban uprisings, and peasant revolts continued over the next several years (Heywood).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is all just basic research that anyone can learn about using the internet. However, I wanted to go on further into this topic as it caught my attention while I was reading the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; newspaper. Before hand, I had no clue about this event in history. Being in the class of Microhistory, I have been given the opportunity to access the archives, or newspaper articles, of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. With this source, I was able to look into fresh insights of the roles individuals, social groups, and political parties played throughout the Russian Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![Image label](1905-01-23-p3.jpg &amp;ldquo;OPEN REVOLUTION IN RUSSIA: People&#39;s appeal to the Tsar. Conflicts with troops. Thousands killed!&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I did my search query, I wanted to see what this newspaper had to say about the &amp;ldquo;Bloody Sunday&amp;rdquo; massacre. Therefore, I looked through the content folder for January 22nd of 1905 but no luck. However the following day, January 23rd, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was full with information regarding this terrible event. According to the newspaper, it all began around 2 o&#39;clock when huge crowds marched to the Winter Palace to present a petition to Tsar. The petition said, “Satisfy these demands and you make Russia happy and glorious. If you do not reply to the people&#39;s prayer, we prefer to die in the Square before your Palace&amp;rdquo;, and sadly that&#39;s what happened. Soon, the crowd started to run away and rapidly barricaded themselves across the city. Reading insights like, &amp;ldquo;troops were firing recklessly&amp;hellip; The air is rent with cries of women and the angry shouts of men&amp;rdquo;, heavily portrays a tense mood. This day, full with unpleasant and dreadful memories for many, has come to be known as the &amp;ldquo;Bloody Sunday&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why, why and how did all of this start? What were the reasons that led to the Revolution in Russia? Looking through relevant posts I was able to find the factors that played a major role in this, other than the Bloody Sunday. Anthony Muniz argues in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/17-analysis-muniz/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that they are four main factors. Things such as huge gaps between social classes, poor economy, land ownership laws, and &amp;ldquo;anger amongst the educated class&amp;rdquo;. Although I agree with Muniz, all of these problems wouldn&#39;t have occurred if the Russo-Japanese War didn&#39;t happen several years before. The citizens of Russia rose in revolutionary groups as they saw Tsar Nicholas II as a weak leader. Civilians didn&#39;t just simply surrender. They immediately rebeled against Tsar&#39;s inhuman actions in a fight that would go on throughout the next 3 years. The question is, will Nicholas II&#39;s actions to preserve his autocracy have serious consequences or will his power over the military suppress any opposition? Jonathan Cannon was able to answer this in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-cannon/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;if the Tsar keeps the support of the army he can maintain power&amp;rdquo;. Conversely, his power over the military declined as soldiers began to support and fight alongside the rebels. Even so, in the end, the Russian government &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rdquo; as the Tsar remained absolute leader. While this may be true, peace only came about when promises were made to the citizens of a &amp;ldquo;people&#39;s government&amp;rdquo; with amendments to come and a new Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heywood, Anthony, and Jon Smele. &lt;em&gt;The Russian Revolution of 1905 : Centenary Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge, 2005. EBSCOhost, search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=nlebk&amp;amp;AN=563956&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naoko SHIMAZU. “Views from the Trenches: New Year’s Truce, Bloody Sunday and Japanese Attitudes toward the 1905 Revolution in Russia.” Horizons: Seoul Journal of Humanities, vol. 5, no. 2, Dec. 2014, pp. 195–208. EBSCOhost, search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=hus&amp;amp;AN=101030349&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith, S. A. &lt;em&gt;The Russian Revolution : A Very Short Introduction&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford University Press, 2002. EBSCOhost, search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=nlebk&amp;amp;AN=100322&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire in the Night</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-hernandez/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-hernandez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often in the Egyptian Gazette fire is mentioned as having caused the death of a resident or the destruction of significant property. On January 4th, 1907 for example, the Gazette reports a large fire on a gunwharf that caused thousands of pounds of goods to be destroyed, officially estimated at a current value of 250,000 British pounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another instance of the debilitating effects of fire mentioned in the Gazette was on January 10, 1905. This fire broke out on Tousson Street in Alexandria, at a store filled with chandeliers, lamps, and large amounts of petroleum. Although a fire engine was on scene 5 minutes after the alarm was activated, eight hoses continuously dumping water could not stop the fire for two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These announcements had vital potential impact on the citizens of Alexandria to raise awareness of the absolute devastation fire could cause and the necessity for precautions against such a danger. The Gazette&#39;s report of fire damage from around the world served the purpose of bringing a more thorough knowledge of the universal issue of uncontrolled fires to the people of Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the fire fighting techniques of the day were not entirely effective, as realized in the above example, the explicit, long term, and life threatening effects of fire were a necessary understanding among the people of Alexandria in those years, and the Gazette provided consistent documentation to serve that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can women be happy without men?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pustam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pustam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this article on women and marriage while finding articles for my analysis project. My project was on wedding fashion, and this article talks about how women don’t consider marrying a man the ultimate way to get a happy life anymore. The writer of this article is very angry about it, saying “Where else [women’s papers] would anyone dare to imply that woman was sufficiently idiotic to believe that marriage &amp;ldquo;of itself alone&amp;rdquo; guaranteed anything?” I honestly kind of thought this article was funny. It was just funny to see the writer get so worked up they had to write an article about it that is mostly made up of quotes and not a lot of their own thoughts (pretty bad journalism if you ask me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something interesting about this was the fact that women are being blamed for the decline in marriage within this article, when there are incidents like one I found in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;- a crazy man killing his wife. Similar to in the Gazette, the writer of the blog post suggests the woman may be at fault for her unhappy marriage. They suggest that she might have cheated on her husband, causing him to kill her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there is another blog post, titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/&#34;&gt;“Women Are Always Lying?”&lt;/a&gt;, which describes an article that rants about how women lie to men by changing their appearance (presumably through makeup). Women are depicted as “a creature of broad and gradual curves, whose first duty it is to persuade you that she is the shape of the fashionable corset…” I can’t speak for women back then, but now women really don’t dress up for the sake of impressing men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When women are treated like this by men in newspaper articles, its really no wonder why they create their own newspapers to say that “it is possible to be as happy without a man’s love as with it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistreatment or misunderstanding?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-brown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Upon visiting the mosque at the University of al Azhar, Mr. Sheldon Amos, judge of the Native Court, claims that he was met with &amp;ldquo;considerable rudeness&amp;rdquo; on behalf of the students there. This incident caused the chancellor of the university to face repercussions from the government, being required to implement a new system for visitors at the institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts of Mr. Amos&amp;rsquo; story do not add up. He claims that the students were rude to him, but at the time he visited the mosque, there was a commotion among the students due to a sudden rain shower. The chancellor of the school claims the visitors were probably sent in the direction of disorder, and that any claims of rudeness are simply a misunderstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer of this June 13, 1906 article in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; seems to believe Mr. Amos. They claim that his job as judge of the Native Court means that he has thorough knowledge of Arabic and could not possibly mistake jostling for rudeness. They even go so far as to question if the chancellor of the school was there at the time of the incident. The writer of the article seems to have some preconceived notions about this university. They claim that an Indian student was recently made fun of for his political views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to outside sources, Amos was born in 1872 in London. His full name was Percy Maurice Maclardie Sheldon Amos. He was appointed to the Cairo Native Court in 1903. He was educated at Cambridge and came from a very wealthy and well-known family. When considering the reasons for the unrest in the article, it is worth noting that Amos was a European man with a position of power in Egypt. European presence in Egypt was agitating to many Egyptians, and as a result caused unrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article is not in any particular section of the paper, but is its own section. The writers of the article input their own opinions on the topic, which is something I have seen in many other articles in the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.laits.utexas.edu/cairo/history/modern/modern.html&#34;&gt;https://www.laits.utexas.edu/cairo/history/modern/modern.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vqronline.org/essay/mixed-courts-egypt&#34;&gt;https://www.vqronline.org/essay/mixed-courts-egypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/10.1093/ref:odnb/9780198614128.001.0001/odnb-9780198614128-e-30403;jsessionid=848062D8750262DB8B32285B5E341BE5&#34;&gt;Dictionary of National Biography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage &amp; Divorce</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jarmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jarmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my blog post, I chose to talk about the topic of Marriage &amp;amp; Divorce in the year of 1907, around the month August. I was particularly intrigued by the emphasis on marriage being placed in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper which is opposed to what we see in these modern times. One specific section in my reading that gathered my interest was titled &amp;ldquo;Alexandria Merchant Divorce&amp;rdquo; published on August 6, 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brief overview about the story resulted in the end of a marriage between Mr. William Getty, a cotton merchant of Alexandria and his wife. Over the past years, she strayed away and disappeared from him, leaving him to wonder about her whereabouts and how she was doing. While on her death bed, she had an incurable diseases that she couldn&#39;t be healed from. She wrote a letter to her husband confessing that she was unfaithful to him throughout the duration of their marriage. In defense of her statement, she felt that the money she had leftover should be given to him since she recently became a Christian Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This excerpt from the passage was quite interesting for me to read because I was fascinated with the explicit details provided and how it was shared with all of the world to see. Although they didn&#39;t share a response from her husband after he received the message from her, I would have wondered what his thoughts, response or even last words to her would have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reference to this article, I found another interesting topic from the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34;&gt;another blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a crazy man killing his wife with an unusual weapon. Although there is no reason for his crazy acts, he committed the crime from speculations that his wife was cheating on him. The magnitude of this article was extremely huge enough to reach the newspaper because people thought the city should be aware of this person and who he is. This article correlated to mine because there was suspicion of cheating in both marriages where the results ended up tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Theater</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-hutson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-hutson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The musical theater correspondent surprised me with their knowledge of &amp;ldquo;Los Huguenots&amp;rdquo;. The editor well-articulated their points of the show, being critical but also giving a lot of praise. They begin with the overall thoughts, saying it began slowly, but within a little bit of time it picked up into a great show. The following paragraphs go deeper into the different performers and even the chorus. The editor praised all the performers on how well they sang, but nothing really on acting skill. They did go onto write the chorus was a failure of the performance, but did no effect the overall show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really felt as if I went to this show, hearing and visualizing the actors throughout. It was very surprising to me to see such good talent being exhibited during this time period, but also the critic who wrote the excerpt was impressive. I did not know that Egypt had such a well-rounded society with a variety of quality entertainment options. However, I do not think it is anywhere as good as what we are seeing during the present day. Today’s entertainment is a wide variety of genres, which means actors must have a wide variety of skills. One of the analysis projects titled, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/analysis/2016/ragland-analysis&#34;&gt;“The Exploration of Musicians in Alexandria”&lt;/a&gt; agrees with this as well. Ragland, the editor writes that most of the performers were amateurs, but were still greatly supported by the community. He goes on to say that there are no negative reviews that he can find, and the &amp;ldquo;Los Huguenots&amp;rdquo; review is no different. The editor does nothing but praise the performance. One last thing I found interesting in his analysis was he said the amount of musicians in the Egyptian Gazette was outstanding. He does not give them by specific name, but mentions the sheer number that are mentioned. I related this to my article because the editor brings up several performers, probably all of the performers from that show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental Shooting</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-beasley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-beasley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 22nd, 1906 the Egyptian Gazette posted an article about an accidental shooting that occurred in the middle of page three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company by the name of Sudan Railways was the headline of Monday’s issue when it was heard that there was a shooting involving the company. A man named Mr. Sequino, a worker for Sudan Railways, was the main topic of this article. He had somehow managed to shoot himself in the mouth. Yes, in the mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owning a gun was unheard of in early twentieth century Egypt. Never the less owning a magnum, a powerful hand gun that packs a punch with a .45 caliber bullet. Working as a bridge foreman one day, Mr. Sequino ‘carelessly’ placed his gun down on a table and it managed to fall off. When reaching down to pick it up it fired a bullet straight at him, wedging the bullet through his two bottom front teeth, knocking them out, and sawing off part of his tongue. The event resulted in him having to take therapy lessons, basically learning how to speak again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guns typically don’t fire on their own, they need someone to pull the trigger. How Mr. Sequino’s gun fired on its own before he even contacted it is just absurd. It really leaves someone wondering about his personality, and if people in early twentieth century Egypt roamed the streets with unsafe handguns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, there are many articles within the Egyptian Gazette that give evidence that people owned and perhaps roamed the streets with guns and other types of weaponry. In my weekly issue there are instances where a rifle club appears, and there is an advertisement for the club practice. This means that people owned rifles in Egypt. Also, in an earlier week there is a mentioning about being able to trade in weapons for even better weapons that were once owned by criminals or murderers. These guns were taken away from them by the police, and then taken to a shop where citizens could trade or purchase them. Mr. Sequino might have purchased his revolver at a store like this, and as you can see, his purchase did not end in a good result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Events like these are included all throughout the Egyptian Gazette. Page three is usually where useful and exciting information about royal families or the Khedive is placed in the newspaper. However, including comical and ridiculous stories such as the one with Mr. Sequino tells us that Egyptian journalism covered an array of topics. It also tells us that the community of Alexandria enjoyed keeping up with relevant and newly developing stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Egypt In A Bubble?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-metallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-metallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economies are cyclical. Fact. They will experience ups and downs. Fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the headlines of “Financial Crisis” glaring from the pages of the “Egyptian Gazette”, it is safe to assume that Egypt will be heading for an economical decline. As 1907 progresses, the financial situation in Egypt seems to be falling to great depths, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the May 5, 1907 edition of the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; claims were made that the downturn was only impacting Cairo and Alexandria, it was “only confined to Alexandria and Cairo.” The positivity, as seen in the article below from May 1907, was meant to keep the entire country from panicking, preventing a self-fulfilling prophecy of a complete market collapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;financial-positivity-19070521.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;financial positivity 19070521&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By June of 1907, only one month later, the country began to feel the effects of the crisis spreading further from the localized markets of Cairo and Alexandria. Banks began to suffer, stock prices began to drop, and the country was searching for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image below is a screenshot from June 1907. It is now apparent that something needs to be done to solve the slipping economy.  The Alexandria Stock and Shareholders Association brought it upon themselves to attempt to curb the fall by creating a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?ei=6i7BWsOpLIX3zgLq6auwAQ&amp;amp;q=define+deputation&amp;amp;oq=define+deputation&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..0j0i22i30k1l7.22758.23978.0.24069.10.8.0.0.0.0.226.613.0j1j2.3.0....0...1.1.64.psy-ab..7.3.611...35i39k1j0i10k1j0i22i10i30k1.0.SinQKTgLTj8&#34;&gt;deputation&lt;/a&gt; and appointing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eldon_Gorst&#34;&gt;Sir Eldon Gorst&lt;/a&gt; as their deputy to lead them in their efforts.  Gorst was the controller of taxes and undersecretary of finances in Britain and was sent to Egypt to work along side Egyptian financial officials to fix their inevitable market meltdown.  He was also tasked with promoting native Egyptian responsibility in government positions (this did not happen and he would become hated by the old British rulers in Egypt and distrusted by Egyptain officials).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sir-eldon-gorst.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;sir eldon gorst&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, in the June 19, 1907 issue of the paper, the crisis was felt abroad, as seen in the article below from the introduction to a quote of a French article. Not only is the crisis officially “raging” in Egypt but is felt all over Europe (which, honestly, has the most to lose seeing as Egypt was still under European rule).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;feeling-the-crisis-abroad-19070619.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;feeling the crisis abroad 19070619&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Domestic Tragedy</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article tells the story of a divorced couple that ultimately ended in fatality. In attempts to fix his relationship, the spouse tried to convince his former wife to get back together. However, when she refused, he got angry and stabbed her multiple times. After this violent and impulsive reaction had subsided, the man realized what he had done, and thinking he had killed his spouse, he drew a revolver and shot himself dead. However, the woman simply fell unconscious and did not die.
This story has a theme similar to Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; pertaining to the story of a spouse thinking his partner is dead and consequentially killing himself because of that thought. It also shows that people would do anything for love, and that people act irrationally when they are put in desperate situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, domestic violence was not uncommon, as shown in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34;&gt;Matthew Cooper&#39;s blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Here Cooper talks about an article on a man who killed his wife with an blow to the head by a bar of iron. Although the context is different between the two instances, it is clear that abuse within marriages was not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising... Has anything really changed?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-majonica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-majonica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I happen to really enjoy encoding &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette.&amp;rdquo; It is almost therapeutic. As I venture into another day of my week in January of 1907, I have become accustomed with its format, easily pulling code from other parts of the paper I, and my classmates, have already worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the paper is the advertisement section. No hassle of OCR, lots of pictures, and its sheer simplicity makes me feel like an encoding wiz. And when I was working on my Thursday issue, I imagined myself reading &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was surprisingly simple for me, to read the newspaper as if I always had, as I even began to memorize the advertisements in the same way people living in Alexandria probably did, knowing their location and contents by heart. Interestingly enough, the most common advertisements seemed to be for travel, focused on both steamship movements and hotels. However, I did not really enjoy reading these advertisements, and even worse were the ones relating to finance or insurance. My favorite by far were the advertisements related to health. These advertisements were less common, but they were unique, scattered throughout the paper making me feel as if I was on a scavenger hunt in search of the next one. They are the complete opposite of the steamship and hotel advertisements that overwhelm the first, second, and last page of the paper. I actually wanted to read the health advertisements because who isn’t intrigued by the idea of something that can make one feel or look better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each and every time I see an advertisement for Peruna, a medicine advertised for women, the miracle stories about how it has changed people’s lives, as well its format and illustrations, catch my attention. Peruna&#39;s advertisements jump off the page, unlike the steamer and hotel advertisements whose contents are seemingly stagnant and are not eye-catching at all. The Mena House Hotel advertisement is an example of their lackluster design, with its only description being that it is a &amp;ldquo;First Class Family Hotel.&amp;rdquo; Hard to say if I would stay there. The same goes for the boring advertisement for the Savoy Palace Hotel, which does not get me excited at all for it to open &amp;ldquo;shortly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different are these advertisement tactics from that of today? Not very; the same tactics are used, especially when advertising medicine, as “success” stories continue to be attached to medicines sold in present day. Yet, in terms of travel, it is easier for hotels to excite the consumer today with vivid websites that show luxurious amenities at the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&#34;&gt;although their contents may have shifted&lt;/a&gt;, people are still consumed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/&#34;&gt;products that provide personal benefit&lt;/a&gt;, and travel, because even now commercials, computer and phone advertisements everywhere consist of these things, similarly to that of Egypt in 1907. In Alexandria it seems that just like in 2018, trying to get the daily news comes with an unexpected bombardment of advertisements that we love to hate, but hate to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to look more into advertising and its impact in present day with technology and print, check out these links below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/technology-is-radically-changing-the-advertising-business--and-the-consequences-are-profound-2014-9&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; talks about how advertising is changing to target the consumer, which is interesting because specific advertisements from &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; were of interest to me, and are probably of interest to you, a concept this article explores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://businesstown.com/magazine-newspaper-direct-mail-advertising-still-work&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; focuses on the idea that print advertisement is in fact not dead, but actually extremely effective because our brains work in such a way that makes us better at memorizing print advertisements over digital ones. In terms of &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; this article highlights the effectiveness of the advertisement section to those who read the newspaper in Alexandria and how it could have bolstered consumer activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2017/08/15/10-years-on-the-iphones-impact-on-advertising/#355d49218fb7&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; analyzes the changes in advertising ten years after the release of the iPhone. When looking at the advertisements in &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the advertisements that we interact with in the present day, this article dissects this transition from them to now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Actor&#39;s Nightmare</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-northcutt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-northcutt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an actress myself, I understand the stress and nervousness that surrounds receiving a good review of your work.  If the critics don’t like me, will the show keep running? Will I lose my job? How can I ever become a star if I have a single, bad review? Unfortunately, for performer Sig. Battani of &lt;em&gt;Ernani&lt;/em&gt; at the Abbas Theatre, these questions may soon become a reality.  This dream-crushing review becomes a reality on the third page on the Monday issue of February 18, 1907.  At first, a reader may think that the critic is praising the actors for their work, as he says that “The fine old filibustering sentiment of “Ernani” seemed to please the performers, and more especially Sig. Arrighetti, who was in splendid form.  Sig. Lucenti was, as ever, delightful all through.”  For those actors, the fear of receiving a career-crushing review has still not come to fruition, &lt;strong&gt;yet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the review takes a turn for the worst as the critic states that “Sig. Battani is most disappointing this year to those who delighted in him during the summer.” The critic tries to lessen the blow to Sig. Battani’s self-esteem by saying that the performance may not have been as bad as the audience thought; perhaps he was sick from the weather or that his voice was changing from a lyric to strong tenor.  This might be because of Sig. Battani’s reputation. Since at least May of 1905, when he was first mentioned in our portion of the Egyptian Gazette, he has received tremendous reviews.  One critic even called him “the best tenor Cairo has had for years.” Unfortunately, the critic for &lt;em&gt;Ernani&lt;/em&gt; was not so complementary, as he did not hold back when he said, “It is a pity his acting is so poor. His manipulation of the dagger (and, indeed, all the death scene) was rather absurd.” Though showing the death of a character on stage is a challenging task, unfortunately for Sig. Battani, a death scene with a dagger cannot be falsified or exaggerated if it is to be believable for the audience.  As the star of the Abbas Theatre for many years, it is intriguing why his performance quality so suddenly dropped. Perhaps Sig. Battani could have redeemed himself by having more believable acting or a stronger voice throughout the rest of the performance. Alas, this is not the case.  For the amount of time that Sig. Battani most likely put into developing this role and his previous theatrical successes, this review is quite a shame.  Let’s hope that Sig. Battani’s future is not destroyed because of this one performance; otherwise, he will have stabbed his himself and his career in the back with his own dagger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cairo Visitor Gravely Injured</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the blog post I chose an article titled “Cairo Visitor Gravely Injured” from page 3 of the Thursday December 13 1906 issue. The article talks about an accident that occurred on the P. and O. express in France the Friday before where two passengers were injured, and I believe one of them died? It&#39;s not very clear and is not actually stated, but is implied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two passengers injured were Mr. and Mrs. Robert Hanna, who were visiting from Dublin. Mrs. Hanna was not seriously injured but it seems that Mr. Hanna was killed. The suspected death was caused by a piece of metal that crashed through the window. Apparently, they’re not sure how it really happened, either from a bridge or a part of the train which doesn’t really make sense because I would think if it came from the bridge it would cause more external damage versus internal like the part of the train would cause making it easier to pinpoint the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads me to question just how in-depth incidents were investigated at this time. Did they just quickly glance at the scene and decide on the circumstances surrounding it, or did they thoroughly investigate and try to find the actual cause. Interestingly enough there is a similar article that was found in &lt;em&gt;The London Times&lt;/em&gt; that follows up on the accident and says that Mr. Hanna was severely injured in the accident and died the next morning at the hospital. It gives a little bit more information about him saying he was 42 years old and was an engineer on an Indian Railway. It also says how his wife Mrs. Hannas condition has improved. While there isn&#39;t a happy ending, at least we are able to find a little bit more information on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death amongst the Egyptians</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-chapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-chapple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 16, 1906 there have been multiple reports if incidents of the Bubonique Plague and Typhoid Fever. Citizens are dying at an alarming rate and there has reportedly been an outbreak on a steamship that was set to sail to Ras-el-Tin. A first class domestic man by the name of R. Cole sailing on H.M.S Venus was suffering from symptoms of &amp;ldquo;interior fever&amp;rdquo; and was rushed to the hospital immediately after disembarking the ship. Mr. Cole tragically succumbed to his illness at 2.45am on October 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second case of typhoid fever occurred on board the Venus since her arrival of Egyptian waters. The first person to experience symptoms was Captain Eyre, who has since been rushed to a hospital in Port Said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week prior to October 15, there have been a report of 6 cases of the Bubonique Plague throughout the country of Egypt, 3 cases at Alexandria, 2 at Suez, and one in the Minieh district. This is alarming as 492 cases have been reported since the start of the year, and this is a large increase from the previous year of 1905 where 264 incidents had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English in the Courts</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ooten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ooten/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short article published on February 25th 1907 is about the first time that English was used as the judicial language in a court case. This is one of many language related events that occurred after the British took control of Egypt as an imperial power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Egypt, and Alexandria in particular, there are many different people speaking many different languages, this causes many conflicts throughout the years. This article shows that attempts were being made by the British to push their agenda ahead through the bureaucracy of Egypt and acquire power from both of the other powers competing for control of the territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the courts in Egypt are different than the ones we know today, European powers had already had a fair amount of influence on how the courts were set up and run. Based on this the British clearly already had a basic framework from which to build off of, and during their occupation only took further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite this it still took the British many years to reach the point of where they were able to get English. This allowance and then use of English in the judicial language of the court provides us with an interesting point of reference of just how long it took for Cromer to gain a modicum of control of this part of Egyptian society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be compared to other points of British influence to determine if the British were took a long time to get this far with only this issue or if this was a common time frame for how long it could take for an effort such as this one to come to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://digitalcommons.law.uga.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2283&amp;amp;context=gjicl&#34;&gt;http://digitalcommons.law.uga.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2283&amp;amp;context=gjicl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/British-Imperialism/&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/British-Imperialism/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Pills for Pale People</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of clickbait, tabloid papers, and fake news, it&#39;s still nice to see that we haven&#39;t changed a bit. This is a classic example of a snake oil salesmen at work. Dr. Williams&amp;rsquo; Pink Pills are said to cure Anaemia, Indigestion, Eczema, Rheumatism, Sciatica, St. Vitus’ Dance, Neuralgia, Nervous Disorders, Paralysis, and Locomotor Ataxy. Since the pills did have ferrous sulphate or just Iron sulphate, it would have an effect on the anemic. This however, is still a scam because the amount that was in his pink pills was much less than actual medicine and because of this, the pills were much weaker and were more expensive than just the regular iron pills doctors would usually prescribe. This is probably one of the only pills that are in song, while the song is a critique of commercialism in society, it was sung by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wu2V3TkHufA&#34;&gt;Benny Bell&lt;/a&gt;. Also something that intrigued me was that you can still &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springbokpharmacy.co.za/Product?product_id=354130&amp;amp;category_id=33098&#34;&gt;buy these pills&lt;/a&gt; online to cure basically anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more &lt;a href=&#34;https://diseasesofmodernlife.org/2016/11/29/pills-for-our-ills-dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34;&gt;elaborate backstory&lt;/a&gt; of the company and pills, as well as how they fared in Asian markets.
[Pink Pills](1907-05-20-p5 selection)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trend of snake oil pills being sold in The Egyptian Gazette is not a new one. Looking through other blog posts I saw a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Esteve-Medicine/&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; about &amp;ldquo;Doan&#39;s Backache Kidney Pills&amp;rdquo;. The man who used it was told he only had 3 months to live but after some pills, he made a miraculous recovery! Another post follows the same vein of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/baxter-Peruna/&#34;&gt;miraculous medicine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russia and her Army</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-cannon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-cannon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about seeing news sources from the time they were written is that you get a first-hand account about a potentially world affecting event. Such is the case of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;’s pieces on Russia and the potential for a revolution. Even though it will not come for a decade, a newspaper like the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was still able to see the potential fall of the tsars. This speaks to me for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one thing, it implies that this was both a solvable issue and one that had been building for decades. In fact, one of the reasons for the fall is directly mentioned in the writing as the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; states on August 9, 1906 that if the Tsar keeps the support of the army he can maintain power. We know the revolutions were as successful as they were because the army began to support the rebels and not the government. Another reason why this aspect interests me is that it shows a global interaction with large scale events, as these were not just things that happened in a bubble. While I went in with expectations that there might be some conflict that hints at World War 1, seeing fears about a Russian Revolution was not expected and yet seems like something that should have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/analysis/2017/muniz-analysis&#34;&gt;analysis on the Russian Revolution&lt;/a&gt;, Anthony Muniz determined that there were four main causes of Revolution which were the social structure of the Russian classes, poor land for the peasants to manage the economy that was having trouble, and dissatisfied nobles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bad Guys</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The article I decided to write my blog post on was about Russian Terrorism in Alexandria. I found this article on page 3 of the Tuesday edition of January 23, 1907. I chose this article because of how interesting the topic was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article talks about how the Russian Consulate in Alexandria had reason to believe that three individuals were contemplating undergoing the task of causing harm to public security. The article explains that these three terrorists had sympathy towards the Russian revolutionary parties causing them to want to strike terror into the autocracy. The terrorists were caught due to the police receiving a warning and keeping a close eye on the small group of menacing men. The men had begun to purchase metals and chemical products that were normally used by private manufacturing companies in order to make high explosives. These suspicions were confirmed when the Captain of a Russian Steamer received a letter from the leader of the terrorist group asking the captain for 5,000 roubles to the boatswain of his vessel to be paid to the Russian Revolutionary Society of Alexandria, and if he failed to do so he would be killed and his ship destroyed. This lead to the three men being arrested and a search by the police found incriminating documents and materials for explosives. Their plan was to put the explosives in the engines of the Russian steamer. These explosives had a two-hour timer set to explode once the steamer had left port. This article was interesting because it shows how Alexandria was affected from the outside world other than just interference from England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=U_SU7fxj9BMC&amp;amp;pg=PA363&amp;amp;lpg=PA363&amp;amp;dq=alexandra+russian+terrorism+1907&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=KjOWTaG_SE&amp;amp;sig=dPOw1UdMd_hMMKFJltQGdvOQAe0&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjFjIvBt9XZAhUFtlkKHaLRCqEQ6AEIQzAC#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=alexandra%20russian%20terrorism%201907&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;https://books.google.com/books?id=U_SU7fxj9BMC&amp;amp;pg=PA363&amp;amp;lpg=PA363&amp;amp;dq=alexandra+russian+terrorism+1907&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=KjOWTaG_SE&amp;amp;sig=dPOw1UdMd_hMMKFJltQGdvOQAe0&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjFjIvBt9XZAhUFtlkKHaLRCqEQ6AEIQzAC#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=alexandra%20russian%20terrorism%201907&amp;amp;f=false&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.historyhome.co.uk/europe/russia1.htm&#34;&gt;historyhome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marxists.org/subject/arab-world/lutsky/ch18.htm&#34;&gt;marxists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/&#34;&gt;Russian Anarchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Chatham-Explosion/&#34;&gt;Chatham Explosion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cotton Industry</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-medina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-medina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The article “Cotton Industry in Lancashire” in the June 24, 1907 issue caught my attention since it shows how a textile that we use today, such as cotton, was used over a century ago. This article discusses how there was a surge in the production of raw cotton and how the industry of yarn weavers was able to handle this situation. In a brief statement – the weavers could not handle the overwhelming amounts of raw cotton being produced and had to cut manufacturing for a few weeks at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;medina-article.png&#34; alt=&#34;Article images&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to the up-rise of the spinning industry for cotton since the method was much more advanced and faster than the weaving method for goods. The cotton industry was being taken over by the newly found cotton industry in America causing an offset in production and quantity of raw cotton in Egypt and Lancashire at the time and in an imbalance in the financial markets. This can be known as &amp;ldquo;War Capitalism&amp;rdquo; a movement where developed nations were taking the crops and markets of smaller nations such as Egypt during this time and doubling their market. There is a great concern for how other markets such as those in America and Europe will impact the growth of the Egyptian cotton market through the West African slave trade, since cotton is Egypt&#39;s number one crop. This led to Egypt selling off a fertile land to large estates to make every available land crops for cotton. By the 1900s, Egypt&#39;s land was made up of 40% of cotton crops. In 1907, Egypt&#39;s cotton crops were thriving and competing internationally with America and England with this textile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the cotton industry is still important in America and is still increasing as one of the top textiles produced in America. In Egypt, the cotton industry is still as prosperous yet unreliable due to wavering points of success and crises in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indiana.edu/~caepr/Conferences/Wicker/Testing%20the%20Noyes%20Hypothesis_IU%20Oct%2024%202014.pdf&#34;&gt;Was the Panic of 1907 a Crisis?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncto.org/2017-state-of-the-u-s-textile-industry/&#34;&gt;State of The U.S. Textile Industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/egypt-cotton/egypt-aims-to-double-its-high-quality-cotton-production-and-export-idUSL8N1JZ0K9&#34;&gt;Egypt Aims to Double Its High-Quality Cotton Production&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history.ac.uk/reviews/review/1873&#34;&gt;Empire of Cotton Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Egyptian - His Manners and Morals</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ebert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ebert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this interesting article on page three of my Tuesday issue. It regards the safety of women who have to pass through the streets in front of the Arab trading shops. The author of the article is defending Europeans and claiming that the Arabic tradesman are the ones who are verbally harassing and potentially molesting these women. The author states &amp;ldquo;ladies who understand Arabic are lucky if they can pass in front of certain cafes, etc., situated in the most respectable quarters of Cairo, without hearing the most atrocious comments&amp;rdquo;(Gael). What I found most interesting about this article was that it was not the poor, lower-class servants and such who were doing this harassing, but rather the upper-class men who &amp;ldquo;possessed some means of education.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, women&#39;s safety has not improved much in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/roger-friedland/sexual-violence-and-the-egyptian-revolution_b_2658500.html&#34;&gt;modern times&lt;/a&gt;. Since this article made women seem so helpless, I looked up &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/1198/57e71816b48979e2f4bc74dee9fccf0b85dd.pdf&#34;&gt;women&#39;s rights in 1906&lt;/a&gt; and found that this was actually a very important time for women&#39;s rights. During this time, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arabwomenwriters.com/index.php/2014-05-03-16-01-55/n/nabaweya-musa&#34;&gt;Nabawiya Musa&lt;/a&gt; pioneered the movement for women&#39;s education. She was the first Egyptian girl to have a high school education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some links to related articles from classmates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/&#34;&gt;women are always lying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34;&gt;wife murder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train on Fire</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-clark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-clark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the issue of Monday, October 22, 1906 in the Egyptian Gazette there was a short article on page three written about an express train, heading from Luxor to Cairo, that caught on fire due to an exploding lamp in one of the first-class cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article gathered my attention for several reasons, the first of which being the words fire and exploding lamp. The only other blog post with an explosion was larger scale, but it was done on purpose. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Chatham-Explosion/&#34;&gt;Read more about this military-style explosion&lt;/a&gt;. Lamps actually exploded fairly often in 1906 because electricity was fairly new and the light bulbs must not have been built properly. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thespruce.com/light-bulb-failure-and-heres-why-1152457&#34;&gt;Read more about the quality of light bulbs in the early 1900s&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently to deal with this burning train car, the best plan of attack was to detach it from the rest of the train and send villagers to put out the fire, which makes sense so as to not allow the fire to spread all around the train, but what about the people inside the car that was on fire?? This brings me to my last point of curiosity, which is certain members of the crew that helped put out the fire. According to the paper “Three Italians distinguished themselves by the coolness and the effectiveness with which they worked.” This just proves that Italians must’ve been cool all throughout history and still are to this day because I’m just imagining three big guys with slicked back hair in suits named Tony communicating wonderfully with each other and the other villagers to put out this train fire. This brings to mind a different blog post about close knit communities in Egypt, because the community of Kift must&#39;ve been close with one another to put out this random train fire. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/barrett-curiosities/&#34;&gt;Read more about the togetherness of the Egyptian community&lt;/a&gt;. The article concludes with the fact that there were no injuries in this fire, which is pretty miraculous considering the assumed lack of experience among the villagers who worked to put out the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, flaming trains are not a thing of the past in Egypt. In the early 2000s a train caught fire due to an illegal use of a gas stove. The passengers of this train weren&#39;t so lucky as there were at least 373 confirmed deaths. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2002/feb/21/brianwhitaker&#34;&gt;Read more about recent train disasters in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggos</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 18th, 1907, Tuesday&#39;s issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was released to the public. In this issue of the newspaper, on the fourth page, under the section labeled &amp;ldquo;Letter to the Editor,&amp;rdquo; a person wrote to the editor about his / her referring to Canis Major&#39;s recent letter. The letter written by Canis Major is posted in the newspaper above the Letter to the Editor – Police Dog Service. Canis Major’s letter discussed the treatment of dogs when getting closer to death. Major stated that “[he] thinks that the matter should be looked into, and something should be done, to make the life of [the] dogs, during the time they wait for death, less painful for them.” In response to Canis Major’s letter, a “Lover of Animals” commented how a friend of theirs dog suffered from a disease “contracted in the black hole of Boulac.” The animal suffered through death, and the person who responded to Canis Major’s letter wanted to make a statement agreeing with him, that dogs should be treated better in their last days and minutes. Having this section, “Letters to the Editor,” allows the public to develop their thoughts and issues about society to the newspaper. This gives them a chance to speak up. Even though, the newspaper most likely cannot put in submissions that will cause a riot, they still put in some that have a small amount of concern from the people which keeps everything well balanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing another search about dogs, not animals, there were only a few articles that came up about the cruelty in their treatment. While there are other blog posts about different animals and dogs, I saw no record of any with an emphasis on the treatment of dogs during their dying stages. Regarding the SPCA, I ran multiple xpath query’s and all were returned with no results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fashionable Wedding</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Captain Charlton, who is an Assistant Military Secretary to the Sirdar, married Gwendoline Whitaker. Her gown was white lace and chiffon and had a white satin Court train, she wore a tulle veil and a wreath of orange blossoms and myrtle. A dress made of those same materials today is worth at least $400 depending on the style. If the dress cost $400 dollars it would convert to 7,045 Egyptian Pounds. While doing some research I found out that Princess Royal Victoria also wore a wreath of orange blossoms and myrtle in 1858. It was very popular in the 1800’s, Princess Alexandra of Denmark, Princess Helena and Princess Alice also wore one in their wedding. She also had a diamond crescent and bow brooch with aquamarine and pearl pendant. These were also very popular accessories in the mid 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bing.com/images/search?view=detailV2&amp;amp;ccid=o1JVy6nb&amp;amp;id=2DC4DFF61BAAA7C9A676BBFF9FD411BF44DB20EA&amp;amp;thid=OIP.o1JVy6nb9_yxKv5ZWPUsdQEsCd&amp;amp;mediaurl=https%3a%2f%2fs-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com%2f600x315%2f57%2f9f%2ff8%2f579ff83cdb915c6d4d994d3825a3d528.jpg&amp;amp;exph=315&amp;amp;expw=600&amp;amp;q=head+wreaths+of+orange+blossom+and+myrtle&amp;amp;simid=608047855234908659&amp;amp;selectedIndex=8&#34; alt=&#34;Wreath of Orangle Blossom and Myrtle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Critiques</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pierre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pierre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The critique speaks about everyone who performed at the Khedival Opera House on the night that Madame Maud Valerie
played at after the different musicians played and sung. He seemed to have been against the common use of repetition
in the ways that are shown by the artists and foreign composers at the time. The mistakes seen from a single musician
was said to be made much more obvious with the musical part that she chose to sing. The next person was a singer from
the Abbis Theatre, who was in the place of another performer, he did rather well, although the tone in his voice was
not as strong with its depth and tone. The next performer was a lady who sung the Tschaikowski, doing quite well the
audience desired one more performance, so she chose to perform Rubinstein&#39;s Romance in E-Flat. The man who performed
directly after her Saillards Bach Allegro, this was bad decision due to the level of passion he used to sing it - not
a great amount of passion - as it caused the audience to feel un-intrigued and uninterested. The incredible Madame Maud
Valerie began to play the piano and performed two pieces in an outstanding form, showing that she was a true musician
and well known by the audiences and the critique.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The More Things Change</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-arenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-arenas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-more-things-change&#34;&gt;The More Things Change&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-more-they-stay-the-same&#34;&gt;The more they stay the same&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing new about racism or xenophobia, and it should be unsurprising, even expected, to find examples of orientalism in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/British-Imperialism/&#34;&gt;imperial newspaper&lt;/a&gt; aimed at colonial agents. What is surprising, and as an immigrant, more than a little upsetting, was reading a quoted article from &amp;ldquo;Home Counties Magasine&amp;rdquo; bemoaning the supposed death of the neighborhood of Whitechapel in East-end. The language used is frightfully familiar. &amp;ldquo;Extreme poverty is perhaps the most striking characteristic of this community&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; The unnamed writer goes on to describe just how &amp;ldquo;the typical alien in his English career&amp;rdquo; establishes himself. He finds a cheap room where he sleeps with his entire family and where he &amp;ldquo;plies his trade.&amp;rdquo; Expanding his business he recruits fellow immigrants, and they &amp;ldquo;dexterously avoid the eye of the law.&amp;rdquo; Ultimately, this faceless alien creates and propagates a nasty system of poverty, crime, and misery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This viciously dehumanizing view of immigrants stands in bewildering contrast to other articles the Egyptian Gazette publishes observing native Egyptians daily. There is almost a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/abduh/&#34;&gt;respect&lt;/a&gt; given to some members of the Muslim community and the next day there is an article welcoming the construction of a Mosque in London!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1905-07-19-BlogImgMosque.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mosque&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that Great Britain had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/24427043?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=edwardian&amp;amp;searchText=racism&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3Facc%3Don%26amp%3Bwc%3Don%26amp%3BQuery%3Dedwardian%2Bracism%26amp%3Bfc%3Doff%26amp%3Bgroup%3Dnone&amp;amp;refreqid=search%3A755db30b4d0fb767b2f49b3c6b757e39&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; of Anti-Semitism in this era that also saw the Dreyfus affair and the proliferation of biological racism that further dehumanized non-white groups. Oscar Slater, for example, was a British Jew living in Glasgow in 1908, and like Dreyfus was wrongfully convicted of a crime he did not commit, in this case the murder of a white British woman. I can only hazard a guess as to why such a heinously racist view of Jewish immigrants in Whitechapel can coexist with the apparent celebration of Muslim culture. The closest I can understand is the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/25691223?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=edwardian&amp;amp;searchText=racism&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3Facc%3Don%26amp%3Bwc%3Don%26amp%3BQuery%3Dedwardian%2Bracism%26amp%3Bfc%3Doff%26amp%3Bgroup%3Dnone&amp;amp;refreqid=search%3A755db30b4d0fb767b2f49b3c6b757e39&amp;amp;seq=5#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;defensive imperialism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; Historian Eric Adler in an article in the &lt;em&gt;International Journal of the Classical Tradition&lt;/em&gt; posits that Late-Victorian/Edwardian imperialists sought to define the British empire in terms with which they could compare it to the Roman empire. Unlike the Romans, Adler posits that a popular refrain of British imperialism was that they effectively sought to &amp;ldquo;protect&amp;rdquo; themselves by expanding. As subjects of British rule, Muslim Egyptians are thus &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; so long as they stay in their separate sphere, since they are not &amp;ldquo;intruding&amp;rdquo; into British space, unlike the Eastern European Jews that are immigrating to Whitechapel. The whole point of empire, other than enrichment, is to protect the colonial nation from the subjects of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; empires when they &amp;ldquo;invade&amp;rdquo; (I cannot stress the quotation marks there enough) home. The new Eastern European Jewish community therefore turns the idea of Empire on its head.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Execution</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-squires/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-squires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; shows that &lt;strong&gt;Double executions&lt;/strong&gt; took place in the early 1900s, especially for murder. In this short article, the two murderers jointly murdered Ibrahim Khalif and in return were hung four months later at the prison. Both men claimed they were wrongly convicted of the crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result for double execution showed up only within two articles of &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; including on July 7, 1905 and within my issue in 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of double executions has pretty much diminished in many nations. In Egypt, they still perform &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_punishment_in_Egypt&#34;&gt;hanging executions&lt;/a&gt;, but since each convict has to go before a jury, double executions haven&#39;t taken place for awhile. In the U.S. Arkansas was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/04/24/525385016/arkansas-prepares-for-first-double-execution-in-u-s-since-2000&#34;&gt;last state to have performed a double execution&lt;/a&gt; which was a few hours apart and for different crimes. These &amp;ldquo;double executions&amp;rdquo; are different than what Alexandria would have done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Hungry</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all going to die.  I am so sorry I had to be the one to break the news, but someone had to. Have you ever thought about your funeral? How you want to die? Or if you want to be buried alone? What if I told you no one in Ancient Egypt was buried alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I am telling you that and it is true. In A.R. William&#39;s “Packing Food for the Hereafter in Ancient Egypt” article she says “Each had spent years preparing a lavish tomb stocked with everything they might need or want in the afterlife, including food, preserved for eternity.” Your death is just as important as our life so one should be prepared for it and they did. W. St Chad Boscawen &lt;a href=&#34;http://theplate.nationalgeographic.com/2015/04/05/packing-food-for-the-hereafter-in-ancient-egypt/&#34;&gt;found that ancient Egyptians were buried with food&lt;/a&gt;. Yay, you won’t spend eternity hungry! This food was found in vases or food dishes and there is a fine collection of food from vegetable matter to bread, fish or even fresh water crustacean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what you are thinking, what if you get thirsty? Have no fear if you are lucky enough in “the temeros” where your body is placed there is a round hole in the middle that contains a drain where offering of beer or wine could be made. Your party doesn’t have to stop because you are dead. In fact in an article written by Patrick J. Kiger called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel.nationalgeographic.com/the-story-of-god-with-morgan-freeman/articles/ancient-egyptian-tombs-and-death-rituals/&#34;&gt;Ancient Egyptian Tombs and Death Rituals&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; it says “Egyptian funerals also were elaborate. The body was placed in a coffin and transported to the tomb in a cart pulled by oxen. It was accompanied by a procession that included relatives, priests and priestesses, along with dancers, and musicians.” &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history.com/topics/tombs&#34;&gt;History.com&lt;/a&gt; says “The original purpose of a tomb was to protect the dead and provide the deceased with a dwelling equipped with necessities for the afterlife.” I really think it was Egypt’s way to send respect and keep the party of life going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it easier now to accept the inevitable? At least you won’t be hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rain in the Desert</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-06-frazier-raininthedesert-jordan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-06-frazier-raininthedesert-jordan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People often think of the Nile River as one of the most fertile places in the world. As a result, many colonies and cities sprouted up. Historically, humans tend to colonize towards large bodies of fresh water such as rivers or lakes because it is essential for life. However, a desert doesn&#39;t seem like a great location to live or get a good supply of fresh water. Alexandria, Egypt is one of those exceptions. On May 30th, 1906, according to their Daily Weather Reports, Alexandria received 0.05 rainfall. It started off with a change in the wind direction from East to West, and the air became very electric. Vivid lightning strikes lit up the sky as thunder came booming in and the clouds began precipitating. While it may not be much, it still rained in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rain is not a phenomenon many people are too pleased with; however, rain brings much more benefits, especially in the desert than some may think. With rainfall, there tends to be a decrease in the high temperature, an increase in the low temperature, cool winds, as well as an increased chance of the Nile flooding in the future. While flooding certainly does not sound good for most, in Alexandria, Egypt, when the Nile floods, it fertilizes the land making it ideal for growing crops. The more floods there are, the more fertile the land is; therefore, the more food that can be grow. Maybe living in the desert is not a bad idea after all. Besides, living in Florida heat has given me an advantage!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maxim Gorki</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-05-chacon-gorki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-05-chacon-gorki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something that has caught my eye while reading these articles from March 1905 to April 1905 is that on the first issue on the third day, there is a small article about a man by the name of Maxim Gorki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says he is to be prosecuted because charges have been given to him that he drafted proclamations aiming to overthrow the existing state of the Empire. It also says his health has broken down and that he is liable to three years of detention in a fortress. It also then gives the day of the trial. Gorki is said to be in a place called Riga and is under surveillance. I find this curious because I would like to know more information on this matter. I would also like to know how the trial ended up. I also find it curious because it is such a small article about this man&#39;s prosecution. I would think it would be longer. I would also like to know about the place, Riga, that he is in and if he is such a dangerous criminal that he has to be under surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey That&#39;s My Good Arm!</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-03-muniz-thats-my-good-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-03-muniz-thats-my-good-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember that crappy day you had, like yesterday? or how about the time you lost your phone for an hour? Those were horrible times, but at least you didn&#39;t lose your favorite arm like Baron London Bavastro de Cortazzi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;muniz-Barons-Arm.png&#34; alt=&#34;Newspaper Head&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started over a dispute over an allegedly unpaid bill at a hotel while in the United States. He had gotten into an argument with the proprietor of the Grayson Hotel and in anger he barged out and forgot his arm in a trunk that he had left. Realizing his mistake he went into the hotel and tried to retrieve it, only to get arrested (damn Americans). Now you&#39;re thinking that it&#39;s only just an arm, I mean what does an arm really do, but you don&#39;t understand how pristine this arm is. It is described by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; as &amp;ldquo;Probably no better left arm can be found in this country than the one which the Baron had. It is almost human, although it is made of papier maché, aluminium, steel and wax.&amp;rdquo; They also state the usefulness saying, &amp;ldquo;The hand of it could twirl a cigarette, write checks and carry a cane&amp;rdquo;. That is the equivalent of losing an Iphone 7! Not only does the baron have to deal with his lost arm, his arrest, but he also has to deal with being a witness to the death of one his friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with all of this the newspaper seems to be mocking Baron de Cortazzi, they take the upmost pleasure in using puns to describe his ordeal, &amp;ldquo;His heart is in Egypt&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;he declares that his neck has felt the heel of the oppressor&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;through various legal complications he has nearly lost his head&amp;rdquo;. Talk about a crappy day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on a serious note who is Baron Cortazzi? Baron Cortazzi was a man who was testifying about a murder that happened to Mrs. Blanche Turner Dennis. His dad apparently owned estates in Egypt and was friends with Arlbett Sackey. His dad must have known some important people because he met Sackey through an unnamed high official in Egypt. He stated that Mrs. Blanche Turner Dennis was Sackey&#39;s fiancée. Baron Cortazzi said that Sackey beat her once and that she may have died from that beating. No other reports could be found of Baron Cortazzi even through x-path query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that Sackey denied any role in Mrs. Dennis&amp;rsquo; death and that someone else was accused of her murder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madame Butterfly: A Metamorphosis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-01-ali-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-01-ali-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lights dim and slowly, the onlooking crowd goes quiet with growing anticipation. The excitable people among the bunch murmur about their excitement to see Signora Pandolfini for their first time as they prepare to hear her sing a soft melody. The people gushing with anticipation hurriedly tell them to shush as they do not want to miss the moment her voice first chirps. The curtains open and just as fast, the tale begins. It’s poetry in motion… sort of. If the crowd’s reaction was anything to go off, Pandolfini really missed the mark on the first act of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.musicwithease.com/puccini-butterfly-story.html&#34;&gt;Madame Butterfly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,a relatively well-known play back in the early 1900s and even now. Back in the early 1900s, the performance had been making the rounds across America and Europe, and it soon found a troop to replicate its excellence in Egypt&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cairoopera.org/history.php?lan=En&#34;&gt;Khedivial Opera House&lt;/a&gt; … for the most part at least. Pandolfini managed to win the crowd over in acts two and three, but the long-awaited play certainly had more than one mishap. While the symphonies played were engaging, many critics said that it left no real impression. This does not equate to bad though, as these same critics believed that the play was truly worthy of playing in the Khedival Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;source-of-interest&#34;&gt;Source of Interest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached here is the act by act synopsis of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.columbia.edu/itc/music/NYCO/butterfly/synopsis.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madame
Butterfly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;MadameB2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;visualization&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Are Always Lying?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-27-doring-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-27-doring-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While finishing the Tuesday edition of my week, I came across an article titled “Women and Lying.” This article was not only random, but shocking in how aggressive it felt. The article talked about how “women lie more constantly, laboriously, and cleverly than men, and in larger proportion.” The author of this article is very meticulous about describing how women lie. Not only does he mention how women lie through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vintagevictorian.com/costume_1905.html&#34;&gt;changing their appearances&lt;/a&gt;, but also how they lie through their feelings, their views, and their tastes. The author then goes onto describe how a woman will lie to alienate your feelings, convincing you to open up your “heavy gate” and walking right in.  It is concluded that the more a wife lies, the smoother the marriage goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was the article that stood out to me the most within my entire week. Not only was it aggressive, but it was very detailed in how, according to the author, women are very successful liars in almost every aspect of life. Without a doubt, reading this could teach you a lot about how women are viewed in the early 1900’s. It’s clear that women were not viewed as equals at this time and did not receive the respect that they had deserved. You can also learn from this the type of articles that were considered acceptable to write about in the paper when there was nothing else important to report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related blog post by MELIZZA BLACK: [“Avoid Female Society”](“Avoid Female Society”) Is this the female society that we are trying to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death of Haicalis Pasha</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-baenen-deathofthepasha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-baenen-deathofthepasha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When reading my week of the Egyptian Gazette, I came across the sad news of the Death of Haicalis Pasha. At first I didn’t know why it was so important but then continuing in the article published I could tell that Egypt lost an important life in the European Press of Egypt. He was known as the “Doyen of the Local Press” which means “the most prominent and respected person in a particular field”.  This got me interested in this man’s life and accomplishments so I started to do some research on him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haicalis earned a Doctorate of Law, was on many Governmental Administrations, was the one who persuaded Mr. Cook, the owner of Thos. Cook &amp;amp; Son tourist agency, an agency which if you have worked with the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; I’m sure you have heard of, to come to Egypt to start his business. In my own opinion, his most important accomplishment was that he was a founder and the Editor of a newspaper called &lt;em&gt;Phare d’Alexadrie&lt;/em&gt;. This paper was known for its “journalistic decency” and not blackmailing individuals, providing readers with just news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was honored in many countries for his work, receiving things like the Legion of Honor, the Order of the Crown of Italy, and many other decorations/honors. He was an important figure in the journalist community and impacted how European Press was constructed in delivering news from Egypt and inversely impacted the Egyptian Gazette.  Even though this doesn’t impact everyday life ultimately in Egypt it still is a very saddening passing of someone who made positive changes to many things in the world. This article gives me more connection to the Egyptian Gazette and makes you realize how much is going on around the world that isn’t reported on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-migdalski-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-migdalski-plague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this short newspaper article on the third page of the first day of my issue, the topic was about a plague outbreak that had numerous cases throughout Egypt. Victims of the plague had been reported dead in a number of villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article states some, but not all, of the cases were said to be pneumonic, which means it affected the lungs. This creates a curiosity for me. If only the majority of the deaths were caused by pneumonia, I wonder if all of the people who died, were infected by the same disease.  I am also curious if the disease affected different people in different ways. The article explicitly states that they deemed this plague to be contracted through direct contact. I am curious as to the origins of this plague and the characteristics and symptoms of it as well. I searched for outside information regarding this plague and &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=r_YDAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA3&amp;amp;lpg=PA3&amp;amp;dq=plague+in+egypt+1906&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=HqzdiEyewX&amp;amp;sig=7Ev85udX7QZKFaTyZEzkBb7ZukY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjD79H4pMLSAhXEOSYKHcjnDo4Q6AEIIjAB#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=plague%20in%20egypt%201906&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;explains that this plague had affected other countries as well such as India, South America, and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the article talks about improvements made in a village where numerous cases of the plague occurred as well as providing treatment to one infected patient that led to their cure. This proves that the medical professionals of Egypt were able to identify the disease and develop a treatment that helped cure at least one patient. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ancient.eu/article/51/&#34;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; explains how diseases were treated in ancient Egypt. People were still exposed to similar diseases that are found today, however, their treatment methods were much different. They used medicines and &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; which referred to asking the gods for treatment. They also made their own medical remedies, many of which contained beer which was believed to have powerful curing effects. I am interested to know how they treated and cured the single patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, medical practices in ancient Egypt have a lasting effect on present methods. Through further research, &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorable.com/ancient-medicine&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; went into detail on how treatments in ancient Egypt influenced treatments used today. For example, ancient Egyptian professionals used various herbs to create medicines to cure diseases and sicknesses. Many of these same remedies are still used today. Ancient medical practices were more advanced than I presumed. There is evidence that Egyptian doctors performed eye surgery, dentistry, used prosthetics, healed broken bones, and more. Many of their treatment and healing methods were published in books that are still being preserved today. It is interesting that medical practices used in ancient times are still being used in one way or another in modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of my classmates and students in the past also inquired questions regarding the plague. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/rymer-plague/&#34;&gt;One student&lt;/a&gt; was also curious to know more about the plague, its origins, symptoms, and treatment. I searched through various blog posts that were written on the plague and noticed a trend. Multiple students were wondering why there was not much information on the plague. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/&#34;&gt;This student&lt;/a&gt; wrote about the small number of reports that were made about the plague. In my issue there was only one small article hidden on the third page. This makes me question how serious the disease was at the time and if it was something that either was not a major threat or if it was being hidden from the public. This is something I hope to learn more about as I continue working with my week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to go through my week in this newspaper, I hope to find more information about this plague. I wonder if the number of deaths will decreases and if a fully effective cure is developed to prevent further infections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6,000 Birds Found Dead</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-14-fitzpatrick-post-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-14-fitzpatrick-post-birds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a morbidly funny article when reading through my week of the Egyptian Gazette. The title, &amp;ldquo;FATE OF 6,000 BIRDS&amp;rdquo; and to summarize the article briefly, after two nights of thick fog, nearly 6,000 birds were found dead under a lighthouse. They were attracted to the light in the fog and flew right against it. (The full article can be found in Page 4 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.rawgit.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/master/1905-12-18.xml&#34;&gt;Monday, December 18, 1905&lt;/a&gt; issue of the Egyptian Gazette.) Not much else is mentioned in the article, it is a rather brief memorial. This struck me as being a unique article so I decided to share it. I did a quick search on the location of the lighthouse, &amp;ldquo;Cape Grisnez&amp;rdquo; and turns out this story takes place in France! Cape Grisnez is in northern France between Wissant and Audresselles. The cape held place to a naval battle during the Napoleonic Wars in 1805, and also would play a historical role in World War II. The lighthouse was built in 1837, originally standing 46 feet tall. In 1861, the lighthouse was raised to 79 feet tall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading articles from the past makes the research more interesting, you read it from the perspective of the time frame it was written, but when investigating further you get a full picture that spans past the newspaper and through to present day. It just struck me funny how such a odd story could make international news, though granted the Egyptian
Gazette was sold to an audience of mainly Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lighthousedigest.com/digest/database/uniquelighthouse.cfm?value=5327&#34;&gt;Lighthouse Digest, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.francethisway.com/places/cap-gris-blanc-nez.php&#34;&gt;France This Way, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unc.edu/~rowlett/lighthouse/fran.htm&#34;&gt;University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Lighthouses of France, North Coast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pe-ru-na</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-14-bolton-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-14-bolton-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; on March 15, 1905 there was a man named Mr. Isaac Brock, and he was 115 years old and claiming to be the oldest man in America.  Mr. Brock lived in McLennan County, Texas, and he accredited his old age of the use of a medicine called “Pe-ru-na.” The article lists facts about Mr. Brock’s life including “born before the United States was formed, saw 22 Presidents elected, shod a horse when 99 years old.” People were so mesmerized by the extent of Mr. Brock’s age that he even wrote a “lengthy biographical sketch,” and he was written about in the &lt;em&gt;Dallas Morning News&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Chicago-Times&lt;/em&gt;.  Mr. Brock claims that Peruna protects him from sudden changes, and it is the greatest remedy for adapting to changes and the age of “catarrhal disease.”  Catarrhal diseases are what we call now Bronchitis or an excess of mucus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peruna was invented by Dr. Samuel Brubaker Hartman who actually preferred the name PE-RU-NA. After researching to find out what PE-RU-NA actually is, I found that it is a tonic that contains 18% alcohol.  It became popular after prohibition, when states went “dry” and banned all alcohol. It was still able to be sold over the counter, and became very popular that is was referred to as the “Prohibition Tonic.” It was so popular that people even named their children after it, and Southern Methodist University named their mascot of a black mustang horse Peruna.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is anarchy important in British Egypt?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-11-ortiz-russian-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-11-ortiz-russian-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the telegraphs, a man by the name of Matteo Moral, a known Anarchist, attempted to assassinate King Alfonso of Spain with a bomb. After being confronted by a police officer, Moral killed the officer. Shortly after, to evade capture, he committed suicide by shooting himself through the heart. Alongside Moral, an English tourist named Hamilton was also arrested under the charges of being an anarchist. The article does not state any more details about Hamilton&#39;s arrest other than the Spanish authority refused to release him to the British.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/Russian-Anarchy.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Russian Anarchy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that the assassination attempt happened in Spain but it is being reported on by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in British Egypt. Why is anarchist activity important to the British? Before communism was the boogeyman of Europe, anarchism seemed to be the ideology that was branded the enemy of the state. A year prior to this assassination attempt, the Russian state was under threat of &amp;ldquo;anarchy&amp;rdquo; during the Russo-Japanese War. That was also reported by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in an article called &amp;ldquo;IS IT PEACE&amp;rdquo; which can be located in the June 1, 1906 edition on page two. Anarchism was an ideology that threatened the state was a whole. In an age where the state extended its power through colonial empires, anarchism threatened to dismantle the colonial system by weakening the state. To Great Britain, tracking anarchist activities of competing empires is important because it is a way to evaluate how strong the enemy central state is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more general information and history on anarchism as an ideology, feel free to read Noam Chomsky&#39;s article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://inthesetimes.com/article/16081/a_history_of_anarchism/&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Anarchism&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Anarchist-Arrested.png&#34; alt=&#34;Anarchist Arrested&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petra</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-08-fricano-petra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-08-fricano-petra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On page four of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.rawgit.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/master/1906-01-09.xml&#34;&gt;January 9th, 1906&lt;/a&gt; edition of The Egyptian Gazette I found an article title: Petra. The article is basically a summary of two authors, Dr. William Libbey and Dr. Franklin E. Hoskins, and their account of traveling through the area. In the article they labeled Petra “a city old as time itself” and made it clear that tourists were rarely welcomed until these two authors spent a surprising five days in the city without molestation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They described Petra as a rose red city that was in possession of some worthwhile monuments. Upon further research, I found images of the city that proved these claims to be true. I also found that the direct translation of Petra, from Greek to English, is ‘Rock’. It is a city that is surrounded by red stone, common to the geography of Jordan, and what makes the monuments worthwhile is that they carved into the red stone that comprises the area. These iconic monuments can be seen in Steven Spielberg’s &amp;ldquo;Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, my interest is not in the aesthetic of Petra, but rather the financial prosperity it offered in terms of its geography. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.petranationalfoundation.org/history.html&#34;&gt;national Petra foundation&lt;/a&gt;, Petra was ideally placed on what is known today as the The King’s Highway in Jordan. This is significant because the Highway lies on a natural fault line, which made the city easily found by traders. I would like to inquire what economic benefit Petra offered Egypt and its people in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##sources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside Links:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.robertfulford.com/petra.html&#34;&gt;http://www.robertfulford.com/petra.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smithsonianmag.com/lifelists/guarding-petra-11031077/&#34;&gt;http://www.smithsonianmag.com/lifelists/guarding-petra-11031077/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog Post Links:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/doublemurder/&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/doublemurder/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Egyptology/&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Egyptology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dishonesty: The Consistency of Politics</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-07-hammermaster-dishonesty-the-consistency-of-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-07-hammermaster-dishonesty-the-consistency-of-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People make careless remarks all the time, especially public figures who then regret what they said. Egyptian royalty in 1906 was no different. The Wednesday, January 31st issue devotes an entire column to the Princess Nazli to allow her to make a statement refuting a comment she had made the previous Saturday. This comment consisted of her saying Egyptians were babies and Lord Cromer &amp;ldquo;did everything.&amp;rdquo; The editor of &lt;em&gt;Al Mokattam&lt;/em&gt;, Dr. Nimr, jumped on this statement and asked the princess if she had adopted the French nationality instead. Princess Nazli then defends herself with the response that she has no desire to change her nationality, but still defends her words. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.revolvy.com/topic/Princess%20Nazli%20Fazl&amp;amp;item_type=topic&#34;&gt;She was a very educated woman, which was uncharacteristic of that society, who had good experience with other cultures&lt;/a&gt;, so she knew how to defend herself. She claims that the translation in the newspaper was correct and stands by what she says, praising Lord Cromer. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.egy.com/historica/queennazli.php&#34;&gt;Princess Nazli had a very involved family, many of whom were of different nationalities&lt;/a&gt;. Although she spends the beginning of her statement defending herself as an Ottoman subject, she seems to spend a lot of time talking about Lord Cromer and her father&#39;s influence, seemingly as a distracting tactic to get off topic. Toward the end of her statement, she revisits the original issue: what she claims as her nationality. Princess Nazli almost seems to attack her critics, asking a series of questions regarding why her nationality was being challenged. The politicians of today use all these same tactics. They make it seem like they address a question while really discussing something else, then turn the conversation around to make themselves look better. I find it fascinating that this trend has persisted throughout so many decades, possibly even multiple centuries. For me, it begs the question: Will politics ever be honest?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Khedive Spends His Time</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-04-ng-how-the-khedive-spends-his-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-04-ng-how-the-khedive-spends-his-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Gazette often features descriptions of the Khedive’s activities in its issues. On the 15th of May, 1906, in particular, it outlined the activities of the Khedive for the day as well as the rest of the summer. During the late 19th and early 20th centuries in Egypt, the Khedive was the reigning governor of the land, who carried out both the responsibilities of being in charge of Egypt as a nation as well as diplomacy with other nations, such as Turkey, with which there had been a recent crisis (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/00263209708701140&#34;&gt;Donald M. Mckale (1997) &amp;ldquo;Influence without power: the last Khedive of Egypt and the great powers, 1914–18,&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Middle Eastern Studies&lt;/em&gt; 33:1, 20-39&lt;/a&gt;). Known as the Ottoman Empire back then, Turkey played a huge role in how Egypt functioned. But an incident with the Sultan resulted in a cut in communications between the two nations. Communication between nations is crucial, as seen from the past and the present, and is paramount in resolving conflicts or delineating a nation’s state of being. However, the British soon took control of Egypt as a colony and also took it upon themselves to conquest Sudan as well &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.onwar.com/aced/chrono/c1800s/yr96/fsudan1896.htm&#34;&gt;(Winston S. Churchill, &lt;em&gt;The River War: An Historical Account of the Reconquest of the Soudan&lt;/em&gt; (1899)&lt;/a&gt;). Towards the year 1914 and the approach of World War I, Great Britain had decided to end the Khediviate rule of Egypt and establish the Sultanate of Egypt, which would culminate with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwi.lib.byu.edu/index.php/Treaty_of_Lausanne&#34;&gt;Treaty of Peace with Turkey Signed at Lausanne, July 24, 1923&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icilma</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-28-nunez-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-28-nunez-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To begin, the name Icilma came from combining the Arabic words ‘icil’ meaning flows and ‘mha’ meaning water.  It was Stephen Armitage who founded Icilma in 1898. He was a civil engineer who found the use in mineral water from a natural spring located in Algeria. Originally wanting to open a spa near the spring, Stephen was moving from city to city trying to sell this mineral water in any way possible. He moved from Algeria to Paris and later growing his product in London. Finally settling in London, he established the business “Nature’s Remedy Company” where he not only worked as a chemist, but also built the machinery that went on to create Icilma cream. Icilma cream then transitioned into Icilma Flour cream due to the Calcium fluoride present in the water. It was later known and advertised as ‘Nature’s Skin Food’. Not only did it heal and prevent blemishes, and blackheads, but it was also a great product for healing mosquito and insect bites as well. It was sold as both a face powder and a soap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading of Sentence</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-16-pearce-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-16-pearce-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the third or fourth pages always begin to get deep into the local news, including stories of crimes, births, deaths, and all sorts of events. One very historical event in Egypt took place around this time - the Denshiwai Affair. On June 26, 1906, a lot of the information being released showed how the criminal trial was beginning to unfold. The trial took place in the Denshiwai village inside of Chibin el Kom, Egypt. A bad attack occurred between rebels and officers of the police force. There was a lineup of prisoners and witnesses who could speak and defend themselves, fairly similar to that of a modern day court system. It&#39;s crazy to think how little the judicial system varies from country to country, especially over 100 years apart, when comparing it to the modern day American system. This seems almost similar to the current Black Lives Matter movements that have occurred across the United States in recent years, as police are being beaten and attacked along with people in the streets. It is interesting how closely history repeats itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday and Thursday, June 28 and 29, 1906, respectively, the final information was reviewed and the sentences were given. The death penalty is decided as one of the most level-headed punishments for the offenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sentence of death was passed on the four following prisoners:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hassan Mahfouz (11)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Youssef Hassan Salim (14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Said Issa Salim (25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mohamed Darwish Zahran (48).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different encounters were mentioned in the case such as the possibility of premeditation, along with the death of Captain Bull, supported by any medical evidence available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“AS the crowd prevented the Major and his two comrades from getting into carriages, pulled them about and beat them, throwing bricks and dry mud at them&amp;hellip;” I like this statement from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, as I think of it as a simile to the present-day life of a student in some ways. As a student myself, being overwhelmed with homework, exams, quizzes can really seem as if I was getting metaphorically beaten, having bricks and dry mud thrown at you. Of course, nobody should have to know the brutal beatings that Captain Bull, Lieutenant Smithwick, and Major Pine-Coffin, along with other innocent people had faced in this attack. All in all, this has been the most enjoyable part of the story of the attack at Denshiwai, as it used some very descriptive language, making it as easy as possible to see the brutal beatings that occurred on that day in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page 6 Disaster</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-10-horton-page6disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-10-horton-page6disaster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this class, I have been assigned the week of February 19, 1906. All in all, I have to say this has been one of absolute favorite classes. Not only have I learned to code and become what I like to call “tech savvy” but I am learning the everyday lives of individuals from not only the United Kingdom but from pretty much anywhere they associate with. When you think about it we are given Monday through Saturday editions of the newspaper to complete; that is a ton of work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every day’s edition, the page six usually consists of financial tables. This is by far the worse part of the “coding” aspect of the class. I mean, the class itself is very time consuming and tedious but using OCR really does help to speed the process up, but of course you cannot run financial tables through OCR. Not once, have I had an easy time just knocking out the page sixes. You might be thinking right now “I wonder what is so bad about the financial tables? You’re given the template, therefore all you need to do is change the actual information within it.” Well, you have successfully answered the question; building the template is the easy part, actually filling in the tables are the difficult part. Actually sitting down and attempting to read what the newspaper actually says the problematic part. Either the letters or numbers are so small that you cannot read it or (in most cases) the scans are extremely blurry in parts of the page. Majority of the time, even if I take smaller section scans of each page to get a clearer reading, it is still does not help. What I read as a three are sometimes an eight, or the “E” is actually a “D” or “B”.  The comparison happen for almost every letter and number, it is just really hard to decipher. Although, I have to say, as frustrating as the page sixes are… typing the last text for that page, sitting back and say “ah yes! Finally I finished!” It’s an extremely rewarding feeling and then I can actually look at the information I wrote down and compare it to other issues and today’s information such as the stocks and shares portion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it quite interesting that when reading reviews of the Cisdem OCR system, on the following websites listed below, everyone seems to praise the system. I mean the system is indeed great, but I come across a lot of errors that still need to be fixed after running it through the OCR. I guess I must be doing something then, but I will definitely be looking into this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cisdem.com/pdf-converter-ocr-mac/reviews.html&#34;&gt;https://www.cisdem.com/pdf-converter-ocr-mac/reviews.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macupdate.com/app/mac/52109/cisdem-pdfconverterocr&#34;&gt;https://www.macupdate.com/app/mac/52109/cisdem-pdfconverterocr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And maybe I am just very naïve, and have not really taken the time to really think about each of the financial tables&amp;rsquo; importance, but I just do not see why the public, whether the person is reading the paper in Great Britain or in Egypt, need to see a balance sheet for Egyptian investments. When you really think about it, that information can only be useful to someone who understands business, but not everyone reading the paper is “business savy.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Regatta Is a Boat Race.</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-08-ukah-a-regatta-is-a-boat-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-08-ukah-a-regatta-is-a-boat-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Gazette will occasionally feature a &amp;ldquo;Sport and Play.&amp;rdquo; section, usually containing scores from cricket games. For the majority of this week, though, the section featured a regatta hosted by the Khedival Yacht Club. Unlike cricket, a regatta is a series of boat races, so I initially found its placement in the newspaper odd, until reading this sub article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;KHEDIVAL2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Yachting in Alexandria&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yachting has apparently found an audience in Alexandria&#39;s sporting community, so much so that private owners with large money influences have begun to participate in races. (That is how I understand it at least.) I figured some additional research into these races was warranted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1907 &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;The Motor Boat: Devoted to All Types of Power Craft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 4, Issue 12, by Francis P. Prial pg. 43: Prial mentions the waters near Alexandria and in Egypt in general as &amp;ldquo;splendid facilities for motorboating&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and how these waters were not receiving enough attention from craft owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the central theme in this source is motorboats, not yachts, I feel the source warrants mentioning because ideal waters might be a reason for the success that yachting in Alexandria had seen, and because the author also speaks highly of the Khedival Yacht Club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1908 &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Encyclopaedia of Ships and Shipping&lt;/em&gt;, by Herbert B. Mason, pg. 328: A general definition of the Khedival Yacht Club: &amp;ldquo;Established 1902. Patron, H. H. the Khedive of Egypt ; Commodore, H.H. Prince Aziz Pacha Hassan&amp;hellip;Entrance fee, £3 ; annual subscription, £2.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the mention of an entrance fee, I assume that anyone could have participated in the regattas, and that the aforementioned private owners had the money to invest in elite crafts that could win races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1907 &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Fore&#39;n&#39;aft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 11, pg. 62: The Khedival Yacht Club is hailed as &amp;ldquo;the only important organization of its kind in Egypt&amp;hellip; and now has two hundred and thirty members and a fleet of fifty yachts. Weekly regattas are held in fort and numerous enjoyable social functions at the handsome club house.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, here are the results of the week in question&#39;s regatta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;KHEDIVAL3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Regatta Results&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ananke, a privately owned craft favored by the newspaper to win the race in its class, could not withstand the wind and waters that day, and had to forfeit the race.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of The Road Man</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-08-fajardo-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-08-fajardo-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a lover of fiction, I decided to pick a short story, named as &lt;em&gt;The Road Man&lt;/em&gt;, for this assignment. The story pertains to a young fellow who always noticed an &lt;strong&gt;elderly prophet&lt;/strong&gt; that always carries a hefty wheelbarrow. I was very amused to this piece because I notice many similarities between the prophet and your average college student. For instance, when the narrator mentions, “His skin, burnt almost black with sun and wind, his shaggy eyebrows and long white beard, suggest the prophets of ancient days”, reminded me of a college senior. As the prophet appears worn down from his exposure to the sun, one may compare that to how a senior appears exhausted, after years of sleep deprivation due to a tedious work load. Ironically, the narrator gave me the impression that he is a college freshman, because he is young and does not have the same years of experiences as the prophet. Many college freshman will not understand a college seniors’ desire to undertake a tedious task due to the lack of experience. However, as the years pass by, college freshmen will fulfill the seniors shoes, as the narrator will fill the prophet&#39;s shoes. I believe this passage is very significant since it is still relevant after being composed 115 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>212 Runs</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-212-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-212-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have never watched a game of cricket in my life, but I had always assumed it was somewhat similar to baseball. A reasonable assumption I would say, as it features the same general idea of guy throwing ball and other guy trying to hit ball. Just that the ball bounces and you are allowed to hit it backwards, apparently. Then I saw the phrase &amp;ldquo;Somerset beat Glousestershire by 212 runs&amp;rdquo;. Well that seems like a rather large number. I realized it was time for some detective work: was this simply a thorough butt-whooping like never seen before, or do the rules of cricket make this a reasonable margin of victory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=AqtpNkMvj5Y&#34;&gt;this short video&lt;/a&gt;, several revelations have been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs are much easier to come by than in baseball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home runs are 6 runs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doubles off the wall are 4 runs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 outs instead of 3 outs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Balls&amp;rdquo; count as a run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Balks&amp;rdquo; count as a run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First base is only 66 feet away as opposed to the usual 90.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singles are runs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games can potentially last up to 5 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well then. I guess losing by 212 runs isn&#39;t as bad as it seems. Still, a crushing loss for Glousestershire. Watch out for this Somerset squad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Man, One Horse</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-rodriguez-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-rodriguez-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Murders overall aren’t that common, so it was even more surprising when I found out that there was a murderous horse on the loose! On July 7, 1906, it was reported that a man sneaked into the yard of a resident. Even though his intentions were never discovered it is assumed by the article that his sole goal was to steal a horse. When in the process of untying the ropes of the animal, the horse kicked him square in the face, killing him instantly. This is one thief that never got a second chance. It makes me wonder if there are any other murderous animals in Alexandria, other than the everyday man. If it wasn’t for the horse killing him I believe the owner would have killed him if caught. I came to this conclusion after reading many articles having to do with thieves and criminals. Even if it wasn’t the owner the police would have surely caught him because according to the newspaper they have an excellent arrest rate. Yet the fate of this poor man was surely set the minute he decided to trespass on someone’s property. Upon reading this I am almost certain that thieves all over the city were either scared of stealing any more horses, or that they were just more careful when stealing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donkey Drivers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-barrett-donkey-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-barrett-donkey-drivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You see them on the horizon. Look down. Avoid Eye Contact. Do not acknowledge them. Fake a phone call. Start crying. Alas, your effort is futile. Whether you like it or not, the dreaded moment will come where you are clotheslined by an arm trying to get you to buy perfume from their kiosk in the middle of the mall. Turns out, this isn&#39;t just a modern day frustration - we&#39;ve been suffering worldwide for over 100 years, minimum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although 1905 Cairo didn&#39;t have an infestation of pushy perfume salesmen, they did have &amp;ldquo;donkey boys&amp;rdquo;. These guys would call after you, bothering you, insisting you use their donkeys to get to your next location. Our complainer who wrote the correspondent was offended they’d think he’d even consider taking anything but a cab. Donkey boys seem like our kiosk worker on steroids; the only thing that’s stopping the residents of Cairo from hitting them is the fact that there’s a police officer too close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution sought is to get a &lt;em&gt;shawish&lt;/em&gt; (meaning Police or Army Sergeant) to make a law against their badgering solicitation. As the complainer remarks, &amp;ldquo;“No reproof has any effect unless it be to bring a flow of filthy language”&amp;hellip; which might be the most British way to say “cussing them out is all that works!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H &amp; C Flick, Cigar Importers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-flick-h-c-flick-cigar-importers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-flick-h-c-flick-cigar-importers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egyptian_cigarette_industry#cite_note-5&#34;&gt;Egyptian cigarette industry&lt;/a&gt; was one of the main exports in Egypt during the time period from the 1880s to the end of the World War I. Just from reading one week of issues of the Egyptian Gazette, I could tell that cigarettes were a major part of an Egyptian’s life. There was at least one advertisement for cigarettes on each page of the newspaper, but one specific advertisement in particular stood out to me the most: “H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, Cigar Importers.” Now this specific ad might not sound important to anyone else, but to me it was very interesting and got me thinking about my ancestry. I am 99.9% sure that I am not related to these Flick’s, but I wonder what it would be like to be a Flick in Egypt in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, Egypt imported a total of 8,078 tonnes of tobacco and a total of 8,377 tonnes in 1906 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=qs_YlWuFjooC&amp;amp;lpg=PR3&amp;amp;pg=PA59#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;Relli Shechter, &lt;em&gt;Smoking, Culture and Economy in the Middle East: The Egyptian Tobacco Market 1850-2000&lt;/em&gt;, p. 59 &lt;/a&gt;). The advertisement states that H. &amp;amp; C. Flick was the largest depot of cigars in Egypt, so I can imagine that Flick’s were a very successful in 1906 due to the increase in cigar imports from 1905 to 1906.  Egyptian tobacco was usually very poorly made and didn’t taste very well, so most of the cigarettes in Egypt were not made from Egyptian tobacco (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/41339516?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES AND TOBACCO, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Society of Arts&lt;/em&gt; Vol. 59, No. 3034 (JANUARY 13, 1911), pp. 201-203&lt;/a&gt;). Due to Egyptian tobacco not being up to par with what most tourists and immigrants are used to, being a cigarette importer was probably a very good business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I might not actually be related to H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, I now know that it would probably be a good family business in Egypt in 1906, but it might be harder to be a cigar importer in the United States in 2017 due to all the information about how terrible cigarettes are for our health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related Blog Post by ALEX CALIENDO: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&#34;&gt;The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miraculous Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-baxter-peruna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Ida Caldwell, a seemingly sweet old lady, has been suffering with “catarrh of the respiratory organs on and off for the last three years”. She had to use her greatest care not to “expose herself to chilly air or dampness as it increased her troubles.” She was advised to change her climate, but she couldn’t leave her family so she had to stay put. Then she was introduced to Peruna which relieved her of her pain in three days, and she was completely cured in two months. What a miracle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post seemed like a serious article about a well-known woman who seemed to be in a lot of pain due to her &amp;ldquo;catarrh of her lungs.&amp;rdquo; However, when I kept reading, I noticed that it was just a gimmicky ad for a sketchy medicine that claimed to &amp;ldquo;cure symptoms of the common cold.&amp;rdquo; The ad seemed really convincing, and I almost believed that this woman had her illness cured because of this medicine. On the downside, I did notice that this ad sounded a lot like the ones I hear today, which seems quite interesting, that advertisements haven’t changed that much since 1906. This was a very interesting, well put together ad, and I do believe that a lot of people would have jumped at the chance to buy this medicine upon reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants that make ice?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-morales-plants-that-make-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-morales-plants-that-make-ice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While going through the newspaper, OCR-ing it, and transcribing it to XML, I usually don&#39;t pay attention to what&#39;s written. Not because I don&#39;t want to - but because I go through it so fast, I don&#39;t have time to. Until I came across this interesting advertisement. At a quick glance of the page, it immediately caught my attention. Yes, the big letters aided in that, but what was in the title is what really got me puzzled. &amp;ldquo;Ice Making Plants&amp;rdquo;? I thought, there’s &lt;em&gt;no way&lt;/em&gt; they found plants that make ice. Upon continuing to read I saw it said &amp;ldquo;Power Driven Machines to produce 1 cwt. Per 24 hours&amp;rdquo; (or about 1lb ≈ every 15 mins). So now I drew another conclusion – they’ve made robotic plants that make ice instead of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this couldn’t be correct so I took it upon myself to call the number on the ad and ask – but &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I got a &amp;ldquo;Your call could not be completed as dialed&amp;rdquo; (must have been a typo). Unfortunately, they didn’t put an email I could contact so I went to my backup-backup plan and scoured the web. After adequate research, I came to my last conclusion: This misleading ad sold ice machines crankable by hand that could be used in &lt;strong&gt;factory&lt;/strong&gt; plants to produce a lot of ice. I also concluded that the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Engineering Co., LTD.&amp;rdquo; didn’t come up with the product, it just resold it as a white label. The RAPLIN originally came from England in the 1890s made by &amp;ldquo;Pulsometer Engineering Co., LTD&amp;rdquo; which continued to manufacture ice machines and other advancements throughout the years. Who knew &lt;del&gt;an innocent&lt;/del&gt; a deceptive advertisement from the early 1900s could get a person from the 21st century so well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=kBMpAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA110&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1898&#34;&gt;Ice and Refrigeration Illustrated Vol. 14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=mj5FAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA233&amp;amp;lpg=RA1-PA233&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1898&#34;&gt;The Practical Engineer. Volume XVII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=cwsAAAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA20&amp;amp;lpg=PA20&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1899&#34;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XXIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gracesguide.co.uk/Pulsometer_Engineering_Co:_1914_Catalogue&#34; title=&#34;Catalogue of Pulsometer&#39;s machines&#34;&gt;Pulsometer Engineering Co: 1914 Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=PYdJAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA172&amp;amp;lpg=PA172&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1908&#34;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XLIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pictures&#34;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RAPLIN_Ice_Machine_Cleaned_Up.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine&#34;&gt; | &lt;img src=&#34;Raplin_Ice_Machine_V2_Cleaned_up.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine V2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death in Egypt and in my Mind.</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-greco-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-greco-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who would have ever of thought, that the utmost important news in Alexandra, in the year 1906, would be the deaths of a native woman and her daughter, and the director of a local hospital. This rather sad news is printed on page 3 of the Monday issue of my week in the Egyptian Gazette.  Not only is the content random, but this page has put a tremendous cramp in my style. It has become the pinnacle of my failure thus far. I do not find it a coincidence that the only page in my issue that is literally printed crookedly, contains the contents of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page has sparked the actual death of my patience, and my social life.  It is the exact reason why I lose sleep at night, and I cannot complete my Monday issue. At this point, I feel that my rant has become some kind of a nuisance, so with that being said, lets get to the subject matter at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mother and daughter were found asphyxiated in their room due to a charcoal fire. It is not mentioned in the paper, but the most obvious cause of death is carbon monoxide poisoning. Were Egyptians at the time not aware of the effects of carbon monoxide on the body? It makes me wonder what level of education the citizens of Alexandra actual possessed. Hell, they make me feel like a genius. In other news, the director of the Greek Hospital at Alexandra, Mr. Stiliano, died of heart disease. In the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, they do not specify what kind of heart disease, which makes me question the educational levels, once again, of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; employees. These two cases of death can properly represent my mind-state at the moment, confused, intrigued, disappointed, yet self-aware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Untimely Death of Prince Mohamed Ibrahim</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-story-theuntimelydeathofprincemohamidibrahim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-story-theuntimelydeathofprincemohamidibrahim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cousin of H.H. the Khedive, Prince Mohamed Ibrahim, was killed along with his driver in a rather unusual car accident. The accident report stated that his driver was speeding, and collided with a train. It is incredibly rare to see train/car collisions spurring from speeding as opposed to a car stopped on the tracks. This incident makes me wonder what exactly was going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was a matter of sheer stupidity on account of the driver? Did he think he could outrun a train, or make it past the tracks before it got there? Was the Prince in a rush to be somewhere? It was on a Saturday night so maybe the driver had a little too much of that Hashish. It is baffling that out of all the things he could have collided with it was a train. In order to be a fatal crash, he had to have most likely come in to contact with the front of the train. This was not even his first car accident. He was also involved in a car accident a year earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first crash, the Prince probably should have taken the hint that his driver was not very skilled at his profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bubonic Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#The Bubonic Plague has Arrived
##Striking Now in Egypt
Spread by Rats and Fleas
The Bubonic Plague has spread from many areas of SouthEast Asia, namely India, and has reached Egypt. The disease has affected many people and places, including Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;AndersonBubonicPlague2.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Plague Strikes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have come down with the disease, and many have been admitted to hospitals. Deaths have also been
associated with this deadly disease. The disease has turned into an epidemic since it once again arose from the depths of ancient times. According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmvh.org/article/the-history-of-plague-part-1-the-three-great-pandemics/&#34;&gt;JMVH&lt;/a&gt;, this new plague, still spread from rats and rat fleas, has taken over all parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it has reached Egypt and Alexandria and has no signs of stopping anytime soon. Death rates are high for the disease, and in some cities without hospitals many people are at risk. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/plague/history/&#34;&gt;CDC&lt;/a&gt; has reported that people should stay away from many of the rats infecting cities, because the cause of the disease is unknown as of yet. Many people die each day as reported in the newspapers, and more are being committed into hospitals at the same time. Many hope that the death rates of the plague decrease over time, but for many people whose family members have already been infected have little hope for the future. Some talk about vaccines and ways to stop the disease, but we have not received any of it yet because people are still dying. Many people in the areas affected by the plague cannot afford to find help, so in some cases, they are left to die on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;AndersonBubonicPlague2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Death on the Street&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gum Trade</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-04-petersen-gum-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-04-petersen-gum-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;gum-in-1906&#34;&gt;Gum in 1906&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something I use every day I hardly think about the origins of it. I never considered the history of gum, but when I saw the article about the gum trade on Wednesday July 11th 1906 it made me think about how long people have been chewing gum. It&#39;s quite interesting to think about. I am an avid gum chewer, so to think about the people that have been in my position a hundred years ago makes me feel quite small in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;gum-trading&#34;&gt;Gum Trading?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently Egypt in 1906 was a major distributor of gum. They exported thousands of cantars of gum, for a decent profit, considering they apparently are a major distributor of the product. However, up to the end of June 1906, their crop yield was only half of what it was around that time the year before. This probably ended up being a severe loss in profit, but Egypt had plenty of money from other exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-was-gum-actually-used-for&#34;&gt;What was gum actually used for?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also began to wonder if gum was actually used for chewing. Could it have been used for other purposes like so many things that existed hundreds of years ago. Was it used to hold something together? Was it used to stop leakages? Maybe it is used just as it is today, just as a way to keep your breath smelling fresh all day, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-answer&#34;&gt;The Answer&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon further inspection the use of gum was not at all what it is used for today. I found out that &amp;ldquo;Arabic Gum&amp;rdquo; was used primarily as a food stabilizer. However, it was also used in traditional lithography, it was used in printing, paint production, glue and even cosmetics. Obviously this means that Gum in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is not the same as the gum sitting in my pocket in 2017. I discovered that substitutes for chewing gum had been invented since the Ancient Greeks, however that was just tree bark. So, overall, gum as referred to in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is quite different from the gum of today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Boil Your Water</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-01-ferguson.katherine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-01-ferguson.katherine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Typhoid fever ravaged many armies, including the Egyptian. Therefore, extensive research was conducted in order to identify the source of infection and how to prevent it. Dr. Leigh Canney was on the forefront of this field in Egypt during the 19th century. “Dr. Leigh Canney was able to produce evidence from the reports of the Army Medical Department to show that the Army was ‘sanitarily untrained and unprotected’”. Furthermore, he recognized that enteric disease came from unsanitary water. However, the Army Medical Department did not want to hear it; this was not the answer they were looking for. Sir T. Gallaway argued against boiling water before drinking stating that, “all our schemes for sterilization of water by boiling or otherwise have had no effect.” Dr. Leigh Canney persisted on not only the sterilization, but also the preservation of clean water. He urged the Army to keep clean water in enclosed clean bottles to prevent contact with flies and dust which could cause recontamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days after this article was posted, on December 6, 1905, a letter to the editor was published regarding the issues faced when implementing the rules on sanitary water. The author states that boiling water and allowing it to cool after a hard days work in the desert is simply impossible, and “the system is not sufficiently practical to hold water”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both sides of the argument have made valid points, we now know that sanitizing drinking water is essential. Contaminated water houses pathogens such as Typhoid, Cholera, and a plethora of others. Although Typhoid had been identified in 1880, a vaccine &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news-medical.net/health/Typhoid-Fever-History.aspx&#34;&gt;was not developed and distributed until 1896&lt;/a&gt;. The chlorination of water during the 20th century also reduced Typhoid prevalence. Currently, India, Pakistan and Egypt are “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.medicinenet.com/typhoid_fever/article.htm&#34;&gt;known as high risk areas for developing this disease&lt;/a&gt;.” 21 million people are infected annually worldwide, with over 200,000 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Result of hashish</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-13-barbosa-hashish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-13-barbosa-hashish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A husband bought some hashish paste, which, after some research, is a recreational drug that has the same active ingredients as marijuana. He had a dose and made the mistake of giving his wife the rest. After she kept tasting it, she saw a fire and began to scream. Her husband rushed towards her and called the police because of the huge fire they saw. When the police arrived, there was no fire and the couple thought that a small roof lamp was the huge fire. I am curious as to whether the couple got punished for taking any form of marijuana and what any other effects happened because of the event. Did friends, family, neighbors, and co-workers make fun of them for such an event? How is marijuana use seen in society back then? Also, was marijuana common or illegal back then. Were laws on drugs strict back then? Another thing I am curious about is just how much did they take to somehow imagine a fire from a lamp. Was their event used as an example against drug use? Of course this event managed to make it into the newspaper so does that mean that it became viral over the town.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Learning through the Newspaper</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within every issue throughout my week I continually saw two advertisements that stood out to me, an advertisement for a school of Language and an advertisement for an &amp;ldquo;English School&amp;rdquo;. Seeing education opportunities from the early 1900s is fascinating to me as it is during the century that public education became a cornerstone in developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First are the Berlitz Schools of Languages, typically found under the &amp;ldquo;Cheap Pre-paid advertisement&amp;rdquo; column on Page 5&#39;s. It sounded familiar to me, and after doing a brief amount of searching, this is a education company/institution that has persisted since 1878 all the way until to the present day, hailing from the state of Rhode Island. In 1905 however, students in Egypt would only be able to attend the locations present in Alexandria and Cairo, unlike now, as the Berlitz Corporation offers full courses online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next advert regarding education that intrigued me was the &amp;ldquo;English School, Nicosia&amp;rdquo; advertisement. Offering a range of subjects, from Turkish to Mathematics, this school seemed a little more similar to institutions of the modern day. Also, this school seemed to have a sessions of Cricket and Football to be played with the instructors, which struck me as something related to more modern school systems. After a small amount of searching, it appears that this school persisted to the modern day just as the Berlitz program did. Besides being one of the more &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.englishschool.ac.cy/schools-history&#34; title=&#34;Nicosia English School Official History Page&#34;&gt;notable institutions of higher learning&lt;/a&gt; in the Middle East, it is also an modern example of social change. For over two decades following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_invasion_of_Cyprus&#34;&gt;Turkish invasion of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;, Turkish students were not admitted into the school, becoming a predominantly Greek Cypriot institution. However in 2003, the English School opened it&#39;s admission to Turkish Cypriots and it&#39;s general admission numbers have only grown exponentially since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Nicosia_school.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image name&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though during this time secondary education wasn&#39;t seen as something that the whole of society deserved, it is still worth looking into these smaller institutions because it gives people a clearer understanding of how a system of education grows as more people become involved in it, and the social changes that occur through a better educated populace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Silent Killer</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-03-corzo-thesilentkiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-03-corzo-thesilentkiller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine reading one of the leading newspapers in the country and coming upon the local and general section. You read about current court cases, the recent parade happening downtown etc. and then you read that yet another person has died from the plague. You think about how devastating the plague has been to the country&amp;hellip; Wait there&#39;s a plague?
In the middle of the 1905 summer on June 16, the Egyptian Gazette reported that another person has died from the plague in a hospital in Damanhour. This report in the newspaper took up literally 2 lines and was probably over looked by the majority of readers. To me it seems that a widespread plague should receive a little more attention than that. Actually a lot more attention. What was the death toll at this point? How far had the plague spread? Are there any treatments being developed for the disease? What are the symptoms? All seem like plausible questions to be asked and reported on by the newspaper but haven’t been. They treated the plague as if it were just as common as the weather report. In only 2 other pages in my week was the plague reported, each being no longer than the report on the 16th.
This odd occurrence begs the question of why hadn’t the newspaper reported something of this magnitude more rigorously? Also it brings up the chilling question of what if the newspaper did it on purpose. What if they had an alternative motive? Regardless of alternative motive or blatant ignorance, the population was being misled regarding the matter of the plague. What else were they being misled about?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-02-the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-02-the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1970, Congress passed the &lt;strong&gt;Public Health Cigarette Smoking Act&lt;/strong&gt;, which prohibited the advertisement of cigarettes, and this law took effect on January 2, 1971. As a result, I have never seen a pro-cigarette advertisement a day in my life. And clearly, that reality differs from that of people who lived in Alexandria in 1905. Here, the Egyptian Gazette, on page three of this issue, is pushing the reader to check out an advertisement for the Cleopatra Cigarette Company, just in case they skimmed over it while reading page one  just moments before. In essence, not only does the “Gazette” advertise for this cigarette company on the very first page of their newspaper, but they also refer the reader back to that advertisement in a later section of the paper, and in doing so, they are essentially advertising for Cleopatra Cigarettes two times in one issue. This just goes to show how lax people’s views on cigarettes were back in 1905. This newspaper “begs” the reader to check out an advertisement for cigarettes, hoping that they’ll end up purchasing the &lt;em&gt;cancer sticks&lt;/em&gt; for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is beautifully juxtaposed with modern society&#39;s view on cigarettes. For one, in 2016, you would never find an advertisement for cigarettes in a local newspaper. Moreover, there are a plethora of campaigns in existence today which put out ads and commercials to influence people to not smoke, or to stop smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cigs-1x-1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of the many types of ads in existence today, aiming to make society aware of the side effects of smoking cigarettes. Being surrounded and exposed by so many negative advertisements like this, it makes me question what my view on cigarettes would be if I lived in 1905 Alexandria, and was exposed to positive ads for cigarettes. Not to mention, how I would feel if my local newspaper advertised cigarettes. And moreover, if my local newspaper advertised their own cigarette advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Dates</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-deadly-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-deadly-dates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You love your family but there’s always those cousins that just annoy you so much that sometimes you just want to feed them some poisoned dates so you don’t have to deal with them anymore. Well that’s precisely what one man of Makhadoora village did to his cousins in May of 1905. This nameless man injected compressed dates with enough of a deadly poison to kill those who ate it. He then gave these deadly fruits to five of his cousins, two men and three women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three women ate the dates and “expired in great agony.” Now if you are not a psychopath, you might be confused as to why this man decided to off his cousins and especially in such a cruel and painful way. Did they inherit a large sum of money from grandma while the killer only received the nice china? Did they eat all of the stuffing at Thanksgiving when they knew it was his favorite?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to the lack of information provided about a motive or even a name for the killer, the world may never know. One thing that is known however, is that this event did cause “considerable excitement” throughout the neighborhood due to the simple fact that it was a murder as opposed to an accidental date poisoning. In my opinion, this fact implies that the neighborhood in Keneh where the murders took place was not used to this violence which might mean that it was a fairly well-off neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that the motive could involve money? It could certainly be a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sad Englishman</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-28-ragland-a-sad-englishman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-28-ragland-a-sad-englishman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A rather unfortunate English soldier was captured by an employee of a Turkish tobacco company who sent one of his ears to the Consul at Monastir, ordering a ransom be paid for him.  Interestingly enough, this tobacco company is still around today&amp;ndash;in a sense.  The company was the Ottoman Empire’s largest foreign investment.  It was called “Tekel” in 1825, but is actually still called “Regie” in Lebanon.  I found it interesting that the company selling Lebanese tobacco is the same company which cut off an English soldier’s ear way back in 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enteric Fever</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-28-eugenio-entericfever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-28-eugenio-entericfever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading through the Egyptian Gazette issues I was assigned, I came across an article that has to do with Enteric Fever. This article intrigued me because I was not familiar with the disease. After reading through the article it sparked my interest and I began to look up what this disease was. I found out that Enteric Fever is also known as Typhoid Fever. This illness is associated with Salmonella typhi bacteria. After reading more about it I realized that Typhoid is caused by bacteria that is similar to Salmonella. This article discusses how it is important to carry out preventative methods for this disease in the army. It then goes on to explain that the health efficiency of the Army has been increased by a lot. They talk about how they encourage men in the army to have better hygiene in hopes for better overall health. I think this is interesting because the article discusses the different types of methods they use to prevent the disease, such as boiling drinking water. It is interesting to see the medical advances for this time compared to current time. Enteric is such a big deal during this time and the prevention of the disease is so important, however as of now I had not even recognized this disease until I read further into it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragic Fall from a Window</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-28-vincent-curiosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-28-vincent-curiosity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blog describes an interesting story about a couple. They were having trouble with each other and were in a huge argument, fighting over something that had previously happened. The husband attempted to throw the wife out the window but he was unable to do so. She grabbed on to him and would not let him throw her out. This is where the story became very strange, as who in his or her right mind would throw someone out of a window! Clearly the couple was a little odd, maybe having some psychological problems. In the end the couple both fell out of the window. It was a very interesting news article to read and I thought it was evil but humorous how in the end both people fell out of the window. I am a bit confused of how the couple even managed to fall out of the window in the first place. It was also mind blowing to comprehend that that was how some people settled their problems.  It was also interesting that the story did not make that big of a scene. In today&#39;s world if someone was to fall out of a window, let along two people at once, a huge commotion would break out. The news would be telling the story state wide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curiosities</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-27-blog-post-1-daisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-27-blog-post-1-daisy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the year 1905, Alexandria, Egypt was becoming a city with a rising society as a result of the introduction to the use of new practices with a variety of beneficial purposes for individuals. As of today, we can still say performing arts such as theatre or music, culinary practices, economic practices, and several cultural practices are still used, usually enhancements of what was practiced in previous years. The city of Alexandria was beginning to get its own sense of balance with opening opportunities to those employers looking for something more than labor. Education was essential for personal growth, however, businessmen often times could not spare even an hour or two to enhance their education. However, thanks to the Berlitz Schools, businessmen were able to work around their schedules to receive classes for those aspiring to learn English, French, German, Italian, and other essential language lessons. To this day, these languages are still practiced by those bilinguals, aside from the use of Arabic: the native language of Egypt. Personally, this caught my attention because this presents a start for receiving an education while working for ends-meet. Also, it amazes me that Berlitz School is still a learning center for those that desire to learn a new language and has grown to be an international program, providing opportunities to learn languages or even study abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Worst Job</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through the financial tables listed on January 9th, I came across a chart detailing ivory deliveries to London. In the midst of reflecting on what 39 tons of elephant tusks would look like, I noticed an odd source of ivory mentioned in the chart: &amp;ldquo;Sea Horse Teeth.&amp;rdquo; This piqued my curiosity, as I had no idea that sea horses were a source of ivory. I immediately began to scheme&amp;ndash;I could open the first sustainable sea horse ivory farm.  But in the midst of this, a problem arose. How does one extract sea horse teeth? Tweezers and a magnifying glass? That sounds like a painstakingly miserable job. Also the chart mentioned that 10 cwt. 1 qrs. 14 lb. (about 144 pounds) of sea horse teeth were delivered! How long would extracting that many teeth take? It might be a venture perfectly suited for the British Colonial project, but I realized I had much less capital to work with (also less forced native labor). It dawned on me that there is no earthly way that this chart is talking about the same sea horse that I am familiar with. A google search revealed I was not the first person to be puzzled about the true source of this ivory. &lt;a href=&#34;http://oldblockwriter.blogspot.com/2013/01/the-mystery-of-seahorse-teeth.html&#34;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; describes a writer&#39;s journey though old trade documents to discover what animal exactly is being referred to after encountering a similar reference to sea horse teeth, before finally realizing that sea horses don&#39;t even have teeth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;seahorsedentist.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;seahorsedentist.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Misinformed Propaganda&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusion was that it depended on the source of the shipment. If from the polar areas, it would be walrus, but if from Africa, it would be referring to hippopotamus teeth. I admit, in this context hippopotamus teeth makes a lot more sense. The word hippopotamus originally comes from Greek, and translates to &amp;ldquo;river horse,&amp;rdquo; while the genus of the seahorse, hippocampus, comes from the Greek words for horse and sea monster. It would seem perhaps that these animals were named a bit backwards. I haven&#39;t been able to find official data on seahorse attack fatalities, but what I have read of hippopotamus&amp;rsquo; make them seem far more monstrous, with one article quoting a statistic provided by the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates foundation that the animal causes upwards of 500 fatalities a year. This chart also provides a snapshot of the global ivory trade before it was realized how much environmental damage was actually being done. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://nationalgeographic.org/media/history-ivory-trade/&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; for a short documentary on the subject. So while my hopes for a sustainable ivory business might be dashed, I suppose the sea horses can rest easy for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odd Football Score</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-15-fling-sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-15-fling-sports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 20, 1905 the Egyptian Gazette posted a section about football at the bottom left corner of Page three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Zealander Football team is the best of the best. In London, on November 18, as suspected, they won another game with the score of 624 to 22. This is a very odd fact because the game of football usually can not reach such high point counts. Unsure of why the score was so high, I began to wonder if &amp;ldquo;football&amp;rdquo; really meant the game of football&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, the New Zealander Football team was most likely a Rugby team. This is inferred by the time period of the newspaper, and also the location of Alexandria. Rugby is a form of football, but not the original game we play here in the States. The objective of Rugby is to carry and/or kick a ball over the other team&#39;s goal line. There are a few ways to score in rugby: try = 5 points, conversion goal = 2 points, penalty goal = 3 points, drop goal = 3 points. Being such small increments of points, it&#39;s questionable how the New Zealanders team scored 624 points in this game recorded in the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This area was known for their interest in sporting activities. Often, sporting events are mentioned in the Egyptian Gazette. This shows that the demand for sporting information and updates was at a high demand in the Alexandria area. The community, as a whole, enjoyed the sporting events and kept up with their favorite team&#39;s Win/Loss ratio through the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-14-rymer-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-14-rymer-plague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reports of a plague should be announced far and wide, so why is it that the Egyptian Gazette practically buried this news in the middle of the page?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 23, 1905, the Egyptian Gazette reported the new of a plague hitting citizens of Alexandria.  Sounds like big news right? In present time, news of a local plague would cover the headlines.  One would think it would as well in 1905; however, the Gazette reported the plague in the middle of page 3, between a headline of stray dogs and the opening of a new school.  Why did this news simply seem to just pass through the cracks of a newspaper and make it on the publication?  Is it possible the newspaper didn’t want people to know about the plague? Was this type of affliction so common in 1905 that it didn’t even phase the subscribers? In either case, it seems to be a pretty harsh place to live in compared to modern standards.  Either this newspaper overlooks the safety of its subscribers heavily, or a plague infection wasn’t even a big enough deal at the time to turn the heads of the common Egyptian.  Its hard to believe a plague would go by so nonchalantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wife Murder</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-cooper-wife-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-cooper-wife-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the twenty-fourth of January, an incident involving a woman and her enraged husband occurred. The man killed his wife by hitting her on the head using a metal bar made of iron and fled the scene. The former clerk from Gabbari has yet to be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motive for committing this heinous crime is unknown. Perhaps his wife was cheating on him or maybe she cooked him a poor meal. I find it interesting that an event of this magnitude is not given a bigger article. Someone&#39;s life has been ended and there is a possibility that others may be in danger. More information should be provided and this news story should not be shrugged off as an every day occurrence. Either way, the suspect is still at large and he needs to be caught before he spreads his mayhem elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubonic Plague In Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Egyptian Gazette, August 28, 1905, the Bubonic plague has reported at least thirteen cases of individuals that had contracted this disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in this snippet of information, housed within the Gazette (see figure below), stems from the fact that the Bubonic Plague (a.k.a. The Black Death), was not confined to Medieval Europe (as many readers would suspect). In fact, the Bubonic plague has existed for thousands of years, the first known case being recorded in China dating back to 224 B.C.E..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant outbreak, and most noticeable, occurred in Europe in the mid-fourteenth century over a five year period (1347 to 1352). During this time period, sources indicate that at least 25 million people died, about one-third of the continent’s population (these numbers are disputed). The often disputed claims as to the cause of such a disease was further investigated in 2010 and 2011, when researchers analyzed DNA from some of its European victims. The consensus to date is that the pathogen responsible was the Yersinia pestis bacterium, which most likely caused several different forms of the plague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;BlackPlague.gif&#34; alt=&#34;image name&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing an outbreak within the borders of Egypt, with so few deaths was incredible, which warrants further understanding of this disease, how it was spread and who it affected. The Gazette’s article (above) mentions that approximately 13 cases were under treatment during the middle of August and beginning of September, 1905. With the plague’s notorious reputation, the Gazette’s allocated space to this pandemic is sapient, especially due to the many cattle deaths in the area within that same time period (the figure to the right indicates the area affected by the Bubonic Plague).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With modern populations shifted to cities in modern day, an unidentifiable plague in one of these areas would prove to be even more catastrophic than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-further-study&#34;&gt;For further study:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yersinia Pestis.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951374/&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951374/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Draft genome of Yersinia pestis from victims of the Black Death.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v478/n7370/full/nature10549.html&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v478/n7370/full/nature10549.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plague in 18th Century Egypt.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://contagions.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/plague-in-18th-century-egypt/&#34;&gt;https://contagions.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/plague-in-18th-century-egypt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Killer</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-soap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a time when merchandise regulation is not nearly as controlled as it is now, it can be expected that there will be defaults in the products produced. [Salicylate of soda](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2220712/?page=1&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2220712/?page=1&lt;/a&gt; Define Salicylate of Soda&amp;rdquo;) was thought to have restorative effects during the mid to late 19th century. It was often recommended to people with joint disease, such as rheumatism, to alleviate pain.  At first the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1322509/?page=7&#34;&gt;negative side effects&lt;/a&gt; associated with salicylate of soda reported were minor, like a relapse in pain after the salicylate of soda was no longer being used. Many users had to be gradually weaned from the chemical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;soap-ad.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sunlight Soap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years after its use in soap, physicians began noting that people who were repeated salicylate of soda users had painful skin and there was even a case of failing vision after taking a bath in the soap with the chemicals. In the early 1900s, manufacturers of soap products containing the chemical were ordered to stop production and were prosecuted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=5a-Uc3NJuPUC&amp;amp;pg=PA206&amp;amp;lpg=PA206&amp;amp;dq=1905+egyptian+sanitary+administration&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=pGXkko-vu3&amp;amp;sig=P6WCUO4P1BmN_u7Zm8Ny2nSY3Dc&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi60p_rs4zQAhWSZiYKHXwdDTMQ6AEIHTAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=1905%20egyptian%20sanitary%20administration&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;sanitary administration&lt;/a&gt;. Large soap companies during this time, like Pears’ Soap, were not being advertised because of the ordeal. Instead, the same issue of the newspaper that published the harmful soap announcement had an ad for Sunlight Soap, which advertises its lack of “obnoxious or harmful feature.” This small news brief gives insight about this time period, showing its lack of medical knowledge and its clever marketing methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pear-soap.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pear Soap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Avoid Female Society”</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-black-avoid-female-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-black-avoid-female-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; includes a section called &lt;strong&gt;“CALENDAR OF THE WEEK”&lt;/strong&gt; in every issue which lists the important events happening in Alexandria and its surrounding areas. This serves as a tool to keep its citizens up-to-date with what is happening in the town and advises them to go and participate in these events. Throughout the week of August 7 to August 12, 1905, the section lists plays, concerts, and other kinds of events for general entertainment. However, the issue for August 7, 1905 includes a peculiar calendar of events. For the areas of Coptic and Mohamedan, the calendar lists actions the people should take rather than events they should attend. What is even more interesting is the actions themselves. For Sunday, August 6th, it reads, “Avoid female society” and on Tuesday, August 8, it reads “Avoid eating onions and garlic”. The week gets even more interesting by following with “Drink cold water before breakfast” and “Great abundance of watermelons”. The calendar section leaves no explanation as to why these events have been posted. I am curious to know whether it was some kind of joke or if these events were meant to be taken seriously for some kind of reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Fight between Greeks</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-doublemurder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-doublemurder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of January 3rd, 1905, two men were murdered behind a bar.
The man responsible is around 20 years old and is very physically fit.
His name is Yanni Antonio Stigrigo and was supposedly in love with the
sister of his victims. Ironically, one of the men he killed would have
made a good husband for his own sister. A fight broke out between the
three men and Yanni was quick to take out his weapon and stab the first brother one time, then stabbed the other brother two times. The second brother was taken to the Greek hospital, but died around midnight. Yanni was arrested outside of Cairo Railway Station and was easily apprehended. He followed police demands and quietly allowed them to put him in handcuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who wants to study murderers and their psychological aspects, I would like to know what the fight was about that made him think killing was the only answer. Due to the love interests involved between the three men, I suspect the fight was relevant to marriage. Of course, crimes like this still occur all over the world everyday. Bar fights are very common, mostly because people become angrier when they are intoxicated and cannot control their behaviors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent example took place in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kjrh.com/news/local-news/police-are-investigating-double-homicide-in-n-tulsa&#34;&gt;Tulsa&lt;/a&gt;. Bar fights happen every night and can occasionally turn deadly if someone does not step in soon enough. The most well known murder at a bar recently was the Orlando night club shooting. Of course, this was a hate crime but still comes to show that similar things happen everyday, this case being particularly extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;barfight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bar fight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the double murder that took place in 1905 in Egypt is similar to events in modern day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-esteve-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-esteve-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-mans-trash-is-another-mans-treasure&#34;&gt;One Man&#39;s Trash is Another Man&#39;s Treasure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, a man wrote to the Egyptian Gazette about the stricture and kidney disease that he had suffered with for 19 years. After living with excruciating pain and being told that he would only have three months to live, this man began taking Doan&#39;s Backache Kidney Pills.&lt;br&gt;
I was immediately curious about this, because &lt;a href=&#34;https://pics.drugstore.com/prodimg/498956/450.jpg&#34;&gt;Doan&#39;s Backache Kidney Pills&lt;/a&gt; are a cheap, over the counter drug that people use today. While someone today might take these pills to relieve minor back pain, this man believes that they saved his life. This speaks a great deal to the quality of medicine during the early 1900&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern day America, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medlineplus.gov/magazine/issues/winter08/articles/winter08pg9-10.html&#34;&gt;kidney disease&lt;/a&gt; is often not curable and can usually only be delayed with extensive treatment and medication. As time passes and it gets worse, dialysis or a transplant is needed. I mention all of this to draw attention to the diagnosis of the man in the Egyptian Gazette. He suffered for 19 years and was diagnosed with three months to live, yet an over the counter drug managed to save his life. Either drugs were much better 100 years ago, or he was severely misdiagnosed. People often take for granted the high level of medicine and easy access to treatment that exists throughout the world today. I wonder how much of an impact old-fashioned medicine had on other people living in the early 1900&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egyptology &amp; Archeology</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-29-egyptology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-29-egyptology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/science/Egyptology&#34;&gt;Egyptology&lt;/a&gt; has caputured pop-culture imagination owing to movies like &lt;em&gt;The Mummy&lt;/em&gt;, and exhibits like King Tut.  Films often emphasize the mysticism, magic, or exoticism of Egyptian artefacts and Tombs.  The Egyptian Gazette, however, provides a closer perspective, both in time and location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the excavation and discovery of these tombs has historical significance on a global scale, the local perspective brings the actual characters that advanced the discovery of these relics to light.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Lionex/dig-eg-gaz/blob/7dbde112756552ed412ee7145eb84208ffe34fd4/ocr/1905-10-06-p3.txt#L88&#34;&gt;newspaper&lt;/a&gt; serves as a medium for criticism and discourse, which time and distance have buried.  The newspaper even brags about the abundance of archeological remains in region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This liveliness caught me off guard, and reminds me that the study of history always lives and breaths, not confined to memory or buried between the covers of a textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, for the people of Alexandria, the archeological wealth around them caputures the public eye and excitement enough for the Egyptian Gazette to publish a story about archeology in two seperate issues, in addition to a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/7d/Colossus_of_Ramesses_II_restored.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ramses II&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newspaper discusses a work by Dr. Petrie, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/cu31924085360844&#34;&gt;A History of Egypt during the XVIIth and XVIIIth Dynasties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. From the newspaper, 6th Oct 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complaint that has been brought against it by foreign critics, to the effect that it is not so much a history as a catalogue of monuments, is here more justified than ever, a period of more than a thousand years - neither the least eventful nor the worst documented in Egypts history-being jammed into a small volume of 400 pages. The delay in its appearance is, we are told in the text, almost entirely due to the groat quantity of monuments remaining to us from the reign of Rameses II., which apparently made it necessary for Prof. Petrie to go carefully through the list and to throw out such as he considered either appropriations of the works of earlier kings, or for some other reason unworthy of note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work was delayed specifically because there was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much history, and so many monuments to examine and study!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Imperialism</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-british-imperialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-british-imperialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.historyworld.net/wrldhis/PlainTextHistories.asp?ParagraphID=hkl&#34;&gt;British imperialism&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely crucial topic in understanding the development of world history, particularly during the period spanning the 19th and early 20th centuries. This era is often characterized by historians as &lt;em&gt;Pax Britannica&lt;/em&gt;, Latin for “British Peace.” It is so called due to the fact that Britain’s worldwide domination in the areas of economics, shipping, and military might kept most of Europe and the world in a state of relative peace. However, as the twentieth century came into view, global forces such as liberal ideals and nationalism threatened Britain’s role as the premier world superpower. Questions of how to proceed with its imperial rule began to multiply both in Britain and in its many colonies and territories abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cromer-sane-imperialism.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cromer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the third page of the May 3rd, 1905 edition of the Egyptian Gazette contains an editorial article &lt;a href=&#34;http://biography.yourdictionary.com/1st-earl-of-cromer&#34;&gt;“Lord Cromer’s Sane Imperialism”&lt;/a&gt; that discusses a moderate “third way” of imperialism that rejects harsh materialistic concepts and embraces more liberal ideas of self-determination and government, when appropriate of course. This article maintains that Lord Cromer’s Annual Report on Egypt and the Sudan contain the necessary elements of pursuing a moderate approach for continuing the might of the Empire moving forward. This editorial provides a fascinating look at the prevailing dialogue of the day in one of Britain’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishempire.co.uk/maproom/egypt.htm&#34;&gt;most crucial imperial territories&lt;/a&gt; about the morality and governance of British imperialism at the dawn of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.newworldencyclopedia.org/4/48/Map_of_the_British_Empire_in_the_1920%27s.png&#34; alt=&#34;The British Empire at the height of its territorial range&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close Knit Community</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-barrett-curiosities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-barrett-curiosities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was going through and correcting the text of the Egyptian Gazette from February of 1905, I noticed that at certain events, the paper gives long lists of names of people who attended. They also do this with passenger lists, or who embarked on a ship, every week. This sparked my mind, making me think is this community very closely knit to the point where most people would know a majority of the names that are listed? Are the names on these lists just the highly recognized citizens, or is it a mix of everyone in the community? The events that they list names for include, but are not limited to, arrivals, departures, visitors lists, guests at restaurants, dances, and even concerts. As I analyze some of the lists, I look at the names and think that they must be only listing the celebrities, or important well known people of their day.  Then as I look at other lists, they seem like just a jumble of names that include everyone, popular or not. These records of who attended events are quite lengthy, which makes me believe that these lists are composed of a mix of everyone in the community, and simply just lists all of the names that either depart or arrive on a ship that week. If this is true, then this community is not as closely knit as I was first lead to believe. I&#39;m sure the citizens still recognized a lot of names from the list, but I do not believe that they are all close with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fatal House Collapse</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-building-collapse-hank-thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-building-collapse-hank-thompson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; covers a bevy of topics from foreign trade to local deaths, however one odd thing I have noticed within it is the rather blasé coverage of the deaths of common people. Take for instance the incident they reported on in the November 1st issue in 1905, shown above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of a house collapsing and killing seven people would have been a rather large headline in a local paper today, such as when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/19/trial-set-to-open-in-fatal-philadelphia-building-collapse.html&#34;&gt;a thrift store collapsed in Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt;. But the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; barely gives any information on it, acting as if it just another everyday occurrence. The coverage is rather sparse by our modern standards, where just about everything that can be sensationalized is, but the most interesting part is when it is compared to other articles within the paper. The paper dedicates an entire section of the paper to simply announce that an aristocratic madam has left Paris, complete with headline, but puts this story in with a group of other local stories and express little interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of reporting just took me off guard at first, especially when is noticed it was not a one-off occurrence. There is a story of a young boy drowning in the Nile, reports of deaths from the Plague and murders all treated with the same aloof attitude. This could possibly be attributed to the simple fact that death was more common 111 years ago. It didn’t effect people in the same way as it does today. Take for instance the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/boy-drowns-in-backyard-pool-in-sydneys-south-west-20161009-grydvb.html&#34;&gt;death of a six-year old child in Sydney Australia&lt;/a&gt;. He has a large separate news story into his death and even has an impending investigation into it. It is possible that the house collapse also has an investigation going on as well, but the newspaper does not mention anything of the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stark contrast in reporting between the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and our modern day newspapers just struck me as an interesting story to blog about, and so I did. Hopefully the reason I presented for this difference can be confirmed or denied later on, but only further research will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somerset</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-somerset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-somerset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My chosen blog post is on the excerpt from May 29’s page 4, titled ‘In Praise of England: American Women’s Preference for Our Country’. It regards a conversation between noted British feminist and philanthropist, Lady Henry Somerset, and an unnamed, anonymous American female expatriate in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Lady-Somerset.png&#34; alt=&#34;May 29, 1905&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, most women that expatriate had spoken to preferred England over their home country (with the exception of one). The reasons the expatriate gave were the comparative independence and equality women receive in England as opposed to back home in America. Women may be praised more back across the pond, she said, but women in England are treated more as equals, ‘occupying a plane of frank comradeship’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking as someone reading this section a century and eleven years after its publication, this initially seemed to be just a sop to contemporary British nationalism. It looked like it was just a way for English businessman, sitting in comfortable chairs in opulent lobbies, being waited on by Egyptian servants, to have a good chortle over the inferiority of those other, lesser, nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I looked up Lady Henry Somerset, mostly just to see if she was anyone important. And she was. She has her own Wikipedia article and anything. Lady Henry was originally Lady Isabella Somers-Cooks, until she married Lord Henry Somerset in 1872. They had a relatively happy marriage, at least seemingly, but it turned out that Lord Henry was gay. And he was going behind Lady Henry’s back to sleep with other men. So she sued him for divorce and custody over her son, shoving Lord Henry out of the closet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m of two minds about this, but I’m leaning towards Lord Henry in this the argument. Lord Henry was forced into a marriage with a person he was fundamentally not attracted to, and so he sought out the company of those he was. Lady Henry shouldn’t have had to suffer the pains of adultery, but Lord Henry shouldn’t have had his sexual orientation forced into public life, especially in a primitive nation like contemporary England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After her marriage fell apart, Lady Henry became (in)famous for being one of the first women in British society to make the reasons behind a separation known publicly. She then became involved in numerous feminist organizations, and was once voted, by the London Evening News, the women readers would most prefer as their Prime Minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I know of Lady Henry’s life and accomplishments, my opinion on this section has barely changed from ‘sop to British nationalism’ to ‘sop to British nationalism plus the biased opinion of a nationalistic ideologue’. The tale of Lady Henry is an interesting one, and this section of the Egyptian Gazette is just one facet of her long and storied life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stuff Movies are Made Of</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-11-taylor-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-11-taylor-collapse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was correcting and reading through some of the news in my week of November 13th-18th, one story in particular stood out to me. In fact, I had to go back and reread it twice because it was so unbelievable. The news story is titled “The Fatal Pit.&amp;rdquo;  It begins with a local man of Karnak, near Luxor who believes that his home was built over “an ancient tomb or some old building.” So, he digs a large pit, enters, comes upon an old door, and does not return. That alone sounds like something from a movie, but things only get crazier. Alarmed by her husband’s disappearance, his wife goes after him. She too enters the pit and does not return. Now the children are concerned about where their parents have wandered off to. So, the son and daughter go to search for them, enter, and do not return. Finally, a lone village native goes to check it out and becomes asphyxiated as soon as he reaches the old door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;taylor-post1-map-image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Karnak-Luxor-map&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a few questions came to me as I read this. The first one being, “is this real?” I am still questioning this, simply because it sounds so outrageous. My second question, of course, was the question of what was behind that old door. No one from this story successfully enters far enough to see what lies within, and the story focuses on their tragic deaths rather than addressing a possible discovery. But, did anyone ever enter? I can’t imagine this mysterious discovery would have been forgotten or overlooked, but maybe it was. This lead to the question of whether scenarios such as this one were common for this time period. Just how often were people discovering strange structures like this under their homes? Was this strange story really so strange?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fashoda Incident</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This small newspaper section addresses the infamous &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/event/Fashoda-Incident&#34;&gt;Fashoda Incident&lt;/a&gt; that occurred between Britain and France during a period of intense colonialism in Africa. It shares that the ex-Prime Minister of France, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Charles-Louis-de-Saulces-de-Freycinet&#34;&gt;M. de Freycinet&lt;/a&gt;, is writing a book that promotes peace and cooperation between France and Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case he presents in &lt;a href=&#34;https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=uc1.$b749498;view=2up;seq=460&#34;&gt;his book&lt;/a&gt; says that England was in the right during the Fashoda Incident but could have easily handled the situation better than they did. He also refutes the claims of the French courts, who said that the French response was a mistake. Put simply, he is about to publish a work that will try to put to rest misconceptions about the event that have been circulating through the public in an attempt to resolve any bad feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is amazing to see this event described in an everyday context and even more fascinating that an ex-Prime Minister of France would declare England to be in the right, despite the competitive nature of colonial affairs. This entry is not only informational, but it also acts as an advertisement of sorts, presenting the name, author and content of a soon to be released book to the public eye. The information and arguments shared through the book may have strengthened Franco-British relations and helped lead to where the two powers stood during World War I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fashoda1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fashoda1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egyptian Gazette Views on Imperialism</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-08-egyptian-gazette-views-on-imperialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-08-egyptian-gazette-views-on-imperialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although there is a constant sense of British imperialism evident throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the attitude toward this imperialism varies widely throughout the paper. For instance, there are many cases where the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; provides long blocks of texts or ads clearly targeted toward rich Englishmen. The paper then proceeds to provide a sentence-long description of an item or event important to African natives. This follows with the expected traditional convention of the paper, seeing as its intended audience was wealthy Westerners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Cecil-Rhodes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cecil Rhodes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was rather surprising to discover a whole column’s length worth of information on a book regarding the emancipation on Egypt. This article, in the December 26th issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, mentioned both sides of the imperialism conflict, saying the author “devotes a whole chapter to the ‘false position of Great Britain in Egypt.’” The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; also seems to be an influential avenue for charity donations, frequently reporting on giving to certain causes and being used as a means for donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper devotes an even greater amount of room to a cluster of articles surrounding the death of a khedivial princess. These articles discuss the death of this princess, who was the sister of Prince Omar Pasha and Prince Djemil Pasha Toussoun, as well as the wife of General Ahmed Djelaleddin Pasha. Her husband wishes to open an inquiry into the circumstances surrounding her death, documented in a French telegram that is also printed in the Egyptian Gazette. Throughout the collection of articles, the princess is never referred to by name, only as the Khedivial Princess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this great amount of detail is due to the shock value of the event or the genuine interest in the matter by English businessmen is open to interpretation. Much of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is still written about administration, war, and other topics that would mainly be of interest to the white population of Alexandria, but these few tidbits to the contrary were an interesting find.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Mail</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-christmas-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-christmas-mail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When going through cultural information from the past, it&#39;s often interesting seeing the information that was deemed interesting or important at the time. Case in point, the article in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Fibinocci1123/Dig-eg-gaz/blob/master/Text/1905-12-01&#34;&gt;Newspaper&lt;/a&gt; serving to tell the public about the deadlines for which to send Christmas cards to various specific European locations if they wish for the letters to be delivered in time for Christmas. However, the information itself isn&#39;t what interests me, but rather the first sentence in particular. The article opens with the statement &amp;ldquo;Our readers will no doubt be interested to know&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; While the information is quite bland and rather meaningless, the context of the information tells a much more interesting story; This is one of the only articles in the issue with an opening such as this. In modern culture, an article like this would be passed over without a second thought; it&#39;s just not as important to us anymore. In Alexandria, 1905, however, it was apparently so important for Christmas cards to go out on time that the newspaper found the information and published an entire article about when to mail cards out if they&#39;re to arrive in the U.K. or Europe by Christmas or the New Year. Furthermore, there is a table in the newspaper occuring in the Saturday issues which provides the day on which a letter, parcel, or money order mail will arrive in a specific destination (such as Europe, Greece, Malta, etc.) if they&#39;re delivered to the office by a specific date and time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder In Cairo</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-oulette-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-07-oulette-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 1905-04-18 Egidio Gerona was ironically murdered upon entering a catholic church in the Mousky. The cause of death came from two bullets fired by a man by the name of Fabio Ninci. Following the incident the murderer was apprehended without resistance outside of the church. The police discovered a few connections between the two men, including their Italian nationality and prior employment. Apparently the murderer had been discharged from the Telephone Company where M. Gerona also worked. The discharge he attributed to M. Gerona, who worked as an electrician the and the murderer sought to avenge himself. In my opinion, the man took his actions way too far, especially over working as a wires-man. With his poor judgment an innocent man was tragically murdered and he put himself away in the central native prison. Two others instances of murder are reported in the paper. First, a Greek band attacked a Bulgarian village, resulting in 15 deaths. The other instance involved the Turks killing 30 Albanians near the town. These reports show  the hectic condition that Macedonia is currently facing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The death of Muhammad &#39;Abduh</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-abduh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-abduh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Muhammad &amp;lsquo;Abduh died on July 11, 1905. Because he was the leading Muslim thinker of Egypt and a prominent player in political and public life, it is not surprising that &amp;lsquo;Abduh&#39;s illness, funeral, and memory were the subject of daily reports in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;article&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pro-British paper lauded the memory of the pro-British cleric.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Billy Ocean meets Prince Lines</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-billy-ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-billy-ocean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 1984, Billy Ocean had a big hit with his song &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caribbean_Queen&#34;&gt;Caribbean Queen&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; It was a versatile song in global terms, as Ocean recorded versions that charted in other markets: &amp;ldquo;African Queen&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;European Queen&amp;rdquo; didn&#39;t require much extra reworking to benefit from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internationalization_and_localization&#34;&gt;internationalization and localization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking about &amp;ldquo;Caribbean Queen&amp;rdquo; while I was preparing an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/advertisements/blob/master/ad-text/pri01.xml&#34;&gt;xml version of the Prince Lines advertisement&lt;/a&gt; that appeared on the front page of most issues of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Prince Lines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ad lists 48 ships owned by the company by name and weight. Each name is a prince of a certain region, nation, type, or character. Billy Ocean might be gratified to see that there is a massive Carib Prince (8,000 tons) and a somewhat slighter African Prince (3,050 tons). No European Prince, but lots of Princes from various parts of Europe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Prince-Line-locations.png&#34; alt=&#34;Prince Lines locations&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was struck by the coverage of names. The geography of colonial shipping interests dictated part but not all of this range&amp;ndash;though the heaviest ships seemed to follow the empire&#39;s shipping lanes. British whimsy seemed to supply other names&amp;ndash;Highlands Prince, Soldier Prince, Merchant Prince, and so on. And of course there&#39;s an Ocean Prince: Billy honored before his time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
