<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>marriage | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/marriage/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/marriage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>marriage</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>marriage</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/marriage/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can women be happy without men?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-pustam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-pustam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this article on women and marriage while finding articles for my analysis project. My project was on wedding fashion, and this article talks about how women don’t consider marrying a man the ultimate way to get a happy life anymore. The writer of this article is very angry about it, saying “Where else [women’s papers] would anyone dare to imply that woman was sufficiently idiotic to believe that marriage &amp;ldquo;of itself alone&amp;rdquo; guaranteed anything?” I honestly kind of thought this article was funny. It was just funny to see the writer get so worked up they had to write an article about it that is mostly made up of quotes and not a lot of their own thoughts (pretty bad journalism if you ask me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something interesting about this was the fact that women are being blamed for the decline in marriage within this article, when there are incidents like one I found in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;- a crazy man killing his wife. Similar to in the Gazette, the writer of the blog post suggests the woman may be at fault for her unhappy marriage. They suggest that she might have cheated on her husband, causing him to kill her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there is another blog post, titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;“Women Are Always Lying?”&lt;/a&gt;, which describes an article that rants about how women lie to men by changing their appearance (presumably through makeup). Women are depicted as “a creature of broad and gradual curves, whose first duty it is to persuade you that she is the shape of the fashionable corset…” I can’t speak for women back then, but now women really don’t dress up for the sake of impressing men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When women are treated like this by men in newspaper articles, its really no wonder why they create their own newspapers to say that “it is possible to be as happy without a man’s love as with it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage &amp; Divorce</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-jarmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-jarmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my blog post, I chose to talk about the topic of Marriage &amp;amp; Divorce in the year of 1907, around the month August. I was particularly intrigued by the emphasis on marriage being placed in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper which is opposed to what we see in these modern times. One specific section in my reading that gathered my interest was titled &amp;ldquo;Alexandria Merchant Divorce&amp;rdquo; published on August 6, 1907.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief overview about the story resulted in the end of a marriage between Mr. William Getty, a cotton merchant of Alexandria and his wife. Over the past years, she strayed away and disappeared from him, leaving him to wonder about her whereabouts and how she was doing. While on her death bed, she had an incurable diseases that she couldn&amp;rsquo;t be healed from. She wrote a letter to her husband confessing that she was unfaithful to him throughout the duration of their marriage. In defense of her statement, she felt that the money she had leftover should be given to him since she recently became a Christian Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This excerpt from the passage was quite interesting for me to read because I was fascinated with the explicit details provided and how it was shared with all of the world to see. Although they didn&amp;rsquo;t share a response from her husband after he received the message from her, I would have wondered what his thoughts, response or even last words to her would have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reference to this article, I found another interesting topic from the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;another blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a crazy man killing his wife with an unusual weapon. Although there is no reason for his crazy acts, he committed the crime from speculations that his wife was cheating on him. The magnitude of this article was extremely huge enough to reach the newspaper because people thought the city should be aware of this person and who he is. This article correlated to mine because there was suspicion of cheating in both marriages where the results ended up tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
