<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>distorts | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/distorts/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/distorts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>distorts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>distorts</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/distorts/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distorted Photo File</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-31-evanoff-technical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-31-evanoff-technical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My biggest issue that I have had during this project is trying to work with
the poor quality photos. Some are angled incorrectly while others are just
difficult to read due to age of the papers when they were scanned. The
scanner seemed to have distorted or incorrectly scanned the pages. This has
forced me to either go back to the library and look to rescan the microfilm
or I had to attempt to enhance the quality of the picture using editing. This
has added a lot of extra work on my part just to get the files to the point
that they can be scanned or read by my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this the OCR wouldn&amp;rsquo;t pick up the actual words, so a lot
of the time I was making minor or major changes to the text files. The pages
have been taking me around 3-4 hours to correct because the OCR application
didn&amp;rsquo;t correctly fix or correct my document. Some of the words it confused or
misspelled were correct and very easy to see. The reader failed to correctly
identify a very clear word. It mixes up the letters &amp;ldquo;o&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;c&amp;rdquo; a lot as well.
For such an intelligent software I am surprised that it can&amp;rsquo;t correctly
differentiate between certain letters and words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
