<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/music/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Music</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/music/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Performance</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-karl-frederickroche/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-karl-frederickroche/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to investigate the music side of the Egyptian Gazette. This is because I found it rather interesting and wanted to see how the people as well as the newspaper itself reacts to musical literature. To my surprise I found that they are much more candid than I would have otherwise expected. When looking at my Monday issue I found an article on a fifth annual musical entertainment scene. They described the pupils there as well as gave the readers insight into some of their hardships as well as how they improved from last year’s performance. Due to this, I can also safely assume that this must be something that regularly occurs since this is the fifth time they have had such an entertainment. As stated, the writer is very candid and explains the downfalls and concerns they had over the performance. For example, the chorus sounded too forced and containing a lack of vibrancy. However, the writer did not only explain shortcomings. He also gave ample credit when he felt it necessary. This happened during a duet for the soprano and tenor which he labeled as “pleasant”, along with a violin solo which he said was given in a manner that was “most commendable”.  It was also stated that this chorus came from Macbeth, which gives me insight into what the Egyptian audience liked to listen to at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading this article, I remember 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pierre/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the blog post&lt;/a&gt;
 that I read before this. It is similar to this one, however, it looked at the individual artists and the culture rather than the performance as a whole. Nonetheless, it provided me with very helpful information, such as how the Egyptian musical culture is different from our own. He also found it interesting to see how the writers explain events such as what I noted with how candid they were. It does indeed make someone wonder if that is how the audience felt. Though this will most likely be a question that can’t be answered simply because we cannot go back to that exact time and see for ourselves. Until then, this is all we have to go off of and we must take it as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Critiques</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pierre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pierre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The critique speaks about everyone who performed at the Khedival Opera House on the night that Madame Maud Valerie
played at after the different musicians played and sung. He seemed to have been against the common use of repetition
in the ways that are shown by the artists and foreign composers at the time. The mistakes seen from a single musician
was said to be made much more obvious with the musical part that she chose to sing. The next person was a singer from
the Abbis Theatre, who was in the place of another performer, he did rather well, although the tone in his voice was
not as strong with its depth and tone. The next performer was a lady who sung the Tschaikowski, doing quite well the
audience desired one more performance, so she chose to perform Rubinstein&#39;s Romance in E-Flat. The man who performed
directly after her Saillards Bach Allegro, this was bad decision due to the level of passion he used to sing it - not
a great amount of passion - as it caused the audience to feel un-intrigued and uninterested. The incredible Madame Maud
Valerie began to play the piano and performed two pieces in an outstanding form, showing that she was a true musician
and well known by the audiences and the critique.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
