<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ABBYY finereader | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/abbyy-finereader/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/abbyy-finereader/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ABBYY finereader</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>ABBYY finereader</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/abbyy-finereader/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running out of Time</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-08-taylor-blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-08-taylor-blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Converting images to text has been a difficult process from start to finish. From the very start, FineReader did not seem to be responding well to my scans. It produced a multitude of errors (nearly every other word at points) that did not seem to be the result of poor scans. Then, one day I went to do some more work with it, and the program wouldn’t start up even though my trial period was not over yet. It displayed a message which said that ABBYY FineReader 12 would be terminated because it was corrupted. I discovered that one other student had the exact same problem, so at least I knew that it was not just my little computer giving up on life from working so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I only had a couple more page threes to do at that point. So, I used my roommate’s Mac and did those. Now that I’ve moved on to other pages, I’m just typing up whatever articles appear since this doesn’t seem to take too much longer than it did to go back and correct all the text. All in all, this class has been far more difficult than I envisioned it being (especially for someone who is not great with computers), but I am not ready to give up on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finereader Rage</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-28-thompson-finereader-rage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-28-thompson-finereader-rage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So my biggest technical difficulty while working on this project has to have been the multiple errors that I encountered while using he OCR. Overall it worked ok, but when it failed, it failed big time. For instance, while correcting some of the errors in one page I was on the very last paragraph and went to save it, and Finereader crashed. Two hours of work, two hours of my life, gone, down the drain, and there was nothing I could do about it. I was understandably irate, but after I took some time for cathartic expression and collected myself, I felt much better. I also found out that I was not alone in my anger, some of my fellow students had been experiencing troubles as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, from what I have seen online, things could have actually been much worse. Apparently it could actually cause other Microsoft programs to crash, at least according to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/kb/2755838&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this support article on Microsoft’s website&lt;/a&gt;
. I could also have run into errors that wouldn’t have allowed me to do any work within Finereader, such as the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledgebase.ocrsdk.com/article/1096&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;license not reading&lt;/a&gt;
, so that fact that it worked for me relatively well is a good thing in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Finereader was a useful program that, while annoying at times, did enable me to do my work properly and relatively quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Reflection</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-25-stefonek-technical-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-25-stefonek-technical-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suppose I&#39;ll start off with how much I&#39;ve learned so far through this course; taking digital images of film, running text recognition software, writing in Markdown and encoding in XML. Though it has all been incredibly interesting and fulfilling, the mention of those words along with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Digital Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
, will likely send chills down my spine for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, my largest technical obstacle was the poor job done by Fine Reader. While it truly saved me a lot of time by translating the text, it also made an overwhelming amount of errors that are incredibly time-consuming and painstaking to correct. If I were to make an estimate, correcting and encoding one page of the newspaper takes about three and a half hours. Aside from that I have had trouble with putting together the tables and advertisements in my week. Several of them do not yet exist as text files that I can pull from and for the ones that I do have access to, it takes about three copy and pastes before I trigger an &amp;ldquo;abuse mechanism&amp;rdquo; on GitHub. This locks me out for a couple of minutes before I can get back to work. But regardless, we push onward!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
