<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>natural | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/natural/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/natural/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>natural</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>natural</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/natural/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s Skin Food</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-castro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-castro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On my Tuesday issue, I found an interesting home remedy for acne and other skin problems. It appears this is something distinct and special to Alexandria. As I was adding the advertisement for page 2 of the October 1906 issue. As a person that loves to learn about skin care and is addicted to by skin care products, this advertisement stood out to me. According to the advertisement, the cream derives from Icilma Natural Water, but most have named it Nature&amp;rsquo;s Skin Food. From the Icilma Natural water a cream is produced called the Icilma Flour Cream. It is described as the being a no grease or oil cream which I find amazing because most skin care products are filled with oil that, as a result, often causes the skin to produce more oil. This is especially helpful to people that have oily skin which leads them to have problematic skin. The advertisement states that it cleanses the pores of the skin and make it pearly white. I think the Icilma Flour Cream could possibly have been the modern invention of acne remedies in Alexandria during the 1900s. The Icilma Flour Cream sounds like the Neutrogena or Proactive most people preferred to use for their skin problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/ddg.12947&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Back to the Roots: Dermatology in Ancient Egyptian Medicine&lt;/a&gt;
 in the 2016 Journal of the German Society of Dermatology, Egyptian medicine and the treatment of acute and chronic wounds and injuries such as cosmetic procedures took an important role. Additionally, it seems that another student, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sabrina Nunez&lt;/a&gt;
, also took a curious look into the Iclimia medicine and discovered that Stephen Armitage founded Iclima in 1989. Yet, it seems that herbal medicine was the best option remedy for the Egyptians seeming as the technology was not very advanced, according to the 2015 review journal 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doaj.org/article/602aea8253f84a068559bb763708c006?&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ancient Egyptian Medicine: A Systematic Review&lt;/a&gt;
. However, there were instances of &amp;ldquo;miracle&amp;rdquo; cures and medicine like Doan&amp;rsquo;s Backache Kidney Pills, as reported by previous student 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Esteve-Medicine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Justin Esteve&lt;/a&gt;
. Nevertheless, the medicine used in Egypt was produced in different ways and counter products such as in mineral-based compounds, set milk, honey using tropical, oral methods, according to an 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27594551&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Treatment Adherence and Beliefs about Medicines among Egyptian Vitiligo Patients&lt;/a&gt;
 published in Dermatologic Theraphy Journal in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
