<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/victorfaynberg/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/victorfaynberg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Digital Egyptian Gazette</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/victorfaynberg/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polo in Egypt: An Attendance Analysis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-faynberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-faynberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What first comes to mind when hearing the term “polo”? Is it a horse? A grassy field? A shirt worn to a somewhat formal occasion? While the term is indeed applicable for all three of these, for the purpose of this analysis I will focus on the Polo relating to the first two. By this I am referring to one of the oldest sports to still be played today. Polo is a team sport where four members of each team mount their horses and, with mallets in hand, strive to direct a ball between a set of goal posts. The game is divided into four to six periods called “chukkers” lasting 7 minutes each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origin of the horseback sport can be traced back to Central Asia as early as 600 B.C. These nomads originated a variation of the game including teams with as many as 100 men to a side, with the main purpose of the sport being military training. After the nomads migration into Persia, polo became a national sport and its popularity blossomed. The invention of modern polo can be credited to British tea planters in Manipur, India, establishing the first polo club known as The Silchar Polo Club. This foundation set in 1859 quickly spread across Europe, becoming popular in Malta, England, and Ireland within a short period of time after its genesis. Polo became a very popular activity for militaries, especially once the game found its way to the United States for its ability to improve the riding skills of cavalrymen, teach leadership qualities, and develop camaraderie among troops. A further history of the sport can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polomuseum.com/sport-polo/history-polo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;

The Egyptian Gazette highlights the sport quite often and it is without a doubt one of the more popular sports in the region. The Gazette makes reference to 12 teams over the span of 1906-1908 as well as four tournaments. My analysis project is set to discover which of these teams produce the greatest amount of “interesting games” as I would like to call them as well as if there is a relation to the amount of interesting games a team has to the spectator turnout for that team’s polo match. I will also be looking into the attendance for each of the four Major tournaments the Gazette reports on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-methodology&#34;&gt;Step 1: Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of this project, I set out to discover which team creates the most amount of what I like to call “interesting games.” I have classified these as games where the final score pins the teams within two goals of each other. For example, games ending 3-1 or 3-2 would be considered interesting. However, games ending 3-0, 4-1, etc. would not be classified as “interesting games.” Also, I did not include tie games into my “interesting games” category despite being within the two goal margin. A widespread opinion in modern sports culture is that tie games can ruin great events and I do believe in this to an extent. Therefore, for the purpose of this study they will not be included. While looking at which teams created the most interesting games, I plan on showing my results with the total amount of games played by each team to see the ratio of games played by a specific team resulting in “interesting games” to total games.
Next, I will be looking into which teams gathered how many spectators. The Gazette often reports the amount of spectators, however I noticed it mostly mentions the crowd during tournament events and not single match friendlies. Hence why there will be more reported scores in my analysis than reported attendances. In this analysis, I will scale the attendance on a point based system giving 0.5 points for a “fair” crowd, 1.0 point for a “large” crowd, and 1.5 points for a “very large” crowd, while giving 0 points for events where attendance was failed to be reported. This will be known as a team’s “Attendance Score.” With the number of interesting games and Attendance score acquired, I will then compare the two to see 1. Which team provides the greatest quantity of interesting games, 2. Which team gathers the greatest amount of spectators, and 3. Is there a correlation between these two variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will use the same method as I did to find Attendance Scores for independent teams as I will for the major events, giving each event their own Attendance Score. I will then divide this by the maximum number of points possible to provide more accurate results. I will do this for if an event is shown for example 10 times in the newspaper and garners a 5 attendance score, than it will be evenly compared with another event shown 5 times that finishes with a score of 2.5. Despite, 5&amp;gt;2.5, the adjusted attendance score would conclude the two events to be equal in drawn attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-querying&#34;&gt;Step 2: Querying&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My analysis resulted in two main query searches. Unfortunately, many of the authors of prior deliverables used different headings in their ‘div’ sections, with some not making the polo section its own ‘div’ all together. Therefore, I used the query //div[@type=&amp;ldquo;page&amp;rdquo;][contains(., &amp;ldquo;chukker&amp;rdquo;)] to search out all dates where there was a reported score for a match. I used the term chukker for each it appears every time there is a reported score in the Gazette. After using this, I manually transferred the teams and scores into an excel document, for there was no uniform way the Gazette reported scores and thus making it almost impossible to make a specific query to target the scores. I also took note of any mention of spectators during this search. My second query served as a backup to my first to find any additional reports of a polo score. Within the Gazette, the team roster is most often mentioned and can be transferred into oxygen by use of a table. One of the players on the team is noted as ‘back’ identifying him as a defensive type player. This term back often appears in a cell within a table and therefore I used the query //table//cell[contains(.,’back’)] to find these tables and see if any reported scores not found in the first query pop up here. Surely enough, I was able to find 6 additional dates with reported scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-data-visualization&#34;&gt;Step 3: Data Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Analysis1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Analysis2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Analysis3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Analysis4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Analysis5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-analysis&#34;&gt;Step 4: Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were twelve teams identified by my query. The Tourists, 60th Rifles, Freebooters, The Mosquitos, Egyptian Army, K.S.C., Inniskilling Dragoons, Coldstream Guards, K.O.S.B, Civilians, Capt. Bartlett&amp;rsquo;s Team, and Staff and Departmental. After running my test and plugging my data into Tableau, the first table shows a stacked bar graph comparing the total amount of games played per team to the amount classified as “interesting.” As seen in the graph, the Inniskilling Dragoons lead the way by means of “interesting games”, followed closely by Egyptian Army and Coldstream Guards. Interestingly enough, the Coldstream Guards lead the group in total games played yet rank third. Less than half of their games played were classified as ‘interesting.’ The Freebooters played only 3 games, however all of their matches can be deemed interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shifting to the second visualization, where I look at Attendance Scores for each team, Inniskilling Dragoons once again lead the charge followed by Coldstream Guards. However, Egyptian army seems to have fallen off for its Attendance score ranks 7th among the 12 teams. Staff and Departmental while only playing 5 games managed to rank third in this category. K.O.S.B and K.S.C both ranked the same in the amount of “Interesting Games”, however, K.S.C finished much higher in Attendance score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third visualization is what I deem to be the most important of the bunch as it shows if there is any connection between the two variables. The upward sloping line of best fit does conclude that despite the small sample size, there indeed seems to be a direct relation between the two, with an increase in teams that play interesting games result in a greater turnout of spectators.
Shifting away from individual teams and into the major events, there are four that the Gazette reports: The Gordon Cup, The Junior Polo Championship, The Polo Cup, and the Open Cup. The fourth visualization shows total attendance per major event and has the Gordon Cup leading the way. The fifth visualization takes this statistic and adjusts it for the maximum amount of potential points. For example, if an event was reported three times, then the maximum points would be 4.5. If the reported Attendance score was 3, then the efficiency score would be .66. This bar graph shows a more accurate result than the fourth, resulting in the Polo Cup drawing the biggest number of spectators per match, surpassing the Gordon cup. This conclusion leads me to believe if both the Gordon Cup and Polo Cup were reported and equal amount of times, the Polo cup would achieve a higher attendance score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-conclusion&#34;&gt;Step 5: Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after all of this, what does it all mean and is there any significant value to this analysis? The short answer is yes, there is significant value. While being very limited in the quantity of analyzed attendances, there is an upward trend between the two variables. An important conclusion that could be considered is the fact that the newspaper serves as a medium of information for these games, and for readers of these newspapers, seeing exciting matchups between teams may entice residents to go out and see these teams perform. It is difficult to find a connection between these numbers and the economy for these were not regulated by any governing association. A further study could investigate the formation of rivalries between squads as I noticed a few matchups appeared much more than others such as the Coldstream Guards and K.S.C. playing the most head to head games at four. These rivalries could also be compared to attendances later down the line when the game is better regulated for I know present day professional sport teams draw bigger crowds when a big rivalry is in town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to note a possibility for error in my analysis. There were only 25 reported matches over the span of three years, which seems very low, as well as attendance numbers only showing up during tournament dates rather than single match friendlies. With more data, the trend line could be shifted and therefore alter my conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Brings in the Crowds for Sporting Events?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-sports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, sports have impacted the lives of not only the participants, but also the fans who choose to watch them. As the sports group, we decided to focus our analysis project on the different factors which can affect spectator turnout across the major sports of the Egyptian Gazette. Among residents of early 1900’s Egypt, three of the most popular sports were football (soccer), polo, and horse racing. By looking into the data that we have collected for these sports, we are able to get an idea of what Egyptian sport fans wanted to see. Through our analysis of the Egyptian Gazette data and cross-checking with multiple studies on attendance of various sports, we have concluded that in early 1900’s Egypt, there were three major factors of sports attendance: level of competition/skill of either side, rivalry between the two sides, and importance/stakes of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of how to get fans in attendance of sporting events is nothing new; as long as there have been sports, there have been those in charge trying to increase attendance. Especially recently, sporting events provide a large stream of revenue, so factors which influence attendance are important information for those involved in sports. Experts and researchers, such as John Douvis and Peter Bird, have tried finding these factors in many different ways across a wide range of sports. These publications are looking at current factors, of which many do not apply to early 1900’s Egypt, however common themes across generations have held true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to collect this data, we ran a series of XPath queries aimed at finding as many games as possible for each sport. We searched for the “sport and play” sections of the newspaper, where sports data and stats are most often found. One problem we came across was that many of the sport and play sections were not tagged with the sport feature type. To combat this, we removed //div[@feature=”sport”] from our queries and replaced it with //head[matches(.,’sport and play’, ‘i’)]. What this did was return to us any div with the header “Sport and Play,” which only included sport and play sections. We utilized this along with searching for sport-specific terms like “chukker” (polo) to collect the full data range that was available to us. We also realized that many sections use qualitative descriptions instead of numbers for attendance data. These sections often used the same terms, such as “fine,” “large,” and “very large,” so we recorded these descriptions anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;football&#34;&gt;Football&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Football was one of the most popular sports at the time, often played between different military regiments or schools. The military teams, such as the Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, were split into teams or “companies,” although they did sometimes compete together. This brings us to our first factor of attendance, level of competition.
&lt;img src=&#34;soccer2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Football&#34; title=&#34;Attendance of each football game&#34;&gt;
When looking at the attendance data for these games, the effect of this factor becomes clear. The matches with high attendance are all between two of the military unit teams at full strength, and not divided into companies. Matches between two of the subdivided units, such as the Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers F. and D. Companies, tended to have much less attendance than the more high-profile competitions. This, of course, is logical because more fans are going to be willing to attend a game if it is between two good teams. The research of Peter J. W. N. Bird on league football attendance also supports this factor. In 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www-jstor-org.proxy.lib.fsu.edu/stable/2348449?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“The Demand for League Football,”&lt;/a&gt;
 Bird looks at various teams and determined that whether or not the team was a contender during the season or a contender for the play-offs was a highly significant factor with a strong positive relation to attendance. Continuing with this first factor, the skill level of the away team appears to also play a role.
&lt;img src=&#34;soccer3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Football2&#34; title=&#34;Football attendance vs margin of victory&#34;&gt;
The data above shows that there was significantly higher attendance in games where the away team had a bigger the margin of victory (shown by the points below 0). This correlation is strikingly direct, and displays an positive relationship between attendance and away team performance. This suggests a number of things, but we concluded the reason for this trend is that when a good team is in town, fans in the area would be likely to attend the game. Often, teams would have large gaps between games at the same away location, so fans understood that each of these games was the last time they could see the team for a while.  This is supported by Hal Hansen and Roger Gauthier, who in 1989 researched and collected 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://content.ebscohost.com/ContentServer.asp?T=P&amp;amp;P=AN&amp;amp;K=16462549&amp;amp;S=R&amp;amp;D=s3h&amp;amp;EbscoContent=dGJyMNLr40Sep644wtvhOLCmr1Gep7dSsKa4TbSWxWXS&amp;amp;ContentCustomer=dGJyMPGrsUi2pq5MuePfgeyx43zx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;40 different factors&lt;/a&gt;
 which impact attendance. Included in these are the record of the visiting team and the number of star athletes on the visiting team. Like it does for the home team, the skill level of the away team makes people more inclined to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;polo&#34;&gt;Polo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the oldest team sports in history, polo was also very popular in early 1900’s Egypt. Like football, polo was often played by military regiments, but polo also included more organized teams. Because there was more parity between teams, attendance is more uniform across games than football.
&lt;img src=&#34;polo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Polo&#34; title=&#34;Attendance of polo games&#34;&gt;
Polo attendance in the Egyptian Gazette was only recorded as “fair,” “large,” or “very large,” so we decided to display these terms numerically 1-3 for our data visualization. Our second attendance factor, rivalry or repeated matchups, applies to our polo data. Teams like the 60th Rifles, the Mosquitos, the Egyptian Army, and the Tourists played each other more often than other teams did, and thus drew significantly bigger audiences for their games. This factor is corroborated by Hansen and Gauthier, who have “Rivalry between competing home team and opponent” as a significant factor. G.V. Wall, a researcher who analyzed attendance of Toronto Blue Jays’ games, also determined that rivalry is an 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sparti.uop.gr/~toda/asmrj/Vol1_c.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“especially prominent indicator of attendance.”&lt;/a&gt;
 As teams play each other more, the competitiveness of the matchup rises, and fans are more interested in the result. Along with this, these teams played more games in general, meaning fans were more familiar with them and more likely to attend a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;horse-racing&#34;&gt;Horse Racing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next sport of the Egyptian Gazette that we are analyzing is horse racing. The data we found for horse racing was unique to that of our other sports because of the different stats and measurements that are recorded for it. First of all, these races all had different stakes and payouts for 1st-3rd place. Helouan was very popular venue for these horse races, but most of these races tended to be lower stakes, more recreational competitions. Instead, we are focusing on the derbies or “plates” with higher stakes. Along with the increased competition, spectators were drawn to these races because of the money on the line. Some of these plates had first place prizes upwards of 25,000 Egyptian pounds, which naturally generated more interest from fans.
&lt;img src=&#34;horse.png&#34; alt=&#34;HorseRacing&#34; title=&#34;Stakes for each race&#39;s top 3 finishers&#34;&gt;
We call this factor the importance factor, because spectators are generally more interested in competitions that are more important and have more on the line, whether it be prize money or a championship trophy. This factor is why, for example, NBA Finals games are more watched than regular season competitions. The importance factor stems from a combination of multiple other factors, as many things go into how “important” a competition is. In the case of horse racing in the Egyptian Gazette, this importance comes from the large sums of money available to the winners. Unsurprisingly, the plates highest in prize amounts are the plates which were most popular and anticipated. The Sahara Stakes is especially significant, boasting a 33,000 first place prize, and a second-place prize double that of any other race we found. These plates are among the most popular of any sporting event in the Egyptian Gazette because of their high stakes and intensity. The importance factor is also seen in the sport of billiards. Despite its popularity, the data found for billiards in the newspaper is rather sparse. However, we can see that the attendance in the match referred to as the “final match” was described as “smoking” and “a concert,” as opposed to others which just state that attendance was “few.” Overall, the factor of importance describes how much the average fan cares about the result of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across any sport, there are common factors which influence spectator turnout. The level of competition, or the skills of either team, is our first attendance factor. Fans would rather watch competition between two good teams than two poor ones, so games with better participants competing will draw more of a crowd. Specifically, in the case of football, the skill of the away team also impacts attendance, as more fans will go to a game if the visiting team is especially good. Rivalries are also a significant factor in attendance, because as two teams continue to play each other, the intensity and emotions of the matchup increase with each game. Finally, fans have more interest in important games with higher stakes and more on the line. When the competition has a large prize, like in horse racing, or is a championship, like in billiards, people have more interest in the outcome of the game and are more likely to choose to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Mummies? A Midlife-Crisis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-15-faynberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-15-faynberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing screams excitement more than finding a new &lt;em&gt;Mummy&lt;/em&gt; to add to your cherished collection. Well, at least this is the case for novelist Pierre Loti who seems to have struck gold in the next piece of his mummy collection. Yes, you read that correctly. Pierre Loti possessed a collection of ancient Egyptian Mummies. This new mummy is said to hold a young princess and Loti claims it is one of the best in his collection, but never explains in what way. Best preserved? Best wrapped? Either way, Mr. Loti seems to be excited about his find. In Loti’s book &lt;em&gt;La mort de Philae&lt;/em&gt;, he records his visit to Egypt and the Museum of Antiquities in Cairo as can be seen 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://anubis4_2000.tripod.com/subpages1/Loti.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierre Loti was born in 1850 in Rochefort, France. His birth name is Louis Marie-Julien Viaud with Pierre Loti being his pseudonym. He was raised in a very religious family, reading the Bible every day and originally aspiring to become a pastor. His career path changed as he desired to adventure around the world. More information about Loti&amp;rsquo;s upbringing can be found in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.museeprotestant.org/en/notice/pierre-loti-1850-1923-2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
 article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superstitions run high in Egypt during this time and touching the dead is a big no. With religion being a focal point in Ancient Egypt, mummification was believed to be a way to preserve the body for resurrection as described by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.historymuseum.ca/cmc/exhibitions/civil/egypt/egcr06e.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
 article. A 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blog post &lt;/a&gt;
 by Claudia Richardson mentions that the dead were buried with an abundance of food for the afterlife. Gwen Lofman in her 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-29-egyptology/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blog Post&lt;/a&gt;
 titled &lt;em&gt;Egyptology &amp;amp; Archeology&lt;/em&gt; mentions how the newspaper served as a medium to share the discovery of these mummies. Loti explains how none of his servants would lay their hands on the body, which resulted in Mr. Loti having to transport it himself. Only when he arrived upstairs with the mummy did he realize he was holding on to a corpse. Either way, he added it to his study just as a kid would add a trophy to his trophy case and went along with his day. A typical day apparently in the life of Pierre Loti. Now if all this didn’t give off enough of an ominous vibe, right by Mr. Loti’s desk in his study resides the mummy of a three year old girl who watches as Loti writes. What an awkward study date that must be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;PL.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PageText&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
