<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mikaylamonaco/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mikaylamonaco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Digital Egyptian Gazette</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mikaylamonaco/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat of the Sun [May 1906-April 1907]</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of climate change on the environment has been something of great controversy and debate in the media. This uncertainty regarding the topic sparked an interest in our group and that was to find the validity of these claims. Our ability to gather different aspects of the weather and relate them to each other was crucial in reaching the results that were acquired. In this project, the main goal is to analyze the weather and heat of the sun in Egypt from May 1906 to April 1907. The subcategories chosen will allow us to see what the impact of the heat of the sun is on subjects such as state of clouds, humidity, maximum and minimum temperatures. Most importantly, we are trying to deduce how all of these factors affect the living conditions in the country of Egypt. The main questions that will be answered is how the heat of the sun varies from May 1906 to April 1907 and how this impacts the humidity, state of clouds, average temperature of Alexandria, and maximum and minimum temperatures in other stations.  The information needed to reach our results will be gathered from the Xpath Queries that will be listed below. This information will then be presented in a bar graph created in Tableau that shows the average heat of the sun monthly and will be compared to the other aspects that affect the climate to see which one plays the largest role. From this visualization we will be able to determine the significance of the data gathered and whether the heat of the sun and other factors of climate are connected in some way or another. Lastly, the results will be placed in historical context to see the importance of the results gathered and whether or not they are supported by the articles we have chosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;xpath-query&#34;&gt;XPath Query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my query, I wanted to pick something that yielded good enough results regarding the Heat of the Sun measures in which we can properly use it in our research, so we&#39;ve come up with this. XPath Query: &lt;code&gt;//table[@xml:id=&amp;quot;deg-ta-dawr01&amp;quot;]/row[matches(.,&#39;heat of the sun&#39;, &#39;i&#39;)]/cell[2]/measure/text()&lt;/code&gt;. In my query, I am limiting the results to only include those from the Daily Weather Report table, as with its corresponding ID. Once I&#39;ve restricted it to the daily weather report, I needed to restrict it further to just the heat of the sun which I did here. I&#39;ve noticed in some of the issues that some people capitalize the phrase &amp;ldquo;Heat of the sun&amp;rdquo; in various ways, so I made it case insensitive with the matches command. This query yielded 120 items, a lot more than what I had expecting and enough results for me to use research on however there were some discrepancies. In the earlier years, 1905 to mid-1906, there weren&#39;t many holes and the data was pretty dense however as I began looking at the results past that, the data begins to thin out, making it hard to use the data. There are many different reasons why this might be. As ironic as it sounds, maybe the &amp;lsquo;Daily Weather Report&amp;rsquo; never actually reported daily, or the students that had the days in which the data was missing never did them, there are several possibilities. As a result, I needed to restrict the timeframe of my research. My initial intent was to explore the heat of the sun index across all years however the data given made it near impossible to do that. Because of this, I&#39;ve decided to restrict it to 1 year, where the data works best in and that was from May 1905 to April 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-visualization&#34;&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have my query results, I needed to take my results and make a visualization out of it. Because my data was dense in my specified timeframe, doing an average of each month was the best thing to do in order to give a visualization of what my data represents as the sample size was large enough to accurately depict the indexes for each month. After putting the results in a spreadsheet, transferring it to Tableau, and averaging the measures per its corresponding month I&#39;ve come up with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;datavisualization1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;data visualization&#34; title=&#34;Initial Bar Graph of Heat of the Sun Averages for each month.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the visualization here is good, as it gives a good initial representation of the heat of the sun averages for each month, as you can tell the graph spikes in October 1906 and sinks in December 1906. As a result, I began to find out why this is happening and noticed that it was an error in the data source. In one of the days for October, the measure was 452, blowing the average way out of proportion. Likewise, with December, a day had a measure of 8, lowering the average. This wasn&#39;t too big of a deal as we are only dealing with averages. Simply excluding the two days with the incorrect measures is all I needed to do in order to make the graph accurately representable of what we are trying to research, so that is what I did. After doing this, the graph looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;datavisualization.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;data visualization&#34; title=&#34;Revised Bar Graph of Heat of the Sun Averages for each month.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can tell, the data flows much better as the months go by. The visualization almost depicts a sinusoidal function as time goes by, where the averages of the heat of the sun peaks in the summer months and flows smoothly until it troughs into the winter months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;significance-of-the-data&#34;&gt;Significance of the Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Daily Weather Report” in the “Egyptian Gazette” gives readers information about the weather for the upcoming day. There are many different columns which describe various sections that relate to the weather like humidity, force of the anemometer, maximum and minimum temperatures, and most importantly, heat of the sun. When looking at the heat of the sun data, it is clear that there is significance behind it. The topic itself is odd; when we look at the weather forecast these days, there is no “heat of the sun” column. We focus on the maximum and minimum temperature for the day and if necessary, the probability of rain. Thus, this begs the question as to why readers of the “Egyptian Gazette” would want to know the heat of the sun for every single day. One reason for this may be that readers would want to know how the sun is heating the earth. The heat of the sun and the temperature are two different thing; the heat of the sun demonstrates how much the sun is heating up the earth, while the temperature shows how hot or cold it is on a specific day. The heat from the sun tends to stay in the ground for a while, and the more sun exposure that the earth gets, the warmer the earth feels. When looking at our data from May 1906 to April 1907, one can tell that the heat of the sun fluctuates throughout the course of the year. The graph shows steady growth during the summer months, reaches its peak during July, and eventually evens out when it comes to the winter and spring months.  Looking at this graph, one can see that the heat of the sun was significantly  higher during fall and summer when compared to the winter and spring months. Particularly, the heat of the sun measures do not start to decline until October and November, two months not commonly known for their excessive heat. However, it can be determined that the reason behind this, is because the earth is moving away from the sun, but all of the heat is still left over from the summer months. It is like how the longest day of the year occurs during the summer solstice, but the hottest day occurs during end of July and early August.  This data is significant because it gives readers a better insight into the heat of the sun in Alexandria, Egypt from 1906-1907. Not a ton of research is published that shows how the heat of the sun changes during the early 1900’s. The “Egyptian Gazette” provides us and other readers or researchers with additional information that was recorded firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;historical-context&#34;&gt;Historical Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the group decides to dig deeper into the Egyptian Gazette issues, weather patterns around the country in the early 1900s make themselves pretty obvious. Although all that can be done on our half is make predictions about why that is so and how the future can be affected, there are luckily an abundance of secondary sources that use previously gathered weather data from parts of Egypt during this same time frame. A specific article that was found discusses the temperature change in the Nile Delta compared over three different eras: 1900-1947, 1950-1981, and 1982-2010. The article is linked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/303018027_Temperature_trend_over_Nile_Delta_Egypt_during_20th_Century&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for reference. It takes measurements from three of Egypt’s busiest ports, those being Cairo, Port Said, and the Port of Alexandria. A lot of the data that we found to exist in the newspaper issues goes along with the data provided in this article, which draws many interesting conclusions. In a historical sense, the winter of 1904 was a particularly dry season for Egypt in comparison to years past and prior. This means the transition into spring and summer would probably be more difficult with less moist soil, making it hard to harvest food. This would further explain the lack of ads included in the Egyptian Gazette issues during the spring months of 1904 because of the drought that occurred the winter prior. As technology advanced in cities like Alexandria, the question of how real global warming became popularized. People began to worry about how transportation would continue to make life more efficient, and how individuals would obtain shelter and food to feed their families with. The overall results concluded in the newspaper issues over time and other data surrounding similar topics found in primary sources test the validity of climate change on the state of Egypt. Correlating different components of Egypt’s climate with their personal statistics can tell the audience about what to expect for Egypt’s future and how to best prepare for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-remarks&#34;&gt;Research Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing this research, there were a few remarks that I would like to point out regarding the accuracy of a given data element and how that can ultimately skew your research. Initially, as I began constructing my XPath Query, as I&#39;ve discussed before, the data isn&#39;t always perfect. The query did not yield results for every single day in all 3 years. The results were dense in the earlier years but as time went by, that data began to thin out, making it very difficult to pick apart data that can accurately represent what I am trying to research. Even though the data that was presented, yielded, some of the measures were wrong, due to human error. For me, as I was dealing with averages across each month, the human error threw my data visualization off-proportion, in which I had to change. I am by no means saying that these digital methods of acquiring data are bad. In fact, the ability to use a query to yield results from various newspapers over several years is very efficient. However, a weakness of researching through digital methods is that the data presented isn&#39;t always accurate, questioning the validity and accuracy of the research itself. Furthermore, the data could be missing, also highlighting the inaccuracy of the data element.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximum Heat of the Sun in Different Stations Across Alexandria [May 1906-April 1907]</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-monaco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-monaco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall goal of this individual analysis project is to analyze a
range of maximum temperatures from data taken from different stations
in Alexandria, Egypt. I chose to investigate the timeline of May 1906
to April 1907 with the hopes of finding whether or not there are
correlations between the temperature of each location themselves. In
combination to this, I also will make inferences between why some
stations are higher than others and how that can relate to how busy
they are. With this in mind, I can further make inferences about foot
traffic and how that affects pollution levels in more popular or less
popular places, inherently affecting temperature data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of general questions that motivated me to focus
on this topic. The general topic of my group analysis project had to
do with looking at temperature change over the decades over the
country of Egypt, so I knew I had to do something within those
parameters. One guiding question I came up with is as follows:
“Do the measures in the heat of the sun section from the ‘Daily
Weather Report’ part of each issue of the newspaper flow accordingly
throughout the months recorded and will this data bring about any
sort of significance on other topics prevalent during this time in
Alexandria?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take a genuine interest in climate change as a global topic in the
present, so seeing how it influenced and was reported in the past was
something I was excited to learn more about. After I drafted this
first question, I began to make inferences about what I thought would
answer the question. Recalling the historical time period of the
European and American Industrial Revolution, I drafted this next
sub-question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How do higher temperatures recorded in various stations around
Alexandria change with the increase in industrialization measures?
With the past two general questions in mind, I decided to combine
them and some other smaller thoughts into the one big question that
serves as a general guideline of the project. It is stated below:
“With the investigation of the maximum temperature data taken from
various issues of the Egyptian Gazette from May 1907-April 1908, what
changes are clearly visible from location to location and how can
these implications be discussed in a social climate?”
Furthermore, let us continue the investigation by taking an interest
in the XPath Query I used to find the basic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;xpath-query&#34;&gt;XPath Query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as the XPath Query goes, I wanted to make sure I chose a
search that would funnel out all of the data I did not need, leaving
me with relevant and applicable numbers. Using the entirety of the
content folder from Github as the identification of sources I was
searching from, I used the following query to find the maximum
temperatures as recorded in different stations in Alexandria covered
in issues of the Egyptian Gazette : //table//cell[contains(.,&amp;lsquo;Max.
Temp &amp;lsquo;)]/following-sibling::cell[1]/text(). This search will give me
the results I need and exclude any irrelevant data, like minimum
temperatures for example. Each issue of the Egyptian Gazette has a
“Daily Weather Report” including a multitude of sources of
information. Some of these sources include the “Maximum Temperatures”
table, the “Minimum Temperatures” table, and more. Once I&#39;ve
restricted it to the daily weather report, I needed to restrict it
further to just the heat of the sun which I did here. The last part
of the query including the “text()” is something I included to leave
the option open for me to further consolidate my research. Just for
interest, I filled in vocabulary such as “population” and “climate”
to learn more about the subject in context. But, the main usage for
this part of the query is where I ended up figuring out how to search
for the time period I was looking for. I got a little over 50 results
from this query, which I thought was a pretty good number to work off
of. Although my group and I originally decided to leave the data
unrestricted because we thought a lot of tables would have holes in
them, we decided to collectively and individually constrict the data
to about a year’s time so we could make quick predictions about
future weather reports across Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-visualization&#34;&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After gathering the data results from Oxygen, I then exported them
into an Atom file and used regular expressions to eliminate
unnecessary components. After this, I continued to export the edited
Atom data to a spreadsheet which was then opened in Tableau. After
playing around with the design of the graph and choosing the axes, I
decided to make a side bar graph to display the results I felt would
be most welcoming to the individual interpreting it. The visual is
below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![data visualization](datavisualization.jpg &amp;ldquo;Initial Bar Graph of Heat
of the Sun Averages for each month.&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My original plan was to create a couple of graphs displaying the
average temperatures in each location as recorded in the Egyptian
Gazette , but while deciphering the data from Oxygen, I changed my
mind. I found there were a lot of gaps in the data over the time
period I chose, which was concerning. I figured it would not be a
very accurate form of data if one station has way more numbers to
factor in than another, which is the main reason I decided to just
keep it simple and use a wholly average graph. A lot of the
components of the graph had dashes instead of actual data points,
which led me to believe maybe the data was inefficiently taken or
there was an issue during publication of the section. If we look at
the visual presented above, maximum temperatures spark during both
April and July. There is a severe decrease in overall maximum
temperatures in January and more obviously February. This was one of
my initial predictions for the data visualization as I figured the
temperature rates would be consistent with the season they were filed
into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an overall sense, the data flows pretty well in the graph above. I
do think it would have been helpful to include the graphs displaying
averages per station from May 1907-April 1908, but I also think it is
important to keep the data as accurate as possible. The whole idea of
this project is generally looking at the effects of high temperatures
in different places and how that impacted parts of society back then.
A general graph supports a general idea, so I believe that “Figure 1”
graph gives a good idea and supports the overarching idea of the
study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;significance-of-the-data&#34;&gt;Significance of the Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this subtopic particularly interesting because I take an
interest in climate change presently, so I think it’s cool to look at
the range between low and high temperatures in Alexandria during the
time period specified. Focusing more on maximum temperatures taken at
different stations in Alexandria lead to explanations dealing with
problems affected by high temperatures. These can range from health
problems, like maybe an increase in sickness with warmer weather or
in response to pollution. A link to a published book that I found on
Google Scholar, Observed Changes in Minimum and Maximum Temperature in
Nile Delta, Egypt in the 20th Century, by Ebtisam Mohamed and Maged
Hussein discuss the increase in temperature in the popular river
throughout the 1900s. Both authors take a range of temperature
samples from the Port Said location and the Cairo weather station
while simultaneously running multiple statistical tests to find
correlations. This article includes data on an annual scale, which is
cool to look at because it corresponds with the data found in the
Egyptian Gazette .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.almanhal.com/Reader/Article/85154&#34;&gt;Link to book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;historical-context&#34;&gt;Historical Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to other nations adopting the industrial standard in the
late nineteenth century and the beginning of the twentieth century,
Alexandria was no exception. An article published by Professor Bent,
an instructor at the University of Oxford, discusses agrarian change
throughout Egypt from 1800-1950. Although this is a super broad time
period, it does include the annual range included in my data and
observations. Bent concluded that the industrial revolution in Egypt
earned its start towards the 1860s-1890s, and proceeded with more
efficiently produced technology up until about the 1930s (Bent 4).
From then on, scientists and business analysts alike researched
efficient and inefficient trends in consumer behavior and the
environmental impacts. I thought this study was pretty interesting to
read because it advocates the interconnectedness of people and
businesses, and how everything impacts the environment as a whole. In
the topic of maximum temperatures, more severe changes to the
environment seem to take measures according to Brent. A higher
population means more pollution concentrated in an area, which will
raise the overall temperature as plotted by the temperature charts.
This can lead to further investigation into how the climate will
change in certain areas dependent upon how many people inhabit that
area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-remarks&#34;&gt;Research Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the process that served as the basis for this
investigation, I have learned a lot about the accuracy of data
collected from the Egyptain Gazette , basic ways to interpret
microfilm, and its overall importance and further implications. I
feel all of these subjects are vital to understand. As far as
accuracy goes, the initial holes that I found in my data when
researching specific stations and dates for their data showed me that
there were times errors occurred and the result was a lack in
numbers. Every time this happened in an issue which I found in Atom,
it decreased the general value of that specific issue and its weather
section specifically. Studying past weather trends, especially in
ever changing climates like Egypt, is important in giving us
information to base predictions for climate change in the future.
Further applicable case studies can be used in similar experimental
designs to show correlations in more detailed settings, but in order
to study the most trustworthy data, you need trustworthy numbers.
This is not always available in the case of the Egyptian Gazette.
Moving on to the actual scanning of the microfilm itself, I learned a
lot about what individuals were interested back then as I performed
markups on the XML documents. The advertisements paid for by the
supplier taught me a lot about graphic design back in the day and
market/advertising design. Using primary sources like issues from the
Egyptian Gazette is extremely helpful in deciphering data from older
sources. This newspaper was produced more than a century ago and is
preserved, thanks to technology, until more than the next century. If
computers, software, and scanning machines were not around today,
then it would take a lot more work in researching and displaying the
data collected for this topic. Although there are some issues with
how trustworthy the data collected is, the technology used to
interpret the data is very helpful in displaying it and sharing it
for others to learn from or be motivated by.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandria-Brussels Vessel Missing</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-19-monaco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-19-monaco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Tuesday issue of ​The Egyptian Gazette​ for the week of November 18, 1907, there is a specific ad which, at first glance, I figured was for a new company providing travel by ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the pages of the days that I’ve gone through so far with these deliverables have been ads for hotels, chocolate companies like Nestle, and more. But when I first saw this ad and researched a bit about its possible background, it came to my surprise that there was barely any information on the event, and it didn’t have a specific title to search by either. Using our present media and technology outlets, it would seem as if the event never occurred. But according to the newspaper, a vessel embarking from Alexandria en route to Brussels went missing months prior in the same year of 1907. It did not say much about the last place the vessel was seen, and all it said about its passengers was that they were men, women, and children all travelling to Brussels for various reasons, including work and vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In researching events during that time period that could match up with the ad included in Tuesday’s issue, I found multiple sources that helped me to interpret the event. In the beginning of my findings, I came across an image that represents what an Egyptian vessel would have looked like at the time of this ad’s publication. This image and the page is linked ​&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SS_Heliopolis_(1907)&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;​. In finding this image, I now have a clearer idea of what the missing vessel discussed in the ad might’ve looked like. I also found a link to a missing vessel en route from the US to Portugal that coast guards believe contained a significant amount of passengers from Brussels. The link to the missing vessel report is included &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marinetraffic.com/en/ais/details/ships/shipid:133862/mmsi:255806004/imo:9200691/vessel:BRUSSELS&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.​ I compared this information to the ad included in the issue of ​The Egyptian Gazette​, and this is what I think a more modern version of the ad would be today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
