<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Football | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/football/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Football</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Football</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/football/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Varsity Match of Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-bolger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-bolger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, March 5th, 1906, the Egyptian Gazette posted an article about football in their &amp;ldquo;Sport and Play&amp;rdquo; section. An &amp;ldquo;enthusiast&amp;rdquo; sent in the article of the summary of this football game hoping that the Egyptian Gazette would be kind enough as to give this &amp;ldquo;enthusiast&#39;s&amp;rdquo; article a corner of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this article was made in 1906, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.egyptianplayers.com&#34;&gt;football&lt;/a&gt; was one of the the most popular sports in Egypt. Egyptians would use to gather around to watch their various clubs play, including the Egyptian &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Fling-Sports/&#34;&gt;national football team&lt;/a&gt;, almost on a daily basis. No matter what level of play it was, football was a big deal wherever it was played in Egypt. There were many other &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.touregypt.net/historicalessays/ancsportsindex.htm&#34;&gt;sports in Egypt&lt;/a&gt;, including polo, which was another popular sport in the Middle East, but football, at the time, stood out amongst all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The match that was being played was referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Varsity match of Egypt&amp;rdquo;. It is one of the most important football matches in Egypt played between Khedivieh and Tewfikieh Schools. This was the first inter-school match played between the teams since December 28th, 1905, with Khedivieh beating Tewfikieh School two goals to one. The Khedivial and Tewfikieh Schools were two secondary schools that had a long standing rivalry in football. There were other secondary schools in Upper Egypt, including Girgeh, Ketieh, and Assouan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tewfikieh boys won the coin toss, but ten minutes into the game, Mahmoud Ali, left wing for Khedivial, scored for the first point of the game. Then, near the end of the first half, the Khedivial centre forward, Ahmed Aly, who is the brother of the player that scored the first goal, added another point for his team to make the score two goals to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole second half was pretty even, as the Khedivial boys topped their rivals two goals to love. This was the 6th consecutive match that the Khedivial School have ended up as the victors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odd Football Score</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-15-fling-sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-15-fling-sports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 20, 1905 the Egyptian Gazette posted a section about football at the bottom left corner of Page three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Zealander Football team is the best of the best. In London, on November 18, as suspected, they won another game with the score of 624 to 22. This is a very odd fact because the game of football usually can not reach such high point counts. Unsure of why the score was so high, I began to wonder if &amp;ldquo;football&amp;rdquo; really meant the game of football&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, the New Zealander Football team was most likely a Rugby team. This is inferred by the time period of the newspaper, and also the location of Alexandria. Rugby is a form of football, but not the original game we play here in the States. The objective of Rugby is to carry and/or kick a ball over the other team&#39;s goal line. There are a few ways to score in rugby: try = 5 points, conversion goal = 2 points, penalty goal = 3 points, drop goal = 3 points. Being such small increments of points, it&#39;s questionable how the New Zealanders team scored 624 points in this game recorded in the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This area was known for their interest in sporting activities. Often, sporting events are mentioned in the Egyptian Gazette. This shows that the demand for sporting information and updates was at a high demand in the Alexandria area. The community, as a whole, enjoyed the sporting events and kept up with their favorite team&#39;s Win/Loss ratio through the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
