<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OCR | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/ocr/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/ocr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>OCR</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>OCR</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/ocr/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reflection on the Tech</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-into-the-rabbit-hole-technical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-into-the-rabbit-hole-technical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like this second blog post is going to saturated with negatives, so I&#39;ll try to keep mine a little brighter by starting with the fact that this initially pain-staking process has really grown on me. At first it was a total chore, slowly trouble shooting every single issue that I had with the multiple programs I had no familiarity with (Oxygen, ABBYY Finereader, and Github), wishing that my advisor would&#39;ve warned better beforehand of such things and hoping that I would have a free weekend again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after about 3 solid weeks of working, something clicked. I started enjoying this previously arduous work. The trouble-shooting became enjoyable, as every issue came to me as an interesting puzzle rather than a pace-breaking wall. Also, the whole philosophy behind this encoding became much clearer to me, and in a way, inspired me to take special care when it came to encoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things on the tech side that I believe led me to enjoying this process more were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a larger monitor to work on: I like having all the information I need to encode in view all at once, it helps me keep things in order and it just keeps things more accurate. Having a monitor that is larger than a standard 13-15-17 in laptop screen really helped me. I was able to pull up boilerplates, have oxygen open, and have a reference scanned image open all in sizes that I could view easily. This expedited the process greatly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a mouse: After trying to encode and OCR on my Surface and comparing it to my work on my desktop, I noticed a night and day difference in quality of pages and general frustration. The mouse allows you to have more exact control of your cursor and gives a less clunky access to your keyboard whilst moving your cursor between multiple points quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and some other technical mishaps/advice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you take the highest quality scans of your microfilm as possible: Because I was foolish and decided to separate my scanning sessions into different days, I ended up getting two different qualities of scans. This made OCR&#39;ing extremely frustrating as it made some pages correctable in about 20 minutes and other pages taking over an hour and a half. In short, SCAN HIGHEST DPI POSSIBLE AND MAKE SURE THE SCANNER GLASS DOES NOT HAVE EXCESSIVE SMUDGING.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always press Ctrl+S or &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; after every page you finish in your issues: It&#39;s been about 3 times that I&#39;ve been so caught up in encoding that I forget to save for a few pages. Inevitably my computer updates or Oxygen crashes, and all that work is lost, leading to one too many instances of my palm colliding with my forehead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml&#34;&gt;TEI webpage&lt;/a&gt; should be considered the holy text of this class. It is referenced by Dr. Hanley, and simple guides are available on dig-eg-gaz. But if you need find anything specific, get spiritual and make a journey into the rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Troubles</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-technology-troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-29-frederick-technology-troubles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first few weeks of this semester I was completely dedicated to toiling for hours in order to receive an “A” in this class. I would stay up until midnight finishing editing text that was OCRd making sure that no detail was overlooked. I would spend hours working on this editing only to go back to it and find that all of my hard work had either disappeared or been undone and not for lack of saving. When I started working with Oxygen, I would find that a file I had just started coding the previous night could not be found when I went to open and edit it the next day. This setback has been a source of major frustration for obvious reasons. I don’t know whether this unfortunate series of events is occurring because of some delayed karma or because I have the dreaded apple computer but it has caused me to become lazy with the workload. That being said, I have prayed to the computer gods to fix my issues so I can save my grade and it seems to have worked so far. In the wake of my realization about how quickly the semester is coming to an end I have kicked back into gear and have decided to push through any and all technical difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCR Woes</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-26-grieco-technical/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-26-grieco-technical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my technical reflection, I have decided to discuss my experiences with the
OCR software, simply because it was easily the most time-consuming and tedious
portion of the technical aspects of this class. Since I have a Mac laptop, I
used the Cisdem OCR software rather than ABBY Finereader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I would like to say is the accuracy with which it translates
the text is quite disappointing. I would estimate that at MOST 60% of the
original text was transcribed to my text editor properly, and even more
frustrating was that specific letters were nearly almost incorrectly written,
for instance the letter “e” for the entirety of the respective pages was often
incorrectly recorded as the letter “a”, and vice versa. Furthermore,
spell-checking entire pages written in French was both lengthy and difficult,
particularly when I could not read some of the words and could not use context
clues to figure out what they were supposed to say (because I do not speak
French). At a certain point I had to simply accept that my XML pages were simply
going to be filled with egregious errors and a certain level of accuracy was
impossible to achieve (much to the chagrin of my mild OCD, but hey it was a
learning experience in patience and Zen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I was not a fan of the OCR software. It was most likely faster than
manually transcribing entire pages of the newspaper, but it was nonetheless
aggravating and stressful. Rant over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficulties with OCR</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-black-difficulties-with-ocr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-black-difficulties-with-ocr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the main goals in this class is to covert an old newspaper into a website that allows it to be easily accessed by anyone. In order to do this we must complete one very vital, and apparently very difficult step: covert pictures of microfilm into reader editable, text. This is called OCR (optical character recognition) and thankfully there are lots of programs available to us to make this process extremely simple, or so it’s thought. One of these programs is ABBYY’s FineReader, which was the one first suggested to us. This program apparently does wonders if you are using a Windows computer, but for us Mac users it only creates disappointment. Instead of converting our images into readable text, it converts them into an agglomeration of random characters that sometimes resemble words in the English language. I’ve provided a short example of one of these “conversions” done on the first few lines of one of my microfilm images. I’ve tried rescanning my images, making adjustments in FineReader, and tried a different OCR program to try and achieve better results and nothing has worked in my favor.  So, instead of making small corrections to the text as it should be, I am forced to basically retype the entire page. This process is &lt;strong&gt;extremely time-consuming&lt;/strong&gt; and I am positive that if I had an OCR program that loved my Mac computer as much as others seem to love Windows ones, I would have completed much more of my work by now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCR OCSucks</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-sain-technical-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-sain-technical-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the whole process of learning new word processing and encoding programs was challenging, the most frustrating aspect was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.abbyy.com/en-us/finereader/about-ocr/what-is-ocr/&#34;&gt;OCR&lt;/a&gt;. It is supposed to be a faster way to translate the newspaper pages into plain text, it turned out to take up about as much time as it would have to hand type it all. I felt as if no matter how many times I scanned the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nedcc.org/free-resources/preservation-leaflets/6.-reformatting/6.1-microfilm-and-microfiche&#34;&gt;microfilm&lt;/a&gt; images and changed the focus, brightness, contrast, or zoomed in on the page, it would not run through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.abbyy.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;ABBYY&lt;/a&gt; in the way I was expecting it to. I was hoping to have to make minimal corrections after the scanned images were OCRed, but with all the pages I have done up to this point, I have had to make a minimum of two hours’ worth of corrections per page. The word processing software may read a majority of the words (I would estimate around 85%), I still spent a majority of my time in this class fixing the mistakes the OCR made. I also found the other programs in this class easier to use than ABBYY. Sometimes while editing a word, the image it received it from would disappear, I also found the ordering of the paragraphs challenging at times. Overall, the program may have saved me some time, but another OCR processor may be more efficient, from my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Difficulties in the Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-06-technical-difficulties-in-ocr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-06-technical-difficulties-in-ocr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first produced my image scans using the library&#39;s microfilm
of the Egyptian Gazette, I thought that by feeding the material into
the OCR software, my computer would automatically spit back the
entire transcription completed error-free. At first I attempted to use
FineReader on my roommate&#39;s laptop, hoping it would yield results, but
when her computer began to lag and I realized how time consuming the
process would be, I switched to using my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the class discovered Cisdem PDF Converter for Mac, I quickly
realized that while some pages contained minimal errors, others required
extensive corrections to yield an accurate reading of the text.
The pages, most of which were rife with errors, took around 2 and a half
hours each to fully type and XML, and even then many advertisements and
charts are still not completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I had completed the vast majority of the transcription, I learned
that by scanning in a higher resolution and stitching multiple images
together, I probably could have produced the paper and a much faster rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I&#39;m continuing to work on completing certain advertisements
and charts, as well as TEI-tagging people and places.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
