<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/jakehimmel/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/jakehimmel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Digital Egyptian Gazette</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/jakehimmel/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine Analysis Project</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many diseases that emerged in the 19th century included cholera, yellow fever, typhus, smallpox, and many more. However, it wasn’t until the late 19th century that weak medical practices became outdated. Before these breakthroughs there was only a basic understanding, which furthermore, commercialized the industry by selling medications with little to know regulation utilizing public fear and desperation. Many campaigns and ads sold the idea of “bad blood” being the cause as these medications were claimed to generate new blood and purify the body. Obviously, we know this is not real science but then, it was all the people knew and believed in regards to infectious diseases that were on a constant rise in the 1900s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;medical-terminology&#34;&gt;Medical Terminology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dr-williams-pink-pills&#34;&gt;Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Book1_15758293045230/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doans-kidney-pills&#34;&gt;Doan&#39;s Kidney Pills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Book1s_15758318890720/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this data, I was able to learn and infer a couple of different things. The first thing that stood out to me was the amount of times the advertisements for these “miracle pills” would come up throughout the Egyptian Gazette. For example, when looking at instances of Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills, in 1905 there were only 16 occurrences of the advertisement. In 1906, that number increased slightly to 19 instances. Then, in 1907, the number skyrocketed to 45 different instances of that advertisement throughout the year in the Egyptian Gazette. When looking Doan’s Kidney Pills, a similar jump can be observed in the Egyptian Gazette. In 1905, 11 instances were recorded, in 1906 12 instances were recorded, and in 1907 the number shot through the roof. This clearly goes to show that the success surrounding these pills was flourishing as much more money was able to be put towards advertising following what I believe was a good year or two of selling their product. I also believe that this is due to this relatively new method of advertising which implemented personal testimonials to sell the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other patterns that I observed from this data was regarding exactly why many of these terms decreased in frequency over the three year time span. I believe after looking at the data and taking a detailed look into what types of treatments that the pills were offering that as medicine became slightly more advanced over this time period, these advertisements began to vouch for treating less and less serious ailments. They instead appear to move towards more general symptoms, the primary one being pain. These advertisements saw an increase in the prevalence of “pain” as pain can be associated with various illnesses, allowing them to generalize to more diseases without distinctly claiming to cure one or the other. As actual treatments for certain illnesses became available, these “miracle pills” began to advertise less towards specific ones and more for general symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of this move towards a better understanding of modern medicine can be seen in the word “blood”. I observed a decrease in the word blood within both advertisements, primarily because medicine was becoming more advanced as actual understanding of the body and pathogens slightly deepened. It was a common misconception that many ailments were caused by an impurity in the blood, and that a way to get new blood was a way to prevent further illnesses. These pills claimed to give “new blood” to the user, although this logic is clearly flawed by today’s understanding. As the understanding of pathology increased during this time period, we can also see a decrease in the word “blood” coming up in the newspaper, leading me to believe that this assumption of blood impurities became less prevalent as other more accurate explanations for illnesses arose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?As for the application of these results to the group project, it ties in strongly with the other topics in the sense that we are able to apply these results to the work of the other topics within this project. For example, by looking at prevalence of words in advertisements, we can infer that certain ailments that are commonly found within the miracle pill advertisements likely also are symptoms of larger diseases that medical schools and hospitals are dealing with. We are able to get a sense for what is affecting the larger population and tie this in by looking at the proper ways that these illnesses and symptoms are being treated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;medical-schools-and-the-diseases-found&#34;&gt;Medical Schools and the Diseases Found&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correlation between the location of medical schools and hospitals with the diseases that were being researched at these medical facilities. By finding if these diseases were prevalent in certain areas, it may be concluded that  the disease was being researched at a prominent medical institution.  The first disease found was Tropical Disease which is mentioned in the Gazette four times. Three of these times were cases within Cairo and the last one was found within Sudan. While this data is not enough to say there was an epidemic, it may be enough to deduce that these areas were experiencing hardships from this disease. The lack of knowledge about this disease stemmed from fear of the collapsing British Empire. One gave a fearful message that the Tropical Disease would lead to the death of the British Empire if it was not completely eradicated. The article then called for the Kasr-el-Ainy and other medical schools to try and find a cure to this disease.  There was only one occurrence of the disease within Sudan at the Gordon College Laboratories,but that is only to talk about trying to find a cure for the animals in that area.   It can be seen by the number of times this disease was mentioned to be in Cairo that this disease was mainly affecting that area during the period of 1905-1906. Also, with the article blatantly warning the public of London about how the disease would cause extreme harm to the British Empire from those who were in Cairo, it can be shown that the disease was mainly affecting this region in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another disease that appeared in the newspaper was trypanosomiasis. This disease was mainly found within Sudan, but upon further inspection it was shown that this disease only stemmed from another disease called sleeping sickness. We used the x-path queries below to research more about sleeping sickness in Sudan and at Gordon College. Sleeping sickness was the main disease that was prevalent since there are 17 occurrences of the term within the newspaper. This disease was being researched by the Gordon College Laboratories in Sudan, but there were articles explaining how the disease was killing off livestock and people within the area of Sudan.Upon further inspection, we wanted to see if there would be a link between the Kasr-el-Ainy and Cairo.  Both of queries yielded no results for either which could mean that the disease was only centralized to Sudan or that a cure was found before it was able to spread to elsewhere. I was able to find one outside resource 
&lt;a href=&#34;search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=edsbl&amp;amp;AN=vdc.100063233501.0x000001&amp;amp;site=eds-live&amp;amp;scope=site.&#34;&gt;Elimination of Sleeping Sickness&lt;/a&gt;
that talked about how political and social conflict within Sudan could lead to a cure for sleeping sickness to be halted. It was a very interesting to see how these disease is still affecting those in Sudan for over 100 years. Also, this article gave me an insight into how modern medicine is now begin used to treat early disease from the 1900s that have caused much harm an area.  The graphs for the analysis of sleeping sickness in Sudan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Kasr-el-Ainy&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;
-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Cairo&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;
-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Sudan&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;
-&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][matches(., &amp;quot;Gordon College&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;i&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/t/dorseydigitalmircolab/views/SleepingSicknessandtrypanosomiasiswithinSudan/Sheet1?:origin=card_share_link&amp;:embed=n:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/#/site/dorseydigitalmircolab/workbooks/60188?:origin=card_share_link&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/t/dorseydigitalmircolab/views/TropicalDiseasesinCairoandSudan/Sheet1?:origin=card_share_link&amp;:embed=n:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;https://prod-useast-a.online.tableau.com/#/site/dorseydigitalmircolab/workbooks/60187?:origin=card_share_link&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diseases&#34;&gt;Diseases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A disease that appeared in the newspaper was the Bubonic Plague or also known as the Third Pandemic. The earliest records of the Bubonic Plague within &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was found on January second of 1905. However, according to history, the first outbreaks of the plague in Egypt took place back in April of 1899 after a long time of disease-free (
&lt;a href=&#34;www.jstor.org/stable/20436191.&#34;&gt;Plague In Egypt&lt;/a&gt;
). The plague has persisted in Egypt each year since 1899 arriving from the trade ports. With that said, that means that the cities closest to the ports must be the ones most affected by it. After gathering the following data through the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and inputting it into Tableau, this statement proved to be correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Bubonicplaguechartdata/Sheet2?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown above, the city that was most frequently affected by the Bubonic Plague was Alexandria. Following Alexandria was Suez, which also has a huge trade port that connects the Red Sea with the Mediterranean Sea. However, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; newspaper explained another possibility of why this might be the case. &amp;ldquo;It is the only town with a drainage system, and many of the drains are in a very dilapidated condition and infested with rats. This may be one of the reasons which account for the persistence of the disease at Alexandria&amp;rdquo; (1906-07-27.xml).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a considerable diminution in the number of cases of plague in Egypt as in the year of 1905. However, the following year, in 1906, the plague spread and the number of cases severely increased. In comparison with 1904, there was a considerable diminution in the number of cases of plague in Egypt as in the year of 1905. However, the following year, 1906, the plague spread and the number of cases severely increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to preventing the spread of this plague, “Clayton Gas” was used in the early 1900s. It destroyed not only rats and vermin, but also the parasites on them and sterilized the eggs of insects as well. Since no cures were discovered until 20 years later, preventions taken towards infected humans were unsuccessful. An important thing to notice is that the infected rat is the cause of the disease remaining endemic in a town, but the epidemic form of the disease is caused by the infected human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph shows how mentions of ad have no correlation to mentions of cholera throughout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/cholera_15753985669840/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one advertisement claims to remedy cholera, diarrhea, colic, and dysentery, and that product is Dr. J. Collis Browne’s Chlorodyne.  Surprisingly enough, the product is only advertised fourteen times over the three years or so of the newspaper that has been encoded.  Further research into Chlorodyne revealed that the medication was an effective treatment for these diseases as well as other ailments not listed in the advertisements.  The reasoning behind its effectiveness were the active ingredients being opiates and marijuana (McCabe, 1979) .  Interestingly enough this advertisement that claims to remedy cholera do not seem to have any correlation to when cholera was mentioned more frequently in the newspaper, even as fears of cholera began to spread within Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an editorial by Charles McCabe written in 1979, he recalls the days when Dr. J. Collis Browne’s Chlorodyne was available everywhere.  McCabe described the potion as  “a staple of British medicine cabinets since 1848.”  He further states that chlorodyne took “care of the most persistent of the traveler’s and imperialist complaints, dysentery of one kind or another.  It [was] also good for hangovers.  It subdues the screaming angst.  It is one of the best sleeping potions I know.”  He further states that the modern version of chlorodyne, which they now call “J. Collis Browne’s Mixture” is not as effective as the older version.  The original concoction was able to “combat ‘colds, coughs, influenza, diarrhea, stomach chills, cholic…” etc. the list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, this advertisement was not run many times over the course of our repository.  And this is strange being that Charles McCabes testimony, although from 1979, was very convincing of how well this product works in treating an assortment of ailments.  Maybe the advertising budget in Alexandria, Egypt at the time was not much, and that&#39;s why the ad was not widely published.  According to McCabe, this medicine was widely published throughout British newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of an ongoing disease plaguing both Egypt and Europe during this time period was tuberculosis. At the beginning of the 19th century treatments consisted of the encouragement of adopting a new lifestyle. Hiking, eating fruits and vegetables, and fresh air were very common examples of this change in “bad living”. As this became outdated, the development of sanatoriums became more acceptable. Due to the lack of technology and understanding of immunology, antibiotics and vaccinations had not yet been invented, therefore, bed rest in a sanatorium was really the only option for the individuals infected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/Tuberculosisstats/Story1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link?:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bar graph displays the frequency of tuberculosis mentioned within the Egyptian Gazette, primarily in the local and general section. Ads such as Dr. Williams’ Pink Pills for Pale People and Puruna feature other disorders and medical conflicts. These include paralysis, rheumatism, and ladies’ complaints. Oddly, however, is the neglect to mention tuberculosis, the infamous “white plague”. Clearly this is a little puzzling seeing how tuberculosis was in many local and general headlines as a deadly concern of the population. This confirms the idea that medical advances were very limited at this time in Egypt and Europe as they were never featured in pill ads that claimed to be the cure-all, miraculously relieving a patient in a matter of days. Many methods and trials probably failed or were not worth mentioning in the Gazette since readers might have been more interested in hearing about success stories rather than failed attempts at one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disease and sickness was a hot topic during this time of uncertainty and doubt, paving the way for big time advertisers to market their ideas and sell an abundance of pill bottles of color- coated candy that claimed to cure everything when in reality, they couldn’t cure a headache. But much of what was not understood during this time can be directly related to what lead to the later understanding of medicine and immunology that we possess today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Prepare for an Outbreak</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An article in my January 30th, 1908 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Protection Against Cholera&amp;rdquo; speaks on the Alexandria Sanitation Department issuing a statement on what steps they will take to stop the spread of cholera.  I find this interesting because when an outbreak of anything happens today, the CDC for example, might send out a similar statement.  What also interests me is the difference between the two organizations that would issue such a statement.  In Alexandria, the sanitation department seemed to have authority over the control and prevention of disease spreading.  This goes on to suggest that early 20th century disease control was thought to be based entirely on sanitation.  In the United States, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/about/organization/mission.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Disease Control&lt;/a&gt;
 (CDC) has authority over the research and prevention of infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article says that its primary goal was to inform the readers of the preparations they can take to guard their own safe being. The following is what the article says the Sanitary Department Suggests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash our hands after every visit to &amp;ldquo;lieux d&#39;aisance&amp;rdquo; and each time before eating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat only well-cooked food; avoid altogether unfiltered water, uncooked milk and butter vegetables and fruits which can be neither cooked nor peeled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid all excess of food, generally, and too cold drinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call in the doctor immediately on the slighted suspicion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch your servants; do not allow them to go out without changing their clothes and washing their hands on returning; do not allow the boabs to have any persons not belonging to the building with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These precautions are interesting because a lot of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/cholera/preventionsteps.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt;
 are commonplace today.  The second portion of the article describes the actions that the sanitary department will do to inspect the town of infectious diseases.  They will inspect establishments and tell them to disinfect with carbonate lime.  This will also result in a number of wells being closing down throughout the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the article, it is mentioned that a &amp;ldquo;Coastguard cruiser&amp;rdquo; is patrolling the waters of the Red Sea, to prevent pilgrims crossing into Egypt.  This article was published towards the end of the Islamic Pilgrimage to Mecca.  Also in this time period are many reports from Mecca of reports of Cholera.  History also has also seen throughout the 19th century that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://origins.osu.edu/article/hajj-and-europe/page/0/1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cholera&lt;/a&gt;
 has spread from Mecca during Hajj.  Therefore the coastguard trying to keep the pilgrims from entering Egypt might be a good way to keep Alexandria safe from the threat of cholera.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cholera</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-himmel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-himmel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cholera&#34;&gt;Cholera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cholera is a bacterial infection that leads to an acute diarrheal disease that dehydrates and can kill the infected within hours.  Today, it is estimated that there are 1.3 to 4 million cases and 21,000 to 143,000 deaths worldwide due to cholera, in mostly socially undeveloped areas (Cholera).  In &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, there are 171 references to the disease ranging from a variety of topics.  Some, if not most of our sample of the Gazette refers to where the disease is spotted in the world and if it threatens Alexandria, Egypt.  Other mentions describe how modern medicine understands the disease and advertisements for medication claiming to remedy cholera amongst other ailments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/mapcholera/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier on in our sample of &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, there is a spike in the mentions of the disease cholera, mostly in the months of August through October 1905.  All of these mentions in this timeframe describe how cholera is ravaging throughout Europe.  Several articles detail its spread geographically throughout northeastern Europe.  For example, in a September, 19th 1905 edition of the newspaper, an article titled “The Cholera Scare” describes a “recent outbreak of cholera in Russia and Germany [that] has caused quite a scare throughout Europe, and it [had] behov[ed] the Sanitary Department to take prompt measures to prevent the dread malady appearing in Egypt…”.  The article later goes on to describe how past epidemics have plagued Egypt, describing the other instances with death tolls in the several tens of thousands.  The article further states that “It is worthy of note that the disease in this country has invariably broken out in the hot months, and disappeared with the advent of cold weather, so that it is reasonable to assume that we shall be spared any visitation [of cholera] this year.”  This prediction proves to be true because there are no mentions of cholera infecting anybody in Egypt within this timeframe, in fact there are articles refuting any rumors that cholera has been spotted in Egypt in this time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From November 1905 to December 1907, there are very few mentions of cholera, most mentions in this timeframe are from either advertisements, or articles describing what is known about cholera and disease in general.  An article from January 26th, 1908 titled “Mosquitoes in Egypt” tells of the need for education for better sanitary practices for the prevention of diseases from coming into Egypt.  Another article called “Egypt’s Curse” from a September 11th issue of the Gazette details the new science of “bacteriology” and what is known about how bacteria work and how they might have survived in a suspended state of animation from the preservation of mummies.  The bacterial resistance of cholera is discussed saying that the bacteria vary in how resistant they are.  Some bacteria seem to perish after only a few hours and some lasted up to eight months with the various experiments that scientists have conducted on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/cholera_15753985669840/Sheet1?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jbh18g/analysis/master/19-analysis-Himmel/%20Chlorodyne.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dr. J. Collis Brown&#39;s Chlorodyne&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one advertisement claims to remedy cholera, diarrhea, colic, and dysentery, and that product is Dr. J. Collis Brown’s Chlorodyne.  Surprisingly enough, the product is only advertised fourteen times over the three years or so of the newspaper that has been encoded.  Further research into Chlorodyne revealed that the medication was an effective treatment for these diseases as well as other ailments not listed in the advertisements.  The reasoning behind its effectiveness were the active ingredients being opiates and marijuana (McCabe, 1979) .  Interestingly enough this advertisement that claims to remedy cholers do not seem to have any correlation to when cholera was mentioned more frequently in the newspaper, even as fears of cholera began to spread within Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/mapcholera/Sheet12?:display_count=y&amp;publish=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link:origin=viz_share_link:showVizHome=no&amp;:embed=true&#34; align=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning in the last month of 1907, cholera outbreaks began to pop up in places close to and in Egypt, namely one case in Suez, Egypt and 34 deaths in the port-town of Sinope, Turkey.  After the new year rolled around, a plethora of cases began to pop up in Mecca and Djeddah, Saudi Arabia.  Almost every day, new reports coming in from those areas tell of plague and death.  These areas are very close to Alexandria and in response, the Sanitary Department of Alexandria has issued a warning of an impending outbreak in the area.  This is particularly interesting because the precautions that the newspaper reports on seem very obvious to someone in today’s time, but may have been completely foreign to readers at this time.  Some of the actions the Sanitary Department advises are to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash hands after using the restroom and before eating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat only well-cooked food and avoid unfiltered water, uncooked milk and butter, and fruits and vegetables that cannot be cooked or peeled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid an excess of food, and cold beverages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek medical attention with the slighted suspicion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not allow servants to go out without changing clothes and washing hands and don’t allow them to bring anyone back with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems as if in later issues of the Gazette there might be more reporting of cholera in the following months to come, possibly some in Alexandria itself.  Since the content repository only goes up to Febuary, 1st 1908, I can only get data on cholera up to this point.  However, the data suggests that there will be a an outbreak soon due to to the Sanitary Department releasing a statement to get prepared for an outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles McCabe  (1979)  The Decline of Things,  Clinical Toxicology,  15:3,  341-342,  DOI:  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3109/15563657908989883&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.3109/15563657908989883&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cholera. (n.d.). Retrieved December 4, 2019, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/cholera&#34;&gt;https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/cholera&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
