<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>picky | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/picky/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/picky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>picky</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>picky</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/picky/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Posting</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-19-crespo-jobposting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-19-crespo-jobposting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This advertisement is found on several issues of the week of May 22nd, 1905. When looking at this ad I found it so specific and very different from what we are used to today. The way this advertisement is written it limits the possible candidates for the job. Today job postings look very different, they are very vague and do not state many details pertaining the actual job. This job posting on the other hand even states that they want male candidates who are unmarried and under 26 years of age. These specifications are put in place because they know that people with these characteristics will be fit to work the most amount of hours and dedicate most of their time to just working. It is crazy how this advertisement even emphasizes the nationality they want to hire and religious affiliation. Today employers look for some of these same qualities but they do not make it public because they could be accused of practicing discrimination in who they hire. In this time and place picking and choosing candidate based on these factors was not seen as something bad, but today this is against the law. Many different advertisements on the Egyptian Gazette are as specific as this one, therefore it seems like this is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
