<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>accident | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/accident/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/accident/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>accident</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>accident</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/accident/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abnormalities in the Mines</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-alainhernandezcorrales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-alainhernandezcorrales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fire has been around since the dawn of time. The use of fire in different aspects has increased but the dangers of being around it still are eye opening. On December 23, 1906 during the process of fire-setting, they had not taken into account the length of the fuse. This error in calculation led to the death of two of the miners and injuries to four more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article functions as a way to show the hardships that can be endured in certain jobs and to be careful with fire. From what I have researched on fire setting, it is a very simple procedure which shouldn&#39;t have too big of a risk factor. While deaths mining are a common occurrence, the cause of death is usually something less controllable. The awareness of the dangers of fire have a larger impact on the community rather than just in the mining field. This occasion makes the citizens of Alexandria question how well they are prepared in the case of a fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article also shows how the community cares about those impacted by these tragedies. It states the condolences of the author to the families affected by this accident and to express their sympathy for their losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-to-other-sources&#34;&gt;Links to Other Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-cannon/&#34;&gt;Analysis Cannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-meyer/&#34;&gt;Analysis Meyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/41496587?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents&#34;&gt;Ancient Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.persee.fr/doc/paleo_0153-9345_2000_num_26_2_4715&#34;&gt;Use of Fire in Prehistoric Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworldcounts.com/counters/environmental_effect_of_mining/health_effects_of_mining&#34;&gt;Environmental Effects of Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Careless” Train Workers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-damiangrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-damiangrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“ROYAL TRAIN DERAILED” was the headline that caught my attention in the October 30, 1907 issue, in which the train carrying the King and Queen of Spain and their infant prince son came off the rails as a result of the “carelessness of a local engine driver.” Shortly after this story, within the same page,
was another story with the headline “Train Collision” with yet another description of a “careless employee.” I became curious if there existed a trend in accidents being caused by “careless” train workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I performed a query to find all instances of the descriptor “careless” found in the same division a “train” was mentioned. My results provided 6 instances of a “careless” individual or group being responsible for a train related accident or issue – 5/6 whom were train workers. Half of the accidents resulted in no injuries, while the other half resulted in severe injuries or death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In searching other blog posts, I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-clark/&#34;&gt;another train incident&lt;/a&gt; in which a train “caught on fire due to an exploding lamp in one of the first-class cars” and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-thompson/&#34;&gt;data analysis&lt;/a&gt; that showed that “train and car wrecks/accidents” accounted for 6% of all deaths recorded in 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As explained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwww.dailynewssegypt.com/2013/05/08/egypts-railways-past-present-and-future/&#34;&gt;the Daily News Egypt&lt;/a&gt;, the construction of railroads in Egypt began in 1834, making it the first railway system in Africa, with a route connecting Alexandria to Cairo and Suez beginning in 1851. Throughout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikes.railhistory.railfan.net/r050.html&#34;&gt;railway&#39;s history&lt;/a&gt;, different companies and organizations would control different portions of track, such as the Egyptian State Railways Administration and the Delta Light Railway Company, resulting in the multitude of railway ads found throughout the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alhough not every incident I found occured in Egypt, the country still has a long history of railway accidents, and, unfortunately, they continue to this day, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ble-t.org/pr/news/headline.asp?id=2877&#34;&gt;the deadliest accident&lt;/a&gt; occurring in 2002 in which over 370 people died when a train caught fire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
