<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>advertisements | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/advertisements/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/advertisements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>advertisements</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>advertisements</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/advertisements/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising... Has anything really changed?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-majonica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-majonica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I happen to really enjoy encoding &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette.&amp;rdquo; It is almost therapeutic. As I venture into another day of my week in January of 1907, I have become accustomed with its format, easily pulling code from other parts of the paper I, and my classmates, have already worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the paper is the advertisement section. No hassle of OCR, lots of pictures, and its sheer simplicity makes me feel like an encoding wiz. And when I was working on my Thursday issue, I imagined myself reading &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was surprisingly simple for me, to read the newspaper as if I always had, as I even began to memorize the advertisements in the same way people living in Alexandria probably did, knowing their location and contents by heart. Interestingly enough, the most common advertisements seemed to be for travel, focused on both steamship movements and hotels. However, I did not really enjoy reading these advertisements, and even worse were the ones relating to finance or insurance. My favorite by far were the advertisements related to health. These advertisements were less common, but they were unique, scattered throughout the paper making me feel as if I was on a scavenger hunt in search of the next one. They are the complete opposite of the steamship and hotel advertisements that overwhelm the first, second, and last page of the paper. I actually wanted to read the health advertisements because who isn’t intrigued by the idea of something that can make one feel or look better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each and every time I see an advertisement for Peruna, a medicine advertised for women, the miracle stories about how it has changed people’s lives, as well its format and illustrations, catch my attention. Peruna&#39;s advertisements jump off the page, unlike the steamer and hotel advertisements whose contents are seemingly stagnant and are not eye-catching at all. The Mena House Hotel advertisement is an example of their lackluster design, with its only description being that it is a &amp;ldquo;First Class Family Hotel.&amp;rdquo; Hard to say if I would stay there. The same goes for the boring advertisement for the Savoy Palace Hotel, which does not get me excited at all for it to open &amp;ldquo;shortly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different are these advertisement tactics from that of today? Not very; the same tactics are used, especially when advertising medicine, as “success” stories continue to be attached to medicines sold in present day. Yet, in terms of travel, it is easier for hotels to excite the consumer today with vivid websites that show luxurious amenities at the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&#34;&gt;although their contents may have shifted&lt;/a&gt;, people are still consumed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/&#34;&gt;products that provide personal benefit&lt;/a&gt;, and travel, because even now commercials, computer and phone advertisements everywhere consist of these things, similarly to that of Egypt in 1907. In Alexandria it seems that just like in 2018, trying to get the daily news comes with an unexpected bombardment of advertisements that we love to hate, but hate to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to look more into advertising and its impact in present day with technology and print, check out these links below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/technology-is-radically-changing-the-advertising-business--and-the-consequences-are-profound-2014-9&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; talks about how advertising is changing to target the consumer, which is interesting because specific advertisements from &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; were of interest to me, and are probably of interest to you, a concept this article explores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://businesstown.com/magazine-newspaper-direct-mail-advertising-still-work&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; focuses on the idea that print advertisement is in fact not dead, but actually extremely effective because our brains work in such a way that makes us better at memorizing print advertisements over digital ones. In terms of &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; this article highlights the effectiveness of the advertisement section to those who read the newspaper in Alexandria and how it could have bolstered consumer activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2017/08/15/10-years-on-the-iphones-impact-on-advertising/#355d49218fb7&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; analyzes the changes in advertising ten years after the release of the iPhone. When looking at the advertisements in &amp;ldquo;The Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in comparison to the advertisements that we interact with in the present day, this article dissects this transition from them to now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H &amp; C Flick, Cigar Importers</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-flick-h-c-flick-cigar-importers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-flick-h-c-flick-cigar-importers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egyptian_cigarette_industry#cite_note-5&#34;&gt;Egyptian cigarette industry&lt;/a&gt; was one of the main exports in Egypt during the time period from the 1880s to the end of the World War I. Just from reading one week of issues of the Egyptian Gazette, I could tell that cigarettes were a major part of an Egyptian’s life. There was at least one advertisement for cigarettes on each page of the newspaper, but one specific advertisement in particular stood out to me the most: “H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, Cigar Importers.” Now this specific ad might not sound important to anyone else, but to me it was very interesting and got me thinking about my ancestry. I am 99.9% sure that I am not related to these Flick’s, but I wonder what it would be like to be a Flick in Egypt in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1905, Egypt imported a total of 8,078 tonnes of tobacco and a total of 8,377 tonnes in 1906 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=qs_YlWuFjooC&amp;amp;lpg=PR3&amp;amp;pg=PA59#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;Relli Shechter, &lt;em&gt;Smoking, Culture and Economy in the Middle East: The Egyptian Tobacco Market 1850-2000&lt;/em&gt;, p. 59 &lt;/a&gt;). The advertisement states that H. &amp;amp; C. Flick was the largest depot of cigars in Egypt, so I can imagine that Flick’s were a very successful in 1906 due to the increase in cigar imports from 1905 to 1906.  Egyptian tobacco was usually very poorly made and didn’t taste very well, so most of the cigarettes in Egypt were not made from Egyptian tobacco (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/41339516?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES AND TOBACCO, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Society of Arts&lt;/em&gt; Vol. 59, No. 3034 (JANUARY 13, 1911), pp. 201-203&lt;/a&gt;). Due to Egyptian tobacco not being up to par with what most tourists and immigrants are used to, being a cigarette importer was probably a very good business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I might not actually be related to H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, I now know that it would probably be a good family business in Egypt in 1906, but it might be harder to be a cigar importer in the United States in 2017 due to all the information about how terrible cigarettes are for our health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related Blog Post by ALEX CALIENDO: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&#34;&gt;The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants that make ice?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-morales-plants-that-make-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-morales-plants-that-make-ice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While going through the newspaper, OCR-ing it, and transcribing it to XML, I usually don&#39;t pay attention to what&#39;s written. Not because I don&#39;t want to - but because I go through it so fast, I don&#39;t have time to. Until I came across this interesting advertisement. At a quick glance of the page, it immediately caught my attention. Yes, the big letters aided in that, but what was in the title is what really got me puzzled. &amp;ldquo;Ice Making Plants&amp;rdquo;? I thought, there’s &lt;em&gt;no way&lt;/em&gt; they found plants that make ice. Upon continuing to read I saw it said &amp;ldquo;Power Driven Machines to produce 1 cwt. Per 24 hours&amp;rdquo; (or about 1lb ≈ every 15 mins). So now I drew another conclusion – they’ve made robotic plants that make ice instead of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this couldn’t be correct so I took it upon myself to call the number on the ad and ask – but &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I got a &amp;ldquo;Your call could not be completed as dialed&amp;rdquo; (must have been a typo). Unfortunately, they didn’t put an email I could contact so I went to my backup-backup plan and scoured the web. After adequate research, I came to my last conclusion: This misleading ad sold ice machines crankable by hand that could be used in &lt;strong&gt;factory&lt;/strong&gt; plants to produce a lot of ice. I also concluded that the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Engineering Co., LTD.&amp;rdquo; didn’t come up with the product, it just resold it as a white label. The RAPLIN originally came from England in the 1890s made by &amp;ldquo;Pulsometer Engineering Co., LTD&amp;rdquo; which continued to manufacture ice machines and other advancements throughout the years. Who knew &lt;del&gt;an innocent&lt;/del&gt; a deceptive advertisement from the early 1900s could get a person from the 21st century so well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=kBMpAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA110&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1898&#34;&gt;Ice and Refrigeration Illustrated Vol. 14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=mj5FAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA233&amp;amp;lpg=RA1-PA233&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1898&#34;&gt;The Practical Engineer. Volume XVII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=cwsAAAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA20&amp;amp;lpg=PA20&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1899&#34;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XXIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gracesguide.co.uk/Pulsometer_Engineering_Co:_1914_Catalogue&#34; title=&#34;Catalogue of Pulsometer&#39;s machines&#34;&gt;Pulsometer Engineering Co: 1914 Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=PYdJAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA172&amp;amp;lpg=PA172&#34; title=&#34;Printed 1908&#34;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XLIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pictures&#34;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RAPLIN_Ice_Machine_Cleaned_Up.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine&#34;&gt; | &lt;img src=&#34;Raplin_Ice_Machine_V2_Cleaned_up.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine V2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-02-the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-02-the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1970, Congress passed the &lt;strong&gt;Public Health Cigarette Smoking Act&lt;/strong&gt;, which prohibited the advertisement of cigarettes, and this law took effect on January 2, 1971. As a result, I have never seen a pro-cigarette advertisement a day in my life. And clearly, that reality differs from that of people who lived in Alexandria in 1905. Here, the Egyptian Gazette, on page three of this issue, is pushing the reader to check out an advertisement for the Cleopatra Cigarette Company, just in case they skimmed over it while reading page one  just moments before. In essence, not only does the “Gazette” advertise for this cigarette company on the very first page of their newspaper, but they also refer the reader back to that advertisement in a later section of the paper, and in doing so, they are essentially advertising for Cleopatra Cigarettes two times in one issue. This just goes to show how lax people’s views on cigarettes were back in 1905. This newspaper “begs” the reader to check out an advertisement for cigarettes, hoping that they’ll end up purchasing the &lt;em&gt;cancer sticks&lt;/em&gt; for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is beautifully juxtaposed with modern society&#39;s view on cigarettes. For one, in 2016, you would never find an advertisement for cigarettes in a local newspaper. Moreover, there are a plethora of campaigns in existence today which put out ads and commercials to influence people to not smoke, or to stop smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cigs-1x-1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of the many types of ads in existence today, aiming to make society aware of the side effects of smoking cigarettes. Being surrounded and exposed by so many negative advertisements like this, it makes me question what my view on cigarettes would be if I lived in 1905 Alexandria, and was exposed to positive ads for cigarettes. Not to mention, how I would feel if my local newspaper advertised cigarettes. And moreover, if my local newspaper advertised their own cigarette advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
