<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>foreigners | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/foreigners/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/foreigners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>foreigners</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>foreigners</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/foreigners/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to Law Against Foreigners in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This ad in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper provides readers with a quick synopsis of a book called The Law Affecting Foreigners in Egypt by James Henry Scott, a lecturer at the Khedivial School of Law, Cairo. The book is an introduction to Egyptian Law as it affected foreigners and provides information on history like; the law of the Ottoman Empire and the Ottoman Capitulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book that the ad speaks of discloses Egyptian law as it once affected the foreigners of Egypt. For instance, from the list of topics the ad provided us with, it can be noted that this book provides us with information on events such as the mixed codes, mixed courts, the capitulations of European states, and the commercial privileges given to the people of Egypt. During the Anglo-Egyptian War, the country of Egypt was not only occupied by British forces but it was colonized by the British from 1882 when the war started, until 1956 when the war ended and the last British forces withdrew in accordance with the Anglo-Egyptian agreement of 1954 after the Suez Crisis. During this past age of time, several legal problems that were present in Egyptian law came about and were also seized with the limited powers of independent legislation. Insights like this about international historic events that has happened internationally has always intrigued me. I believe that international law allows students like myself to form bits of knowledge into the worldwide legal system and its effect on both national and international policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=gKIuAAAAIAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA288&amp;amp;lpg=PA288&amp;amp;dq=Mr.+Scott,+of+the+Khedivial+Law+School+Cairo&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=nHjRElq7vn&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U2u2ymFGRhBOm1CgfETFkwPHePcSQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjOs6Gz_K7mAhWPxVkKHcgTCikQ6AEwAXoECAYQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=Mr.%20Scott%2C%20of%20the%20Khedivial%20Law%20School%20Cairo&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this review&lt;/a&gt; that gives an opinionated review and summary of the book itself. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/367847?seq=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; describes the social tensions and the how tht teaching of European law was in Egypt before 1900. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encyclopedia.com/history/encyclopedias-almanacs-transcripts-and-maps/capitulations-middle-east&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; describes how the capitulations were in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
