<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>disease | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/disease/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/disease/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>disease</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>disease</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/disease/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Prepare for an Outbreak</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An article in my January 30th, 1908 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Protection Against Cholera&amp;rdquo; speaks on the Alexandria Sanitation Department issuing a statement on what steps they will take to stop the spread of cholera.  I find this interesting because when an outbreak of anything happens today, the CDC for example, might send out a similar statement.  What also interests me is the difference between the two organizations that would issue such a statement.  In Alexandria, the sanitation department seemed to have authority over the control and prevention of disease spreading.  This goes on to suggest that early 20th century disease control was thought to be based entirely on sanitation.  In the United States, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/about/organization/mission.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Disease Control&lt;/a&gt; (CDC) has authority over the research and prevention of infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article says that its primary goal was to inform the readers of the preparations they can take to guard their own safe being. The following is what the article says the Sanitary Department Suggests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash our hands after every visit to &amp;ldquo;lieux d&amp;rsquo;aisance&amp;rdquo; and each time before eating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat only well-cooked food; avoid altogether unfiltered water, uncooked milk and butter vegetables and fruits which can be neither cooked nor peeled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid all excess of food, generally, and too cold drinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call in the doctor immediately on the slighted suspicion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch your servants; do not allow them to go out without changing their clothes and washing their hands on returning; do not allow the boabs to have any persons not belonging to the building with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These precautions are interesting because a lot of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/cholera/preventionsteps.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; are commonplace today.  The second portion of the article describes the actions that the sanitary department will do to inspect the town of infectious diseases.  They will inspect establishments and tell them to disinfect with carbonate lime.  This will also result in a number of wells being closing down throughout the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the article, it is mentioned that a &amp;ldquo;Coastguard cruiser&amp;rdquo; is patrolling the waters of the Red Sea, to prevent pilgrims crossing into Egypt.  This article was published towards the end of the Islamic Pilgrimage to Mecca.  Also in this time period are many reports from Mecca of reports of Cholera.  History also has also seen throughout the 19th century that &lt;a href=&#34;https://origins.osu.edu/article/hajj-and-europe/page/0/1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cholera&lt;/a&gt; has spread from Mecca during Hajj.  Therefore the coastguard trying to keep the pilgrims from entering Egypt might be a good way to keep Alexandria safe from the threat of cholera.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubonic Plague In Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;According to the Egyptian Gazette, August 28, 1905, the Bubonic plague has reported at least thirteen cases of individuals that had contracted this disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest in this snippet of information, housed within the Gazette (see figure below), stems from the fact that the Bubonic Plague (a.k.a. The Black Death), was not confined to Medieval Europe (as many readers would suspect). In fact, the Bubonic plague has existed for thousands of years, the first known case being recorded in China dating back to 224 B.C.E..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most significant outbreak, and most noticeable, occurred in Europe in the mid-fourteenth century over a five year period (1347 to 1352). During this time period, sources indicate that at least 25 million people died, about one-third of the continent’s population (these numbers are disputed). The often disputed claims as to the cause of such a disease was further investigated in 2010 and 2011, when researchers analyzed DNA from some of its European victims. The consensus to date is that the pathogen responsible was the Yersinia pestis bacterium, which most likely caused several different forms of the plague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;BlackPlague.gif&#34; alt=&#34;image name&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing an outbreak within the borders of Egypt, with so few deaths was incredible, which warrants further understanding of this disease, how it was spread and who it affected. The Gazette’s article (above) mentions that approximately 13 cases were under treatment during the middle of August and beginning of September, 1905. With the plague’s notorious reputation, the Gazette’s allocated space to this pandemic is sapient, especially due to the many cattle deaths in the area within that same time period (the figure to the right indicates the area affected by the Bubonic Plague).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With modern populations shifted to cities in modern day, an unidentifiable plague in one of these areas would prove to be even more catastrophic than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-further-study&#34;&gt;For further study:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yersinia Pestis.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951374/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951374/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Draft genome of Yersinia pestis from victims of the Black Death.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v478/n7370/full/nature10549.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v478/n7370/full/nature10549.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plague in 18th Century Egypt.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://contagions.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/plague-in-18th-century-egypt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://contagions.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/plague-in-18th-century-egypt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
