<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>race | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/race/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/race/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>race</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>race</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/race/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Regatta Is a Boat Race.</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-08-ukah-a-regatta-is-a-boat-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-08-ukah-a-regatta-is-a-boat-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Gazette will occasionally feature a &amp;ldquo;Sport and Play.&amp;rdquo; section, usually containing scores from cricket games. For the majority of this week, though, the section featured a regatta hosted by the Khedival Yacht Club. Unlike cricket, a regatta is a series of boat races, so I initially found its placement in the newspaper odd, until reading this sub article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;KHEDIVAL2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Yachting in Alexandria&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yachting has apparently found an audience in Alexandria&#39;s sporting community, so much so that private owners with large money influences have begun to participate in races. (That is how I understand it at least.) I figured some additional research into these races was warranted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1907 &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;The Motor Boat: Devoted to All Types of Power Craft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 4, Issue 12, by Francis P. Prial pg. 43: Prial mentions the waters near Alexandria and in Egypt in general as &amp;ldquo;splendid facilities for motorboating&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and how these waters were not receiving enough attention from craft owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the central theme in this source is motorboats, not yachts, I feel the source warrants mentioning because ideal waters might be a reason for the success that yachting in Alexandria had seen, and because the author also speaks highly of the Khedival Yacht Club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1908 &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Encyclopaedia of Ships and Shipping&lt;/em&gt;, by Herbert B. Mason, pg. 328: A general definition of the Khedival Yacht Club: &amp;ldquo;Established 1902. Patron, H. H. the Khedive of Egypt ; Commodore, H.H. Prince Aziz Pacha Hassan&amp;hellip;Entrance fee, £3 ; annual subscription, £2.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the mention of an entrance fee, I assume that anyone could have participated in the regattas, and that the aforementioned private owners had the money to invest in elite crafts that could win races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1907 &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Fore&#39;n&#39;aft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 11, pg. 62: The Khedival Yacht Club is hailed as &amp;ldquo;the only important organization of its kind in Egypt&amp;hellip; and now has two hundred and thirty members and a fleet of fifty yachts. Weekly regattas are held in fort and numerous enjoyable social functions at the handsome club house.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, here are the results of the week in question&#39;s regatta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;KHEDIVAL3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Regatta Results&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ananke, a privately owned craft favored by the newspaper to win the race in its class, could not withstand the wind and waters that day, and had to forfeit the race.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
