<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>theater | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/theater/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/theater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>theater</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>theater</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/theater/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madame Butterfly: A Metamorphosis</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-01-ali-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-01-ali-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lights dim and slowly, the onlooking crowd goes quiet with growing anticipation. The excitable people among the bunch murmur about their excitement to see Signora Pandolfini for their first time as they prepare to hear her sing a soft melody. The people gushing with anticipation hurriedly tell them to shush as they do not want to miss the moment her voice first chirps. The curtains open and just as fast, the tale begins. It’s poetry in motion… sort of. If the crowd’s reaction was anything to go off, Pandolfini really missed the mark on the first act of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.musicwithease.com/puccini-butterfly-story.html&#34;&gt;Madame Butterfly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,a relatively well-known play back in the early 1900s and even now. Back in the early 1900s, the performance had been making the rounds across America and Europe, and it soon found a troop to replicate its excellence in Egypt&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cairoopera.org/history.php?lan=En&#34;&gt;Khedivial Opera House&lt;/a&gt; … for the most part at least. Pandolfini managed to win the crowd over in acts two and three, but the long-awaited play certainly had more than one mishap. While the symphonies played were engaging, many critics said that it left no real impression. This does not equate to bad though, as these same critics believed that the play was truly worthy of playing in the Khedival Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;source-of-interest&#34;&gt;Source of Interest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached here is the act by act synopsis of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.columbia.edu/itc/music/NYCO/butterfly/synopsis.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madame
Butterfly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;MadameB2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;visualization&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
