<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/tyriellejarmon/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/tyriellejarmon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Digital Egyptian Gazette</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/tyriellejarmon/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage &amp; Divorce</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jarmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-jarmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my blog post, I chose to talk about the topic of Marriage &amp;amp; Divorce in the year of 1907, around the month August. I was particularly intrigued by the emphasis on marriage being placed in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper which is opposed to what we see in these modern times. One specific section in my reading that gathered my interest was titled &amp;ldquo;Alexandria Merchant Divorce&amp;rdquo; published on August 6, 1907.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief overview about the story resulted in the end of a marriage between Mr. William Getty, a cotton merchant of Alexandria and his wife. Over the past years, she strayed away and disappeared from him, leaving him to wonder about her whereabouts and how she was doing. While on her death bed, she had an incurable diseases that she couldn&amp;rsquo;t be healed from. She wrote a letter to her husband confessing that she was unfaithful to him throughout the duration of their marriage. In defense of her statement, she felt that the money she had leftover should be given to him since she recently became a Christian Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This excerpt from the passage was quite interesting for me to read because I was fascinated with the explicit details provided and how it was shared with all of the world to see. Although they didn&amp;rsquo;t share a response from her husband after he received the message from her, I would have wondered what his thoughts, response or even last words to her would have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reference to this article, I found another interesting topic from the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette&amp;rdquo; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;another blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a crazy man killing his wife with an unusual weapon. Although there is no reason for his crazy acts, he committed the crime from speculations that his wife was cheating on him. The magnitude of this article was extremely huge enough to reach the newspaper because people thought the city should be aware of this person and who he is. This article correlated to mine because there was suspicion of cheating in both marriages where the results ended up tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
