<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>death | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/death/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>death</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>death</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/death/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Domestic Tragedy</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-donofrio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-donofrio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article tells the story of a divorced couple that ultimately ended in fatality. In attempts to fix his relationship, the spouse tried to convince his former wife to get back together. However, when she refused, he got angry and stabbed her multiple times. After this violent and impulsive reaction had subsided, the man realized what he had done, and thinking he had killed his spouse, he drew a revolver and shot himself dead. However, the woman simply fell unconscious and did not die.
This story has a theme similar to Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; pertaining to the story of a spouse thinking his partner is dead and consequentially killing himself because of that thought. It also shows that people would do anything for love, and that people act irrationally when they are put in desperate situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, domestic violence was not uncommon, as shown in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Matthew Cooper&amp;rsquo;s blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Here Cooper talks about an article on a man who killed his wife with an blow to the head by a bar of iron. Although the context is different between the two instances, it is clear that abuse within marriages was not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cairo Visitor Gravely Injured</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-fitzpatrick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-fitzpatrick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the blog post I chose an article titled “Cairo Visitor Gravely Injured” from page 3 of the Thursday December 13 1906 issue. The article talks about an accident that occurred on the P. and O. express in France the Friday before where two passengers were injured, and I believe one of them died? It&amp;rsquo;s not very clear and is not actually stated, but is implied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two passengers injured were Mr. and Mrs. Robert Hanna, who were visiting from Dublin. Mrs. Hanna was not seriously injured but it seems that Mr. Hanna was killed. The suspected death was caused by a piece of metal that crashed through the window. Apparently, they’re not sure how it really happened, either from a bridge or a part of the train which doesn’t really make sense because I would think if it came from the bridge it would cause more external damage versus internal like the part of the train would cause making it easier to pinpoint the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me to question just how in-depth incidents were investigated at this time. Did they just quickly glance at the scene and decide on the circumstances surrounding it, or did they thoroughly investigate and try to find the actual cause. Interestingly enough there is a similar article that was found in &lt;em&gt;The London Times&lt;/em&gt; that follows up on the accident and says that Mr. Hanna was severely injured in the accident and died the next morning at the hospital. It gives a little bit more information about him saying he was 42 years old and was an engineer on an Indian Railway. It also says how his wife Mrs. Hannas condition has improved. While there isn&amp;rsquo;t a happy ending, at least we are able to find a little bit more information on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death amongst the Egyptians</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-chapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-chapple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 16, 1906 there have been multiple reports if incidents of the Bubonique Plague and Typhoid Fever. Citizens are dying at an alarming rate and there has reportedly been an outbreak on a steamship that was set to sail to Ras-el-Tin. A first class domestic man by the name of R. Cole sailing on H.M.S Venus was suffering from symptoms of &amp;ldquo;interior fever&amp;rdquo; and was rushed to the hospital immediately after disembarking the ship. Mr. Cole tragically succumbed to his illness at 2.45am on October 16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second case of typhoid fever occurred on board the Venus since her arrival of Egyptian waters. The first person to experience symptoms was Captain Eyre, who has since been rushed to a hospital in Port Said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week prior to October 15, there have been a report of 6 cases of the Bubonique Plague throughout the country of Egypt, 3 cases at Alexandria, 2 at Suez, and one in the Minieh district. This is alarming as 492 cases have been reported since the start of the year, and this is a large increase from the previous year of 1905 where 264 incidents had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggos</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-degroat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-degroat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 18th, 1907, Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was released to the public. In this issue of the newspaper, on the fourth page, under the section labeled &amp;ldquo;Letter to the Editor,&amp;rdquo; a person wrote to the editor about his / her referring to Canis Major&amp;rsquo;s recent letter. The letter written by Canis Major is posted in the newspaper above the Letter to the Editor – Police Dog Service. Canis Major’s letter discussed the treatment of dogs when getting closer to death. Major stated that “[he] thinks that the matter should be looked into, and something should be done, to make the life of [the] dogs, during the time they wait for death, less painful for them.” In response to Canis Major’s letter, a “Lover of Animals” commented how a friend of theirs dog suffered from a disease “contracted in the black hole of Boulac.” The animal suffered through death, and the person who responded to Canis Major’s letter wanted to make a statement agreeing with him, that dogs should be treated better in their last days and minutes. Having this section, “Letters to the Editor,” allows the public to develop their thoughts and issues about society to the newspaper. This gives them a chance to speak up. Even though, the newspaper most likely cannot put in submissions that will cause a riot, they still put in some that have a small amount of concern from the people which keeps everything well balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing another search about dogs, not animals, there were only a few articles that came up about the cruelty in their treatment. While there are other blog posts about different animals and dogs, I saw no record of any with an emphasis on the treatment of dogs during their dying stages. Regarding the SPCA, I ran multiple xpath query’s and all were returned with no results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Hungry</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-richardson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-richardson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all going to die.  I am so sorry I had to be the one to break the news, but someone had to. Have you ever thought about your funeral? How you want to die? Or if you want to be buried alone? What if I told you no one in Ancient Egypt was buried alone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I am telling you that and it is true. In A.R. William&amp;rsquo;s “Packing Food for the Hereafter in Ancient Egypt” article she says “Each had spent years preparing a lavish tomb stocked with everything they might need or want in the afterlife, including food, preserved for eternity.” Your death is just as important as our life so one should be prepared for it and they did. W. St Chad Boscawen &lt;a href=&#34;http://theplate.nationalgeographic.com/2015/04/05/packing-food-for-the-hereafter-in-ancient-egypt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;found that ancient Egyptians were buried with food&lt;/a&gt;. Yay, you won’t spend eternity hungry! This food was found in vases or food dishes and there is a fine collection of food from vegetable matter to bread, fish or even fresh water crustacean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know what you are thinking, what if you get thirsty? Have no fear if you are lucky enough in “the temeros” where your body is placed there is a round hole in the middle that contains a drain where offering of beer or wine could be made. Your party doesn’t have to stop because you are dead. In fact in an article written by Patrick J. Kiger called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel.nationalgeographic.com/the-story-of-god-with-morgan-freeman/articles/ancient-egyptian-tombs-and-death-rituals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ancient Egyptian Tombs and Death Rituals&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; it says “Egyptian funerals also were elaborate. The body was placed in a coffin and transported to the tomb in a cart pulled by oxen. It was accompanied by a procession that included relatives, priests and priestesses, along with dancers, and musicians.” &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history.com/topics/tombs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;History.com&lt;/a&gt; says “The original purpose of a tomb was to protect the dead and provide the deceased with a dwelling equipped with necessities for the afterlife.” I really think it was Egypt’s way to send respect and keep the party of life going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it easier now to accept the inevitable? At least you won’t be hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The death of Muhammad &#39;Abduh</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-abduh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-abduh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Muhammad &amp;lsquo;Abduh died on July 11, 1905. Because he was the leading Muslim thinker of Egypt and a prominent player in political and public life, it is not surprising that &amp;lsquo;Abduh&amp;rsquo;s illness, funeral, and memory were the subject of daily reports in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;article&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pro-British paper lauded the memory of the pro-British cleric.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
