<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>death | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/death/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>death</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>death</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/death/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Prepare for an Outbreak</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-25-jake_himmel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An article in my January 30th, 1908 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Protection Against Cholera&amp;rdquo; speaks on the Alexandria Sanitation Department issuing a statement on what steps they will take to stop the spread of cholera.  I find this interesting because when an outbreak of anything happens today, the CDC for example, might send out a similar statement.  What also interests me is the difference between the two organizations that would issue such a statement.  In Alexandria, the sanitation department seemed to have authority over the control and prevention of disease spreading.  This goes on to suggest that early 20th century disease control was thought to be based entirely on sanitation.  In the United States, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/about/organization/mission.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Disease Control&lt;/a&gt;
 (CDC) has authority over the research and prevention of infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article says that its primary goal was to inform the readers of the preparations they can take to guard their own safe being. The following is what the article says the Sanitary Department Suggests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash our hands after every visit to &amp;ldquo;lieux d&amp;rsquo;aisance&amp;rdquo; and each time before eating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat only well-cooked food; avoid altogether unfiltered water, uncooked milk and butter vegetables and fruits which can be neither cooked nor peeled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid all excess of food, generally, and too cold drinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call in the doctor immediately on the slighted suspicion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch your servants; do not allow them to go out without changing their clothes and washing their hands on returning; do not allow the boabs to have any persons not belonging to the building with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These precautions are interesting because a lot of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/cholera/preventionsteps.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt;
 are commonplace today.  The second portion of the article describes the actions that the sanitary department will do to inspect the town of infectious diseases.  They will inspect establishments and tell them to disinfect with carbonate lime.  This will also result in a number of wells being closing down throughout the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the article, it is mentioned that a &amp;ldquo;Coastguard cruiser&amp;rdquo; is patrolling the waters of the Red Sea, to prevent pilgrims crossing into Egypt.  This article was published towards the end of the Islamic Pilgrimage to Mecca.  Also in this time period are many reports from Mecca of reports of Cholera.  History also has also seen throughout the 19th century that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://origins.osu.edu/article/hajj-and-europe/page/0/1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cholera&lt;/a&gt;
 has spread from Mecca during Hajj.  Therefore the coastguard trying to keep the pilgrims from entering Egypt might be a good way to keep Alexandria safe from the threat of cholera.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleepy driver results in fatal accident</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-peytonsmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-16-peytonsmith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One incident that I found very curious to research upon was one that I found in my Wednesday issue, in the Telegrams section that writes about an accident that happened in a town named Shrewsbury, located in the Mid-west part of England. As a train was traveling from Crewe to Bristol, it got into this accident in this town located right in the middle of the two cities and resulted in the death of 19 and injured 40.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;label&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the incident occurred, the cause of what happened is still uncertain. In an article, found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.revolvy.com/page/Shrewsbury-rail-accident&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
, the officials at the scene examined the driver, and found out that he was not intoxicated nor under any influence of drugs, making the situation even more difficult to pinpoint. In another article, found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shropshirestar.com/news/nostalgia/2017/10/14/sleeping-driver-mystery-of-shropshires-worst-crash/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
, they have another spectulation on why the incident came about, many officials believing that he was sleepy. The article reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot was that approaching Shrewsbury, sleep overcame him. He passed Harlescott crossing and Crewe Bank without knowing it, and did not see the signals at danger, and on the downward gradient coming in to Shrewsbury the train picked up speed rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident itself, even after 100 years, is something to always keep in mind. From 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/england/shropshire/7044176.stm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;another article&lt;/a&gt;
, a member of the Shrewsbury Railway Heritage Trust, Dave Giddens, believes that the incident should never be forgotten. In his own words he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s very good, even after 100 years to still remember the people who were involved in it and the people that lost loved ones,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, there are other incidents in the Egyptian Gazette that also involves train crashes, in one 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-clark/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;
 by Gavin Clark, another incident involving a train accident was published in the newspaper in 1906. But instead of it being an actual crash, the train caught on fire. In another 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-story-theuntimelydeathofprincemohamidibrahim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;
, made Will Hanley himself, entails an incident where a Prince was killed in an unusual car accident as he was hit by a train. Just from this, it can be concluded that train safety has definitely advanced in the 100 years. Nowadays, you rarely hear of a train crash, resulting in the death of people, where back then it seemed as if this was a common occurence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, one might ask &amp;ldquo;Why would a train accident be newsworthy in an Egyptian newspaper?&amp;quot;. The answer is simple, Britain took control over all parts of Egypt back during the time this was written. Acting as a protectorate under British rule, this lasted from 1886 to 1914. Because of this, it was very common to find British news all throughout the contents of the &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Gazette,&amp;rdquo; where the editors themselves were often at times British. At the same, for this incident specifically, it was located in the Telegrams section, where they report news from all around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RailwayAccident.png&#34; alt=&#34;Railway Accident&#34; title=&#34;Photo of the Railway accident in Shrewsbury as officials are investigating the scene.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abnormalities in the Mines</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-alainhernandezcorrales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-alainhernandezcorrales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fire has been around since the dawn of time. The use of fire in different aspects has increased but the dangers of being around it still are eye opening. On December 23, 1906 during the process of fire-setting, they had not taken into account the length of the fuse. This error in calculation led to the death of two of the miners and injuries to four more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article functions as a way to show the hardships that can be endured in certain jobs and to be careful with fire. From what I have researched on fire setting, it is a very simple procedure which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have too big of a risk factor. While deaths mining are a common occurrence, the cause of death is usually something less controllable. The awareness of the dangers of fire have a larger impact on the community rather than just in the mining field. This occasion makes the citizens of Alexandria question how well they are prepared in the case of a fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article also shows how the community cares about those impacted by these tragedies. It states the condolences of the author to the families affected by this accident and to express their sympathy for their losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-to-other-sources&#34;&gt;Links to Other Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-cannon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Analysis Cannon&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-meyer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Analysis Meyer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/41496587?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ancient Mining&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.persee.fr/doc/paleo_0153-9345_2000_num_26_2_4715&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Use of Fire in Prehistoric Mining&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworldcounts.com/counters/environmental_effect_of_mining/health_effects_of_mining&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Environmental Effects of Mining&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drowning in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-ashleycrisafulli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-10-17-ashleycrisafulli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A prominent topic in many issues of the “Egyptian Gazette” is that of death. There are many different occurrences of death and they occur in all different ways. The one that stuck out to me the most was drowning. On page 3 of the Monday February 25, 1907 issue the story “Well Known Minister Drowned” caught my attention. This article talks about the death that occurred during sea travel from Liverpool to Alexandria. A reverend gentleman had fallen overboard during a storm. However, this was not the only death stated in the article. A few days prior the ship&amp;rsquo;s carpenter had drowned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is a common topic in this paper, I wonder why they don’t go into detail about what happened to the minister that drowned. They merely state the fact that he went overboard during a storm. It is also interesting that there were two occurrences of drowning on the same boat in the same time. This makes me wonder how many others were effected in this same way. I went to explore more about death by drowning or shipwrecks and struggled to find data specific to Egypt. However, I did come across a source that showed many shipwrecks that occurred between 1833 and today, showing that shipwrecks were more common in this 1900s period. This could also be because ships were used to transport exports such as cotton. Egypt shipped cotton and other materials to Britain using ships. Although these would not be the same ships as the one the minister drowned on it is important to note that they were commonly used for many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this death occurred during travel which is something that has happened to many people in 1900s. In the blog post 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“Cairo Visitor gravely Injured”&lt;/a&gt;
, the article examined also looks at death that occurred while someone was traveling. They also questioned how in-depth incidents were investigated at the time. Death was also talked about in other blog posts. In many cases there are posts about the plague, which appears to be a more common way to die at this time. From all of these article we see how death was reported and how it ranged in how in depth it was investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Domestic Tragedy</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-donofrio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article tells the story of a divorced couple that ultimately ended in fatality. In attempts to fix his relationship, the spouse tried to convince his former wife to get back together. However, when she refused, he got angry and stabbed her multiple times. After this violent and impulsive reaction had subsided, the man realized what he had done, and thinking he had killed his spouse, he drew a revolver and shot himself dead. However, the woman simply fell unconscious and did not die.
This story has a theme similar to Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; pertaining to the story of a spouse thinking his partner is dead and consequentially killing himself because of that thought. It also shows that people would do anything for love, and that people act irrationally when they are put in desperate situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, domestic violence was not uncommon, as shown in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matthew Cooper&amp;rsquo;s blog post&lt;/a&gt;
. Here Cooper talks about an article on a man who killed his wife with an blow to the head by a bar of iron. Although the context is different between the two instances, it is clear that abuse within marriages was not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cairo Visitor Gravely Injured</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-fitzpatrick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the blog post I chose an article titled “Cairo Visitor Gravely Injured” from page 3 of the Thursday December 13 1906 issue. The article talks about an accident that occurred on the P. and O. express in France the Friday before where two passengers were injured, and I believe one of them died? It&amp;rsquo;s not very clear and is not actually stated, but is implied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two passengers injured were Mr. and Mrs. Robert Hanna, who were visiting from Dublin. Mrs. Hanna was not seriously injured but it seems that Mr. Hanna was killed. The suspected death was caused by a piece of metal that crashed through the window. Apparently, they’re not sure how it really happened, either from a bridge or a part of the train which doesn’t really make sense because I would think if it came from the bridge it would cause more external damage versus internal like the part of the train would cause making it easier to pinpoint the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads me to question just how in-depth incidents were investigated at this time. Did they just quickly glance at the scene and decide on the circumstances surrounding it, or did they thoroughly investigate and try to find the actual cause. Interestingly enough there is a similar article that was found in &lt;em&gt;The London Times&lt;/em&gt; that follows up on the accident and says that Mr. Hanna was severely injured in the accident and died the next morning at the hospital. It gives a little bit more information about him saying he was 42 years old and was an engineer on an Indian Railway. It also says how his wife Mrs. Hannas condition has improved. While there isn&amp;rsquo;t a happy ending, at least we are able to find a little bit more information on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death amongst the Egyptians</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-chapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-chapple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 16, 1906 there have been multiple reports if incidents of the Bubonique Plague and Typhoid Fever. Citizens are dying at an alarming rate and there has reportedly been an outbreak on a steamship that was set to sail to Ras-el-Tin. A first class domestic man by the name of R. Cole sailing on H.M.S Venus was suffering from symptoms of &amp;ldquo;interior fever&amp;rdquo; and was rushed to the hospital immediately after disembarking the ship. Mr. Cole tragically succumbed to his illness at 2.45am on October 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second case of typhoid fever occurred on board the Venus since her arrival of Egyptian waters. The first person to experience symptoms was Captain Eyre, who has since been rushed to a hospital in Port Said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week prior to October 15, there have been a report of 6 cases of the Bubonique Plague throughout the country of Egypt, 3 cases at Alexandria, 2 at Suez, and one in the Minieh district. This is alarming as 492 cases have been reported since the start of the year, and this is a large increase from the previous year of 1905 where 264 incidents had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggos</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-degroat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 18th, 1907, Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was released to the public. In this issue of the newspaper, on the fourth page, under the section labeled &amp;ldquo;Letter to the Editor,&amp;rdquo; a person wrote to the editor about his / her referring to Canis Major&amp;rsquo;s recent letter. The letter written by Canis Major is posted in the newspaper above the Letter to the Editor – Police Dog Service. Canis Major’s letter discussed the treatment of dogs when getting closer to death. Major stated that “[he] thinks that the matter should be looked into, and something should be done, to make the life of [the] dogs, during the time they wait for death, less painful for them.” In response to Canis Major’s letter, a “Lover of Animals” commented how a friend of theirs dog suffered from a disease “contracted in the black hole of Boulac.” The animal suffered through death, and the person who responded to Canis Major’s letter wanted to make a statement agreeing with him, that dogs should be treated better in their last days and minutes. Having this section, “Letters to the Editor,” allows the public to develop their thoughts and issues about society to the newspaper. This gives them a chance to speak up. Even though, the newspaper most likely cannot put in submissions that will cause a riot, they still put in some that have a small amount of concern from the people which keeps everything well balanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing another search about dogs, not animals, there were only a few articles that came up about the cruelty in their treatment. While there are other blog posts about different animals and dogs, I saw no record of any with an emphasis on the treatment of dogs during their dying stages. Regarding the SPCA, I ran multiple xpath query’s and all were returned with no results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Hungry</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all going to die.  I am so sorry I had to be the one to break the news, but someone had to. Have you ever thought about your funeral? How you want to die? Or if you want to be buried alone? What if I told you no one in Ancient Egypt was buried alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I am telling you that and it is true. In A.R. William&amp;rsquo;s “Packing Food for the Hereafter in Ancient Egypt” article she says “Each had spent years preparing a lavish tomb stocked with everything they might need or want in the afterlife, including food, preserved for eternity.” Your death is just as important as our life so one should be prepared for it and they did. W. St Chad Boscawen 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://theplate.nationalgeographic.com/2015/04/05/packing-food-for-the-hereafter-in-ancient-egypt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;found that ancient Egyptians were buried with food&lt;/a&gt;
. Yay, you won’t spend eternity hungry! This food was found in vases or food dishes and there is a fine collection of food from vegetable matter to bread, fish or even fresh water crustacean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what you are thinking, what if you get thirsty? Have no fear if you are lucky enough in “the temeros” where your body is placed there is a round hole in the middle that contains a drain where offering of beer or wine could be made. Your party doesn’t have to stop because you are dead. In fact in an article written by Patrick J. Kiger called &amp;ldquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel.nationalgeographic.com/the-story-of-god-with-morgan-freeman/articles/ancient-egyptian-tombs-and-death-rituals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ancient Egyptian Tombs and Death Rituals&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;rdquo; it says “Egyptian funerals also were elaborate. The body was placed in a coffin and transported to the tomb in a cart pulled by oxen. It was accompanied by a procession that included relatives, priests and priestesses, along with dancers, and musicians.” 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history.com/topics/tombs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;History.com&lt;/a&gt;
 says “The original purpose of a tomb was to protect the dead and provide the deceased with a dwelling equipped with necessities for the afterlife.” I really think it was Egypt’s way to send respect and keep the party of life going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it easier now to accept the inevitable? At least you won’t be hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death of Haicalis Pasha</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-baenen-deathofthepasha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-baenen-deathofthepasha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When reading my week of the Egyptian Gazette, I came across the sad news of the Death of Haicalis Pasha. At first I didn’t know why it was so important but then continuing in the article published I could tell that Egypt lost an important life in the European Press of Egypt. He was known as the “Doyen of the Local Press” which means “the most prominent and respected person in a particular field”.  This got me interested in this man’s life and accomplishments so I started to do some research on him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haicalis earned a Doctorate of Law, was on many Governmental Administrations, was the one who persuaded Mr. Cook, the owner of Thos. Cook &amp;amp; Son tourist agency, an agency which if you have worked with the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; I’m sure you have heard of, to come to Egypt to start his business. In my own opinion, his most important accomplishment was that he was a founder and the Editor of a newspaper called &lt;em&gt;Phare d’Alexadrie&lt;/em&gt;. This paper was known for its “journalistic decency” and not blackmailing individuals, providing readers with just news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was honored in many countries for his work, receiving things like the Legion of Honor, the Order of the Crown of Italy, and many other decorations/honors. He was an important figure in the journalist community and impacted how European Press was constructed in delivering news from Egypt and inversely impacted the Egyptian Gazette.  Even though this doesn’t impact everyday life ultimately in Egypt it still is a very saddening passing of someone who made positive changes to many things in the world. This article gives me more connection to the Egyptian Gazette and makes you realize how much is going on around the world that isn’t reported on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-migdalski-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-migdalski-plague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this short newspaper article on the third page of the first day of my issue, the topic was about a plague outbreak that had numerous cases throughout Egypt. Victims of the plague had been reported dead in a number of villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article states some, but not all, of the cases were said to be pneumonic, which means it affected the lungs. This creates a curiosity for me. If only the majority of the deaths were caused by pneumonia, I wonder if all of the people who died, were infected by the same disease.  I am also curious if the disease affected different people in different ways. The article explicitly states that they deemed this plague to be contracted through direct contact. I am curious as to the origins of this plague and the characteristics and symptoms of it as well. I searched for outside information regarding this plague and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=r_YDAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA3&amp;amp;lpg=PA3&amp;amp;dq=plague&amp;#43;in&amp;#43;egypt&amp;#43;1906&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=HqzdiEyewX&amp;amp;sig=7Ev85udX7QZKFaTyZEzkBb7ZukY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjD79H4pMLSAhXEOSYKHcjnDo4Q6AEIIjAB#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=plague%20in%20egypt%201906&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;
explains that this plague had affected other countries as well such as India, South America, and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the article talks about improvements made in a village where numerous cases of the plague occurred as well as providing treatment to one infected patient that led to their cure. This proves that the medical professionals of Egypt were able to identify the disease and develop a treatment that helped cure at least one patient. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ancient.eu/article/51/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt;
 explains how diseases were treated in ancient Egypt. People were still exposed to similar diseases that are found today, however, their treatment methods were much different. They used medicines and &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; which referred to asking the gods for treatment. They also made their own medical remedies, many of which contained beer which was believed to have powerful curing effects. I am interested to know how they treated and cured the single patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, medical practices in ancient Egypt have a lasting effect on present methods. Through further research, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorable.com/ancient-medicine&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;
 went into detail on how treatments in ancient Egypt influenced treatments used today. For example, ancient Egyptian professionals used various herbs to create medicines to cure diseases and sicknesses. Many of these same remedies are still used today. Ancient medical practices were more advanced than I presumed. There is evidence that Egyptian doctors performed eye surgery, dentistry, used prosthetics, healed broken bones, and more. Many of their treatment and healing methods were published in books that are still being preserved today. It is interesting that medical practices used in ancient times are still being used in one way or another in modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of my classmates and students in the past also inquired questions regarding the plague. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/rymer-plague/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;One student&lt;/a&gt;
 was also curious to know more about the plague, its origins, symptoms, and treatment. I searched through various blog posts that were written on the plague and noticed a trend. Multiple students were wondering why there was not much information on the plague. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This student&lt;/a&gt;
 wrote about the small number of reports that were made about the plague. In my issue there was only one small article hidden on the third page. This makes me question how serious the disease was at the time and if it was something that either was not a major threat or if it was being hidden from the public. This is something I hope to learn more about as I continue working with my week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to go through my week in this newspaper, I hope to find more information about this plague. I wonder if the number of deaths will decreases and if a fully effective cure is developed to prevent further infections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death in Egypt and in my Mind.</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-greco-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-06-greco-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who would have ever of thought, that the utmost important news in Alexandra, in the year 1906, would be the deaths of a native woman and her daughter, and the director of a local hospital. This rather sad news is printed on page 3 of the Monday issue of my week in the Egyptian Gazette.  Not only is the content random, but this page has put a tremendous cramp in my style. It has become the pinnacle of my failure thus far. I do not find it a coincidence that the only page in my issue that is literally printed crookedly, contains the contents of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page has sparked the actual death of my patience, and my social life.  It is the exact reason why I lose sleep at night, and I cannot complete my Monday issue. At this point, I feel that my rant has become some kind of a nuisance, so with that being said, lets get to the subject matter at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mother and daughter were found asphyxiated in their room due to a charcoal fire. It is not mentioned in the paper, but the most obvious cause of death is carbon monoxide poisoning. Were Egyptians at the time not aware of the effects of carbon monoxide on the body? It makes me wonder what level of education the citizens of Alexandra actual possessed. Hell, they make me feel like a genius. In other news, the director of the Greek Hospital at Alexandra, Mr. Stiliano, died of heart disease. In the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, they do not specify what kind of heart disease, which makes me question the educational levels, once again, of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; employees. These two cases of death can properly represent my mind-state at the moment, confused, intrigued, disappointed, yet self-aware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wife Murder</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-cooper-wife-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-09-cooper-wife-murder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the twenty-fourth of January, an incident involving a woman and her enraged husband occurred. The man killed his wife by hitting her on the head using a metal bar made of iron and fled the scene. The former clerk from Gabbari has yet to be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motive for committing this heinous crime is unknown. Perhaps his wife was cheating on him or maybe she cooked him a poor meal. I find it interesting that an event of this magnitude is not given a bigger article. Someone&amp;rsquo;s life has been ended and there is a possibility that others may be in danger. More information should be provided and this news story should not be shrugged off as an every day occurrence. Either way, the suspect is still at large and he needs to be caught before he spreads his mayhem elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Fight between Greeks</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-doublemurder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-30-doublemurder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of January 3rd, 1905, two men were murdered behind a bar.
The man responsible is around 20 years old and is very physically fit.
His name is Yanni Antonio Stigrigo and was supposedly in love with the
sister of his victims. Ironically, one of the men he killed would have
made a good husband for his own sister. A fight broke out between the
three men and Yanni was quick to take out his weapon and stab the first brother one time, then stabbed the other brother two times. The second brother was taken to the Greek hospital, but died around midnight. Yanni was arrested outside of Cairo Railway Station and was easily apprehended. He followed police demands and quietly allowed them to put him in handcuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who wants to study murderers and their psychological aspects, I would like to know what the fight was about that made him think killing was the only answer. Due to the love interests involved between the three men, I suspect the fight was relevant to marriage. Of course, crimes like this still occur all over the world everyday. Bar fights are very common, mostly because people become angrier when they are intoxicated and cannot control their behaviors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent example took place in 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kjrh.com/news/local-news/police-are-investigating-double-homicide-in-n-tulsa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tulsa&lt;/a&gt;
. Bar fights happen every night and can occasionally turn deadly if someone does not step in soon enough. The most well known murder at a bar recently was the Orlando night club shooting. Of course, this was a hate crime but still comes to show that similar things happen everyday, this case being particularly extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;barfight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bar fight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the double murder that took place in 1905 in Egypt is similar to events in modern day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fatal House Collapse</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-building-collapse-hank-thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-24-building-collapse-hank-thompson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; covers a bevy of topics from foreign trade to local deaths, however one odd thing I have noticed within it is the rather blasé coverage of the deaths of common people. Take for instance the incident they reported on in the November 1st issue in 1905, shown above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of a house collapsing and killing seven people would have been a rather large headline in a local paper today, such as when 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/19/trial-set-to-open-in-fatal-philadelphia-building-collapse.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a thrift store collapsed in Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt;
. But the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; barely gives any information on it, acting as if it just another everyday occurrence. The coverage is rather sparse by our modern standards, where just about everything that can be sensationalized is, but the most interesting part is when it is compared to other articles within the paper. The paper dedicates an entire section of the paper to simply announce that an aristocratic madam has left Paris, complete with headline, but puts this story in with a group of other local stories and express little interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of reporting just took me off guard at first, especially when is noticed it was not a one-off occurrence. There is a story of a young boy drowning in the Nile, reports of deaths from the Plague and murders all treated with the same aloof attitude. This could possibly be attributed to the simple fact that death was more common 111 years ago. It didn’t effect people in the same way as it does today. Take for instance the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/boy-drowns-in-backyard-pool-in-sydneys-south-west-20161009-grydvb.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;death of a six-year old child in Sydney Australia&lt;/a&gt;
. He has a large separate news story into his death and even has an impending investigation into it. It is possible that the house collapse also has an investigation going on as well, but the newspaper does not mention anything of the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stark contrast in reporting between the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and our modern day newspapers just struck me as an interesting story to blog about, and so I did. Hopefully the reason I presented for this difference can be confirmed or denied later on, but only further research will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The death of Muhammad &#39;Abduh</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-abduh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/will-abduh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Muhammad &amp;lsquo;Abduh died on July 11, 1905. Because he was the leading Muslim thinker of Egypt and a prominent player in political and public life, it is not surprising that &amp;lsquo;Abduh&amp;rsquo;s illness, funeral, and memory were the subject of daily reports in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;article&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pro-British paper lauded the memory of the pro-British cleric.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
