<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>women | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/women/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>women</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>women</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/women/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can women be happy without men?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pustam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-pustam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this article on women and marriage while finding articles for my analysis project. My project was on wedding fashion, and this article talks about how women don’t consider marrying a man the ultimate way to get a happy life anymore. The writer of this article is very angry about it, saying “Where else [women’s papers] would anyone dare to imply that woman was sufficiently idiotic to believe that marriage &amp;ldquo;of itself alone&amp;rdquo; guaranteed anything?” I honestly kind of thought this article was funny. It was just funny to see the writer get so worked up they had to write an article about it that is mostly made up of quotes and not a lot of their own thoughts (pretty bad journalism if you ask me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something interesting about this was the fact that women are being blamed for the decline in marriage within this article, when there are incidents like one I found in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;- a crazy man killing his wife. Similar to in the Gazette, the writer of the blog post suggests the woman may be at fault for her unhappy marriage. They suggest that she might have cheated on her husband, causing him to kill her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there is another blog post, titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/&#34;&gt;“Women Are Always Lying?”&lt;/a&gt;, which describes an article that rants about how women lie to men by changing their appearance (presumably through makeup). Women are depicted as “a creature of broad and gradual curves, whose first duty it is to persuade you that she is the shape of the fashionable corset…” I can’t speak for women back then, but now women really don’t dress up for the sake of impressing men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When women are treated like this by men in newspaper articles, its really no wonder why they create their own newspapers to say that “it is possible to be as happy without a man’s love as with it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Egyptian - His Manners and Morals</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ebert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-ebert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this interesting article on page three of my Tuesday issue. It regards the safety of women who have to pass through the streets in front of the Arab trading shops. The author of the article is defending Europeans and claiming that the Arabic tradesman are the ones who are verbally harassing and potentially molesting these women. The author states &amp;ldquo;ladies who understand Arabic are lucky if they can pass in front of certain cafes, etc., situated in the most respectable quarters of Cairo, without hearing the most atrocious comments&amp;rdquo;(Gael). What I found most interesting about this article was that it was not the poor, lower-class servants and such who were doing this harassing, but rather the upper-class men who &amp;ldquo;possessed some means of education.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, women&#39;s safety has not improved much in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/roger-friedland/sexual-violence-and-the-egyptian-revolution_b_2658500.html&#34;&gt;modern times&lt;/a&gt;. Since this article made women seem so helpless, I looked up &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/1198/57e71816b48979e2f4bc74dee9fccf0b85dd.pdf&#34;&gt;women&#39;s rights in 1906&lt;/a&gt; and found that this was actually a very important time for women&#39;s rights. During this time, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arabwomenwriters.com/index.php/2014-05-03-16-01-55/n/nabaweya-musa&#34;&gt;Nabawiya Musa&lt;/a&gt; pioneered the movement for women&#39;s education. She was the first Egyptian girl to have a high school education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some links to related articles from classmates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/&#34;&gt;women are always lying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&#34;&gt;wife murder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Are Always Lying?</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-27-doring-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-27-doring-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While finishing the Tuesday edition of my week, I came across an article titled “Women and Lying.” This article was not only random, but shocking in how aggressive it felt. The article talked about how “women lie more constantly, laboriously, and cleverly than men, and in larger proportion.” The author of this article is very meticulous about describing how women lie. Not only does he mention how women lie through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vintagevictorian.com/costume_1905.html&#34;&gt;changing their appearances&lt;/a&gt;, but also how they lie through their feelings, their views, and their tastes. The author then goes onto describe how a woman will lie to alienate your feelings, convincing you to open up your “heavy gate” and walking right in.  It is concluded that the more a wife lies, the smoother the marriage goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was the article that stood out to me the most within my entire week. Not only was it aggressive, but it was very detailed in how, according to the author, women are very successful liars in almost every aspect of life. Without a doubt, reading this could teach you a lot about how women are viewed in the early 1900’s. It’s clear that women were not viewed as equals at this time and did not receive the respect that they had deserved. You can also learn from this the type of articles that were considered acceptable to write about in the paper when there was nothing else important to report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related blog post by MELIZZA BLACK: [“Avoid Female Society”](“Avoid Female Society”) Is this the female society that we are trying to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
