<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Egypt | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/egypt/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/egypt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Egypt</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/egypt/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to Law Against Foreigners in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-10-shanezedouglas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This ad in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper provides readers with a quick synopsis of a book called The Law Affecting Foreigners in Egypt by James Henry Scott, a lecturer at the Khedivial School of Law, Cairo. The book is an introduction to Egyptian Law as it affected foreigners and provides information on history like; the law of the Ottoman Empire and the Ottoman Capitulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book that the ad speaks of discloses Egyptian law as it once affected the foreigners of Egypt. For instance, from the list of topics the ad provided us with, it can be noted that this book provides us with information on events such as the mixed codes, mixed courts, the capitulations of European states, and the commercial privileges given to the people of Egypt. During the Anglo-Egyptian War, the country of Egypt was not only occupied by British forces but it was colonized by the British from 1882 when the war started, until 1956 when the war ended and the last British forces withdrew in accordance with the Anglo-Egyptian agreement of 1954 after the Suez Crisis. During this past age of time, several legal problems that were present in Egyptian law came about and were also seized with the limited powers of independent legislation. Insights like this about international historic events that has happened internationally has always intrigued me. I believe that international law allows students like myself to form bits of knowledge into the worldwide legal system and its effect on both national and international policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=gKIuAAAAIAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA288&amp;amp;lpg=PA288&amp;amp;dq=Mr.&amp;#43;Scott,&amp;#43;of&amp;#43;the&amp;#43;Khedivial&amp;#43;Law&amp;#43;School&amp;#43;Cairo&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=nHjRElq7vn&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U2u2ymFGRhBOm1CgfETFkwPHePcSQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjOs6Gz_K7mAhWPxVkKHcgTCikQ6AEwAXoECAYQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=Mr.%20Scott%2C%20of%20the%20Khedivial%20Law%20School%20Cairo&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this review&lt;/a&gt;
 that gives an opinionated review and summary of the book itself. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/367847?seq=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt;
 describes the social tensions and the how tht teaching of European law was in Egypt before 1900. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encyclopedia.com/history/encyclopedias-almanacs-transcripts-and-maps/capitulations-middle-east&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt;
 describes how the capitulations were in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cotton Industry</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-medina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-medina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The article “Cotton Industry in Lancashire” in the June 24, 1907 issue caught my attention since it shows how a textile that we use today, such as cotton, was used over a century ago. This article discusses how there was a surge in the production of raw cotton and how the industry of yarn weavers was able to handle this situation. In a brief statement – the weavers could not handle the overwhelming amounts of raw cotton being produced and had to cut manufacturing for a few weeks at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;medina-article.png&#34; alt=&#34;Article images&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to the up-rise of the spinning industry for cotton since the method was much more advanced and faster than the weaving method for goods. The cotton industry was being taken over by the newly found cotton industry in America causing an offset in production and quantity of raw cotton in Egypt and Lancashire at the time and in an imbalance in the financial markets. This can be known as &amp;ldquo;War Capitalism&amp;rdquo; a movement where developed nations were taking the crops and markets of smaller nations such as Egypt during this time and doubling their market. There is a great concern for how other markets such as those in America and Europe will impact the growth of the Egyptian cotton market through the West African slave trade, since cotton is Egypt&amp;rsquo;s number one crop. This led to Egypt selling off a fertile land to large estates to make every available land crops for cotton. By the 1900s, Egypt&amp;rsquo;s land was made up of 40% of cotton crops. In 1907, Egypt&amp;rsquo;s cotton crops were thriving and competing internationally with America and England with this textile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the cotton industry is still important in America and is still increasing as one of the top textiles produced in America. In Egypt, the cotton industry is still as prosperous yet unreliable due to wavering points of success and crises in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://indiana.edu/~caepr/Conferences/Wicker/Testing%20the%20Noyes%20Hypothesis_IU%20Oct%2024%202014.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Was the Panic of 1907 a Crisis?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncto.org/2017-state-of-the-u-s-textile-industry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;State of The U.S. Textile Industry&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/egypt-cotton/egypt-aims-to-double-its-high-quality-cotton-production-and-export-idUSL8N1JZ0K9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Egypt Aims to Double Its High-Quality Cotton Production&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history.ac.uk/reviews/review/1873&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Empire of Cotton Review&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bubonic Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#The Bubonic Plague has Arrived
##Striking Now in Egypt
Spread by Rats and Fleas
The Bubonic Plague has spread from many areas of SouthEast Asia, namely India, and has reached Egypt. The disease has affected many people and places, including Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;AndersonBubonicPlague2.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Plague Strikes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have come down with the disease, and many have been admitted to hospitals. Deaths have also been
associated with this deadly disease. The disease has turned into an epidemic since it once again arose from the depths of ancient times. According to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jmvh.org/article/the-history-of-plague-part-1-the-three-great-pandemics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JMVH&lt;/a&gt;
, this new plague, still spread from rats and rat fleas, has taken over all parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it has reached Egypt and Alexandria and has no signs of stopping anytime soon. Death rates are high for the disease, and in some cities without hospitals many people are at risk. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/plague/history/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CDC&lt;/a&gt;
 has reported that people should stay away from many of the rats infecting cities, because the cause of the disease is unknown as of yet. Many people die each day as reported in the newspapers, and more are being committed into hospitals at the same time. Many hope that the death rates of the plague decrease over time, but for many people whose family members have already been infected have little hope for the future. Some talk about vaccines and ways to stop the disease, but we have not received any of it yet because people are still dying. Many people in the areas affected by the plague cannot afford to find help, so in some cases, they are left to die on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;AndersonBubonicPlague2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Death on the Street&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatham Explosion</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week of the &lt;strong&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/strong&gt; contained a consistent current event throughout the duration
of the week regarding the blowing up of an old naval vessel, &lt;em&gt;The Chatham&lt;/em&gt;.  Apparently being fairly important
news, as the vessel had wrecked in a major fresh water canal popular for the movement and
transportation of good, this week of the paper held a special section each day for the process
of the ship’s disposal.  The amount of dynamite that had been acquired to destroy the wreckage
was on pace to set a world record for the largest explosion of dynamite to date, weighing nearly
ninety two tons.  Of course, along with this massive amount of explosives came the necessity to
put to plan a series of precautions and emergency aids in case anything went wrong.  The
explosives were to be carried to the scene of the wreckage by train, and detonated through a
length of copper wire hooked up to a detonator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wills-explosion-screenshot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot-name&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The townspeople at this time were extremely
anxious for the explosion out of fear that some of their personal property may accidentally be
destroyed.  However, as the week continues on and the anticipation comes to rise, the people
near the explosion were shockingly disappointed in the effect of it.  Having built up a drastic
image in their mind, the world record shattering explosion was fairly disappointing to the
people, as they hardly even felt the shock being nineteen kilometers away from the site.  The
underwater explosion destroyed a decent amount of the naval vessel, while shooting tons of
sand, water, and other debris hundreds of feet in the air.  While the explosion was considered
a success, there was a slight repair process and one of the banks of the canal had been fairly
destroyed, and a number of railway lines needed repair.  However, officials told the paper
that transportation shouldn’t be delayed more than a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
