<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scanning | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/scanning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/scanning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>scanning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>scanning</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/scanning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running out of Time</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-08-taylor-blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-08-taylor-blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Converting images to text has been a difficult process from start to finish. From the very start, FineReader did not seem to be responding well to my scans. It produced a multitude of errors (nearly every other word at points) that did not seem to be the result of poor scans. Then, one day I went to do some more work with it, and the program wouldn’t start up even though my trial period was not over yet. It displayed a message which said that ABBYY FineReader 12 would be terminated because it was corrupted. I discovered that one other student had the exact same problem, so at least I knew that it was not just my little computer giving up on life from working so hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I only had a couple more page threes to do at that point. So, I used my roommate’s Mac and did those. Now that I’ve moved on to other pages, I’m just typing up whatever articles appear since this doesn’t seem to take too much longer than it did to go back and correct all the text. All in all, this class has been far more difficult than I envisioned it being (especially for someone who is not great with computers), but I am not ready to give up on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
