<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/food/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Food</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Food</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/food/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Hungry</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-richardson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all going to die.  I am so sorry I had to be the one to break the news, but someone had to. Have you ever thought about your funeral? How you want to die? Or if you want to be buried alone? What if I told you no one in Ancient Egypt was buried alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I am telling you that and it is true. In A.R. William&amp;rsquo;s “Packing Food for the Hereafter in Ancient Egypt” article she says “Each had spent years preparing a lavish tomb stocked with everything they might need or want in the afterlife, including food, preserved for eternity.” Your death is just as important as our life so one should be prepared for it and they did. W. St Chad Boscawen 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://theplate.nationalgeographic.com/2015/04/05/packing-food-for-the-hereafter-in-ancient-egypt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;found that ancient Egyptians were buried with food&lt;/a&gt;
. Yay, you won’t spend eternity hungry! This food was found in vases or food dishes and there is a fine collection of food from vegetable matter to bread, fish or even fresh water crustacean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what you are thinking, what if you get thirsty? Have no fear if you are lucky enough in “the temeros” where your body is placed there is a round hole in the middle that contains a drain where offering of beer or wine could be made. Your party doesn’t have to stop because you are dead. In fact in an article written by Patrick J. Kiger called &amp;ldquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel.nationalgeographic.com/the-story-of-god-with-morgan-freeman/articles/ancient-egyptian-tombs-and-death-rituals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ancient Egyptian Tombs and Death Rituals&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;rdquo; it says “Egyptian funerals also were elaborate. The body was placed in a coffin and transported to the tomb in a cart pulled by oxen. It was accompanied by a procession that included relatives, priests and priestesses, along with dancers, and musicians.” 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.history.com/topics/tombs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;History.com&lt;/a&gt;
 says “The original purpose of a tomb was to protect the dead and provide the deceased with a dwelling equipped with necessities for the afterlife.” I really think it was Egypt’s way to send respect and keep the party of life going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it easier now to accept the inevitable? At least you won’t be hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
