<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>language | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/language/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>language</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>language</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tags/language/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page 6 Disaster</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-10-horton-page6disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-10-horton-page6disaster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this class, I have been assigned the week of February 19, 1906. All in all, I have to say this has been one of absolute favorite classes. Not only have I learned to code and become what I like to call “tech savvy” but I am learning the everyday lives of individuals from not only the United Kingdom but from pretty much anywhere they associate with. When you think about it we are given Monday through Saturday editions of the newspaper to complete; that is a ton of work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every day’s edition, the page six usually consists of financial tables. This is by far the worse part of the “coding” aspect of the class. I mean, the class itself is very time consuming and tedious but using OCR really does help to speed the process up, but of course you cannot run financial tables through OCR. Not once, have I had an easy time just knocking out the page sixes. You might be thinking right now “I wonder what is so bad about the financial tables? You’re given the template, therefore all you need to do is change the actual information within it.” Well, you have successfully answered the question; building the template is the easy part, actually filling in the tables are the difficult part. Actually sitting down and attempting to read what the newspaper actually says the problematic part. Either the letters or numbers are so small that you cannot read it or (in most cases) the scans are extremely blurry in parts of the page. Majority of the time, even if I take smaller section scans of each page to get a clearer reading, it is still does not help. What I read as a three are sometimes an eight, or the “E” is actually a “D” or “B”.  The comparison happen for almost every letter and number, it is just really hard to decipher. Although, I have to say, as frustrating as the page sixes are… typing the last text for that page, sitting back and say “ah yes! Finally I finished!” It’s an extremely rewarding feeling and then I can actually look at the information I wrote down and compare it to other issues and today’s information such as the stocks and shares portion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it quite interesting that when reading reviews of the Cisdem OCR system, on the following websites listed below, everyone seems to praise the system. I mean the system is indeed great, but I come across a lot of errors that still need to be fixed after running it through the OCR. I guess I must be doing something then, but I will definitely be looking into this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cisdem.com/pdf-converter-ocr-mac/reviews.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.cisdem.com/pdf-converter-ocr-mac/reviews.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macupdate.com/app/mac/52109/cisdem-pdfconverterocr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.macupdate.com/app/mac/52109/cisdem-pdfconverterocr&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And maybe I am just very naïve, and have not really taken the time to really think about each of the financial tables&#39; importance, but I just do not see why the public, whether the person is reading the paper in Great Britain or in Egypt, need to see a balance sheet for Egyptian investments. When you really think about it, that information can only be useful to someone who understands business, but not everyone reading the paper is “business savy.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Learning through the Newspaper</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within every issue throughout my week I continually saw two advertisements that stood out to me, an advertisement for a school of Language and an advertisement for an &amp;ldquo;English School&amp;rdquo;. Seeing education opportunities from the early 1900s is fascinating to me as it is during the century that public education became a cornerstone in developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First are the Berlitz Schools of Languages, typically found under the &amp;ldquo;Cheap Pre-paid advertisement&amp;rdquo; column on Page 5&amp;rsquo;s. It sounded familiar to me, and after doing a brief amount of searching, this is a education company/institution that has persisted since 1878 all the way until to the present day, hailing from the state of Rhode Island. In 1905 however, students in Egypt would only be able to attend the locations present in Alexandria and Cairo, unlike now, as the Berlitz Corporation offers full courses online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next advert regarding education that intrigued me was the &amp;ldquo;English School, Nicosia&amp;rdquo; advertisement. Offering a range of subjects, from Turkish to Mathematics, this school seemed a little more similar to institutions of the modern day. Also, this school seemed to have a sessions of Cricket and Football to be played with the instructors, which struck me as something related to more modern school systems. After a small amount of searching, it appears that this school persisted to the modern day just as the Berlitz program did. Besides being one of the more 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.englishschool.ac.cy/schools-history&#34; title=&#34;Nicosia English School Official History Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;notable institutions of higher learning&lt;/a&gt;
 in the Middle East, it is also an modern example of social change. For over two decades following the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_invasion_of_Cyprus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Turkish invasion of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;
, Turkish students were not admitted into the school, becoming a predominantly Greek Cypriot institution. However in 2003, the English School opened it&amp;rsquo;s admission to Turkish Cypriots and it&amp;rsquo;s general admission numbers have only grown exponentially since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Nicosia_school.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image name&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though during this time secondary education wasn&amp;rsquo;t seen as something that the whole of society deserved, it is still worth looking into these smaller institutions because it gives people a clearer understanding of how a system of education grows as more people become involved in it, and the social changes that occur through a better educated populace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curiosities</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-27-blog-post-1-daisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-27-blog-post-1-daisy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the year 1905, Alexandria, Egypt was becoming a city with a rising society as a result of the introduction to the use of new practices with a variety of beneficial purposes for individuals. As of today, we can still say performing arts such as theatre or music, culinary practices, economic practices, and several cultural practices are still used, usually enhancements of what was practiced in previous years. The city of Alexandria was beginning to get its own sense of balance with opening opportunities to those employers looking for something more than labor. Education was essential for personal growth, however, businessmen often times could not spare even an hour or two to enhance their education. However, thanks to the Berlitz Schools, businessmen were able to work around their schedules to receive classes for those aspiring to learn English, French, German, Italian, and other essential language lessons. To this day, these languages are still practiced by those bilinguals, aside from the use of Arabic: the native language of Egypt. Personally, this caught my attention because this presents a start for receiving an education while working for ends-meet. Also, it amazes me that Berlitz School is still a learning center for those that desire to learn a new language and has grown to be an international program, providing opportunities to learn languages or even study abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
